<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – What is No-code development?</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/</link><description>Recent content in What is No-code development? on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Application layout</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/application-layout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/application-layout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>As a driver of agile software development&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Configuration over customisation principle</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/configuration-over-customization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/configuration-over-customization/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Implementing dynamic logic with rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/implementing-dynamic-logic-with-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/implementing-dynamic-logic-with-rules/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: No-Code application development life cycle</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/application-development-life-cycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/application-development-life-cycle/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: No-code design principles</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/nocode-design-principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/nocode-design-principles/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Designing process in Kianda is considered one of the most important factors when creating a process. With a good design, your process will run smoothly and efficiently without the need of going through unnecessary steps, calculations or actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When designing your process, think of simplicity, think of all the necessary inputs and outputs that your process may have. When you know what kind of inputs and outputs are needed in your process, you will be able to figure out what kind of fields you need to gather information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-the-process-outcome">What is the process outcome&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/why-no-code-outcome.jpg" alt="Outcome dashboard">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When starting to design your process, first you need to think of is the &lt;strong>outcome&lt;/strong> of the process, what is the end &lt;strong>result&lt;/strong> that you are expecting after your complete the process. For example if you want to create an &lt;strong>Inspection Process&lt;/strong>, what would you want to be the result of this process. You will definitely want to know how the inspection went, did it pass the inspection, fail, are there any repairs that need to be made and does the inspection needs to be completed again? You most likely need a &lt;strong>report&lt;/strong> of the inspection itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="users-of-the-process">Users of the process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When designing your process, you need to consider who will be using your process. This will determine how many forms are need for your process. Taking the inspection example from earlier, you might need someone to start the process with requesting an inspection. We also might need a form for the inspector who will do the inspection. This brings the process to two forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that you know how many forms are needed, we can start thinking about the information that we need to gather within each of the forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-information-is-needed">What information is needed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you know what the outcome is, you need to figure out what kind of information you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to fulfill the outcome. To keep it simple, we will stick with our inspection example and the report as our outcome. What kind of information do we need on the report? The inspectors details perhaps, date of the inspection, maybe photographs for proof of visual checks. We might also need a signature from both the inspector and the area manager. These are just an example of what kind of information might be needed for a report, there can be lots more but the idea is to slowly step through the &lt;strong>requirements&lt;/strong> of the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-fields-are-needed">What fields are needed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/action-fields.jpg" alt="Outcome dashboard">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we know what the information we need to gather for our process, lets look into how are we going to capture that information. There are 16 predefined fields in Kianda that allows you to capture different types of information, for example, text, dates, files, signatures, visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> for more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With all the fields available, you can easily decided what kind of fields are needed for different types of information that you want to collect. For example images can be captured using the image field, files of any type can be captured using the file filed, text box fields are used for any form of text, For example, names, feedbacks, emails or passwords.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you have decided what fields you will use to gather your information, you can move on to functionality of your process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-functionality-is-needed">What functionality is needed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Business rules are what make Kianda forms come alive. They represent the actual actions users intend to perform when they interact with form components - for example, sending automated emails, revealing certain parts of a form based on user interactions and automatically generating Word and PDF documents from completed forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 60 predefined rules across 10 categories and they can be applied to fields (controls), forms, groups of forms or even to a whole process - see &lt;a href="#rules-list">Rules list&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two key principles to consider when working with rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#rule-design">Rule design&lt;/a> - Consider the type of rule you are going to apply and what you are going to apply it to - for example, to a button, field or form. As part of your design considerations it is important to know what you can do with rules, in particular, the use of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/conditions/">conditions&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/expressions/">expressions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#rule-order">Rule order&lt;/a> - If there are several rules attached to an item like a button, then the order the rules are going to be executed in becomes important. You can change the rule execution order to suit your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have discussed all major designing principles of your process, to learn more how to plan your first process, visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/">Plan your process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: No-Code Development Best Practices</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/best-practices/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process design vs instances</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/process-design-vs-instances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/process-design-vs-instances/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Why choose no-code?</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/why-choose-nocode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/no-code/why-choose-nocode/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No-Code development involves the creation of applications or business processes without the need to code. A no-code platform provides a Graphical User Interface (GUI) so that &lt;strong>citizen developers&lt;/strong> or non-IT business professionals can easily create and deploy digital solutions to meet business needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of how the solution is created, the output must meet all the requirements of a modern web application - being accessible through all major browsers and platforms and responsive in design so that it can be used on a variety of devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda form and dashboard &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> provides an intuitive interface where both technical and non-technical users can quickly start building digital processes and forms for use on any type of device.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-choose-no-code-development">Why choose no-code development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No-code development with Kianda simplifies the whole process of creating forms and its functionality. You can develop a fully working solution to your business needs, in days and even hours. You do not need to know how to code or even know what coding is. Kianda&amp;rsquo;s GUI consists of 16 predefined &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">fields&lt;/a> and 60 &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">rules&lt;/a> that you can choose from, you can simply click on a field to create it, change the layout of fields by drag and dropping them where suited. To apply a rule, select a field and click on the rule that you want to be applied. There is nothing easier than that, no need to work hours on end to develop a textbox field and its validation, it&amp;rsquo;s already built-in within Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda as a platform focuses on automating business processes with the usage of forms. The no-code aspect is crucial as you can develop a fully automated process very quickly, compared to your typical ways of developing applications, forms or websites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda also allows you to connect to multiple data sources that your organisation may already be using, for example, SharePoint, DocuSign, Active Directory or any relational database such as SQL, MySQL or Oracle, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Data connectors&lt;/a> for more. When a connection has been established with a data source that your organisation is using, you can use data from the source within your Kianda processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take an example of an On-boarding process within your organisation. The need to keep track of sending contracts through email, signatures and all the necessary information that is required. It can be easily done from one process and a couple of forms, each step of an on-boarding can be separated into forms that both, the new employee and the hiring manager can access. You can use file fields to upload your contracts, text box and date fields to gather information, and use rules to make your process dynamic. By adding rules to your process, you can dynamically create the new employees company email, add them to groups and systems that you may be using and give them permissions that match their company role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the code is already in Kianda, you just have to join it all together into a process that you need!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-implement-no-code-development">How to implement no-code development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a no-code platform, Kianda allows you to develop process to you business needs from your own browser. To implement the no-code feature that are built in, you will be using our &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>. Designer is used to start creating a process or edit an existing one. When using the Designer to create your process, you will be able to add forms, within the forms, add fields and rules that are already predefined. To access the Designer for a process, go to &lt;strong>Administrator &amp;gt; Designer&lt;/strong> from the home page of your Kianda subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Designer view of a process&lt;/em>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/why-no-code.jpg" alt="Designer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="adding-fields-to-a-form">Adding fields to a form&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Adding fields to a form is very easy in Kianda, all you need to do is click on the field that you want to use. You are able to click and drag that field to position it wherever you want inside of the form. Watch the short video below to see how easy it is to add forms and fields within Kianda.
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/designerintro.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="adding-rules-to-your-process">Adding rules to your process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Adding rules to your process is what makes Kianda come alive. You can add rules to your process by attaching them to the predefined fields, forms within your process or the process itself (applying a rule to a process will execute the rule when the process is loaded). Attaching a rule is easy, simply select a field or a form and click on the rule you want to add. This will automatically prompt you with the rule settings allowing you to fill in the needed information in order for the rule to work. The functionality of rules is already built-in, you just need to connect it by setting it up with the existing fields from your process. Checkout the video below to see how easy it is to add a rule to your process.
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/rules.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Find out more about Kianda and how to create your first process by going to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/">Getting started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>