<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/</link><description>Recent content in Rules on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: General rule concepts</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Rules are an important component of any process as they can be used to trigger automated actions, requiring minimal user management once created. There are 60 predefined rules in Kianda covering workflow applications, communications and file management to name a few.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="categories-of-rules">Categories of rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> - Enables you to execute actions that might change the flow of the information within a process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Communications&lt;/strong> - Enables sending emails or meeting requests or even user (push) notifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> - This is an important and flexible rule group because it allows you to configure CRUD (Create, Read, Update and Delete) actions to configured data sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> - This enables you to retrieve a user property, updating user properties or lookup for a user based on a user attribute.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong> - Allows operations such as the generation of a word document and conversion to PDF and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tables&lt;/strong> - Provides specialised rules to enable working with tables like sorting, copying table rows to another table and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dates&lt;/strong> - Enables convenient date calculation with advanced options like ignoring weekends or special dates.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form actions&lt;/strong> - Allows operations like submit, save, close and delete forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> - Provides a variety of operations to be performed on the SharePoint connection. These rules include operations like create a list, find a user, define permission to an item, check-in / out an item or adding a user to a SharePoint group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="working-with-rules">Working with rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following headings step through how to view, add, copy, edit and disable rules in processes. It is also important to keep in mind how rules should be listed when multiple rules are used on the same field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="when-to-add-a-rule">When to add a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-view-a-rule">How to view a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If rules have already been created&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field or form that contains a rule, for example a button at the end of a form. If a field within a form which rules attached this will be indicated within the form, as shown in the example below where the column &lt;strong>Instances&lt;/strong> has &lt;strong>1 rule&lt;/strong> attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-on-a-field.jpg" alt="Rule attached to a form field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, click on the given &lt;strong>rule name&lt;/strong> to view the rule details, for example a &amp;lsquo;Set form&amp;rsquo; rule called &amp;lsquo;Set link&amp;rsquo; as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/view-rule.jpg" alt="View rule details">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Details of the rule are available in the &lt;strong>Edit rule&lt;/strong> dialog box, for example the &lt;strong>Set form field&lt;/strong> rule is shown below.&lt;br>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-details-examples.jpg" alt="Rule details">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You can view rule conditions by clicking on &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> and actions to be performed as part of the rule are under &lt;strong>Action&lt;/strong>. Other features to note in the dialog box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Expression&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis_frame.png" alt="Expression button"> used to add expressions to rules so that dynamic values can be returned based on calculations or form IDs, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/expression-builder/">Expressions&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mapping&lt;/strong> - mapping is used within rule actions, for example in the &lt;strong>Set form field&lt;/strong> rule shown in the image above, the rule updates a form field based on a given value or expression. In many other fields mapping can be used to determine &lt;strong>success&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>error&lt;/strong> during rule execution, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/success-error-mapping/">Success and error mapping&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-add-a-rule">How to add a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a rule to a specific component:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>select a category&lt;/strong> of rules, and then &lt;strong>select the rule&lt;/strong> you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Edit the &lt;strong>rule dialog box&lt;/strong> and click &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;. The rule will be displayed on the right-hand side of the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-copy-a-rule">How to copy a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Duplicating rules can be very useful where you have similar rules that are associated with different fields. To duplicate a rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field with the desired rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, click on the &lt;strong>Duplicate rule&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/duplicate-rule.jpg" alt="Duplicate rule"> button next to the rule name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose &lt;strong>Copy to another field&lt;/strong> if you wish to copy to another field and select the field you want to copy to. Select &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Alternatively select &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> without copying to another field or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-a-rule">How to edit a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Follow the steps to &lt;a href="#how-to-view-a-rule">View an existing rule&lt;/a> to open the &lt;strong>Edit rule&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Edit rule dialog box, you can change:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the rule&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create or edit conditions for the rule by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change how the rule performs by changing details under &lt;strong>Action&lt;/strong>. Actions will differ depending on the rule in use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-disable-a-rule">How to disable a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Disabling a rule means that the rule is not active but is still visible in the &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> pane. The rule can be activated at any time again by clicking on the toggle button.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field that contains a rule, for example a button at the end of a form, or a field within a form which if it has rules attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, beside the given &lt;strong>rule name&lt;/strong> slide the toggle button from &amp;lsquo;on&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;off&amp;rsquo; to view the rule details, for example a &amp;lsquo;Set form&amp;rsquo; rule called &amp;lsquo;Set link&amp;rsquo; as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-disabled.jpg" alt="Rule disabled">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To enable the rule at any time again follow the steps above and slide the toggle button into the &amp;lsquo;on&amp;rsquo; position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-enabled.jpg" alt="Rule enabled">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="where-to-place-a-rule-in-a-list-of-rules">Where to place a rule in a list of rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The rule order refers to the order of execution of multiple rules. To change the rule order:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field with the rules attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, drag and drop the rules in the order you want them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The top-most rule is the first rule to be executed. By default buttons at the end of a form will automatically have &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> rules. If you create rules you may wish to have these rules placed &lt;strong>above&lt;/strong> these shutdown rules so that your rules are executed first before form shutdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> Rule order becomes important when the output of one rule impacts the execution of another, for example if a process remains &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; because a user must perform a particular action, then it is useful to have an automated email reminder sent to the user while the process is open. For example
the order of rules on a &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> button could be: Set Status, Send Email, Submit, Save, Close, whereby the status of the process instance is set first, before an automated email and then the form shutdown rules of Submit, Save and Close occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about multiple rules, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/multiple-rules/">Multiple rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="conditions">Conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flexible and dynamic conditions form an important component to make forms fully dynamic. This feature enables you to create natural language conditions when rules should be triggered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/condition-editor.png" alt="Condition Editor">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To configure a rule to conditionally execute an action:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field or form that the rule will be attached to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane, click on a &lt;strong>category&lt;/strong> of rules, for example &lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> and then a rule itself, for example &lt;strong>Process security&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> button within the rule.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the conditions that satisfy your scenario. Multiple conditions can be grouped with condition groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>For more information on Conditions, go to the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="custom-rules">Custom rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Under custom rules, you will find any custom-developed rules available under your developer section. Custom rules provide access to rules that are built for extensibility of Kianda capabilities. This is particularly used in situations when existing rules do not provide the required functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Custom rules have the purpose of providing a user interface for the end-users. If you need to build &amp;ldquo;a rule&amp;rdquo; then you should use a custom rule widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It allows a developer to quickly build a reusable component that would then be used by process designers in real processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check-out the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/low-code/">development&lt;/a> section for more details on how to build custom widgets in Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced the key concepts of rules. Click on the links below to read more about rule concepts in detail:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Workflow rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> rules is one category of &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">rules&lt;/a> used relating to user interactions with form components. Using Workflow rules will also allow you to change the flow of information within a process. For example in a simple Training Process that is made up of three forms by default, the &lt;strong>first form&lt;/strong> in a process is the &lt;strong>current form&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/3-form-example.jpg" alt="Three form process example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example above, the workflow for this process would be completion of the forms in this order: &lt;strong>Training Request&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Training Approval&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Training Attendance&lt;/strong> however using Workflow rules, you could use &lt;strong>Go to form&lt;/strong> to force the &lt;strong>Training Attendance&lt;/strong> form to be the current form after the Training Request form has been completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You could also use the &lt;strong>Assign form&lt;/strong> rule to assign editing rights to particular users so they can edit forms. See more about Go to form and Assign form below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using rules in this way changes the flow of the process, and additional levels of security and user interaction can be added using &lt;strong>Process security&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Hide or disable&lt;/strong> see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-workflow-rules">Getting started with Workflow rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/workflow-rules.jpg" alt="Workflow rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are seven types of &lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="hide-or-disable">Hide or disable&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This rule is used to hide, disable, show or enable one or more fields, one or more sections or entire forms. This rule has special meaning in terms of workflow allowing the application to direct user action and flow by hiding or showing entire sections of the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="make-required">Make required&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Use this rule to make individual fields required or entire forms. Unlike the field property &amp;lsquo;Required&amp;rsquo;, this rule will dynamically allocate a mandatory status on chosen forms or fields, that users must complete and submit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="go-to-form">Go to form&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Go to form rule navigates the user from the current form to the destination form. This rule could also set the destination form&amp;rsquo;s display mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="assign-form">Assign form&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This rule enables dynamic form ownership and form security assignment of a form owner by assigning a user or a group to a form. You could also choose to override or append the form owner. By default only form owners can see the form in edit&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="process-security">Process security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This rule defines the security of the entire process instance (record). Using this rule, you could add any user or group with the right permissions to view/update any instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="start-a-sub-process">Start a (sub) process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Start a process rule helps you create a new instance of the same process or a different process. You could also map the inputs from the current instance to a new instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;h3 id="schedule-a-rule">Schedule a rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This rule helps you schedule a rule/rules to be triggered one time, with a recurring schedule or immediately. For example, this rule could be used to schedule a daily reminder email to a user if the task is not complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the six types of &lt;strong>Workflow rules&lt;/strong>. Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these types of rules in more detail:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Communication rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Communication&lt;/strong> rules is one category of &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">rules&lt;/a> to enable automated communications with process users, for example sending meeting requests or even user push notifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-communication-rules">Getting started with Communication rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>Communication&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Communications&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/communication-rules-all.jpg" alt="Communication rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are four types of &lt;strong>Communication&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Send email&lt;/strong> - allows you to send automated emails that contain images, text, process and other links and attachments.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Meeting request&lt;/strong> - allows you to send automated emails that contain a meeting request.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Anonymous form link&lt;/strong> - this rule creates a link to a form which can be sent to external users,.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>User alert&lt;/strong> - this rule sends an alert to a user who can then access a process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules is the category of rules that enables the flow of data between data connectors and form elements, for example reading or writing data from a database table or performing data manipulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/data-rules-all.jpg" alt="Data rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take an example of one of the rules in the Data rules category, the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule. This rule can be used to extract data from a data source and use this information in a Kianda form. Take an example of an Employee Onboarding or New hire process, where a user chooses a country for a &amp;lsquo;Country&amp;rsquo; field from a drop-down list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/find-items-example.jpg" alt="Drop-down list Find items example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The drop-down list is populated using a SharePoint list in this example, and the &amp;lsquo;Country&amp;rsquo; field in turn uses a &lt;strong>Find item&lt;/strong> rule to populate the table below it in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/find-items-populate.jpg" alt="Find items rule populating a table">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The section below introduces each of the Data rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-data-rules">Getting started with Data rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are five types of &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Create item&lt;/strong> - The create item rule is used to create an item on your data connection. This is a straightforward rule which allows you to connect to your data source and map inputs. You can also map a data source field or text back to Kianda on success or store an error message on failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Delete item&lt;/strong> - To delete an item from your data connection, you could use a data source filter and map data source field or text from a data connection to Kianda form field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update item&lt;/strong> - This rule works in the same way as the Delete item rule. At any point, if you would like to update any item on your data connection, use this rule. To find an item to update, you could use a data source filter and map the input fields or text.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> - Use this rule together with a datasource to perform a query and return data for use with the form. To find an item, you could use a data source filter which acts as a conditional bridge between Kianda and data-connections. If the condition is true, you could map the data source field or text to the Kianda form field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Set form field&lt;/strong> - This rule is used to update the value of fields in a form. The field value could be simple text or based on a custom expression with the ability to define JavaScript expressions. Use this rule to copy content between fields or to apply a custom expression to set the value of a given field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the five types of &lt;strong>Data rules&lt;/strong>. Click on the links below to find out more about each rule in detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: User rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/users/</guid><description>
&lt;p>User rules is one category of &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">rules&lt;/a> to enable operations based on user attributes, such as updating user properties and looking up users in a data connector by property.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-user-rules">Getting started with User rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the User rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-rules-intro.jpg" alt="User rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are four types of User rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get user property&lt;/strong> - this rule is used to get data from a selected user profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lookup user by property&lt;/strong> - this rule is used to look up a user by attribute, for example email address.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> - this rule sends an invitation to a contact in a partner organisation for them to access a shared process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update user property&lt;/strong> - this rule is used to update a property in a user profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: File management rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong> rules is one category of &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">rules&lt;/a> to enable operations such as the generation of Word documents, and conversion to PDF format.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-file-management-rules">Getting started with File management rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-managemt-rules.jpg" alt="File management rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are seven types of &lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Copy file&lt;/strong> - this rule copies a file from one data location to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Convert to PDF&lt;/strong> - this rule converts a Word document to PDF format.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Generate word document&lt;/strong> - this rule generates a Word document from data associated with a process instance using a user-designed template.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Generate excel document&lt;/strong> - this rule generates an Excel workbook from data associated with a process instance using a user-designed template.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Set existing file&lt;/strong> - this rule is used to make an existing file available within a configured file field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Merge PDF&lt;/strong> - this rule merges two or more PDF files into a single PDF file.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Create a file anonymous link&lt;/strong> - this rule generates file links that can be shared anonymously to external users.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Table rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/tables/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong> rules is one category of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">rules&lt;/a> to enable table operations such as sorting, copying table rows to another table, exporting and importing table data as .csv files and adding and removing table rows. These operations are useful to implement in external data sources, automating actions using Kianda processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-table-rules">Getting started with Table rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Tables&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/table-rules-all.jpg" alt="Table rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 12 types of Table rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Loop table&lt;/strong> - this rule loops through table rows, where other rules can be triggered and implemented.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Add table row&lt;/strong> - this rule adds a new row to a table.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Remove table row&lt;/strong> - this rule removes a current row from a table.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Import CSV&lt;/strong> - this rule imports .csv or .xlsx file data into a table, based on mapping provided within the rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Export CSV&lt;/strong> - this rule is export the contents of a table to a .csv file.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Copy table rows&lt;/strong> - this rule copies table rows from one table to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clear table rows&lt;/strong> - this rule removes table rows that match given criteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lookup value from table&lt;/strong> - this rule performs a lookup on a table value that match given criteria&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update table values&lt;/strong> -this rule updates table columns that match given criteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sort table&lt;/strong> -this rule sorts table data based on multiple conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Aggregate table&lt;/strong> - this rule aggregates table values.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide/Show column&lt;/strong> - this rule allows you to hide or show columns within a table&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Date rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/dates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/dates/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> rules is a category of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">rules&lt;/a> that allows for the calculation and manipulation of dates, for example to add time units to a date, to compare dates and allow customised formatting of date display.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-date-rules">Getting started with Date rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Dates&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/date-rules-all.jpg" alt="Date rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are four types of &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Add time to date&lt;/strong> - this rule allows the addition of time to a date which can be based on a chosen parameter such as starting from now, today or another specified value.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Calculate time&lt;/strong> - this rule calculates the number of time units between two dates, or from now.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Compare dates&lt;/strong> - this rule allows the comparison of date fields to know if one date is for example, between dates, before or after a given date.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Format date&lt;/strong> - this rule applies custom formatting to input date fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Form action rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/form-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/form-actions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Rules within the &lt;strong>Form action&lt;/strong> rules category allow you to perform form specific actions on forms and processes such as saving a form / process, submitting a form, closing a form, deleting a process and validating form input.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-form-action-rules">Getting started with Form action rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>Form action&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Form action&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form-action-rules-all.jpg" alt="Form action rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are six &lt;strong>Form action&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Validate input&lt;/strong> - provides ability perform flexible data validation and prevents incorrect data submission&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Field display mode&lt;/strong> - this rule forces the display mode to override the automatic display mode of fields and forms&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Submit form&lt;/strong> - marks the current form as complete and makes it read-only&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Save form&lt;/strong> - commits a record or process instance in the server&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Close form&lt;/strong> - closes the form and navigates to another resource&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Delete form&lt;/strong> - marks the record or process instance to be deleted&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: AI rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/kianda-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/kianda-ai/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Artificial Intelligence powered text analysis performs sentiment analysis to text content&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SharePoint rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/sharepoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/sharepoint/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> rules are associated with SharePoint specific functionality. These rules are typically used to perform actions with SharePoint connectors that are not related with data, for example resetting SharePoint permissions or adding a user into a group on SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sharepoint-rules-all.jpg" alt="Sharepoint rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-started-with-sharepoint-rules">Getting started with SharePoint rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>Sharepoint&lt;/strong> rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Sharepoint&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 10 &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a list&lt;/strong> - creates a new list in a SharePoint site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a site&lt;/strong> - creates a new site on SharePoint, enabling the use of a site template.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a group&lt;/strong> - creates a new group on SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find a user&lt;/strong> - finds or searches for a user within SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add a user to a group&lt;/strong> - adds a SharePoint user to a SharePoint group. It is important to note the difference between Sharepoint users and Kianda users. Sharepoint users are users of the Sharepoint system. Kianda users are users of the Kianda system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remove a user from a group&lt;/strong> - removes a SharePoint user from a SharePoint group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reset an item permission&lt;/strong>s - changes the SharePoint permissions for a given list, document or folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Check in / out an item&lt;/strong> - checks in or out a file in SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Get attachments&lt;/strong> - reads the attachments from a SharePoint list&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create anonymous link&lt;/strong> - creates anonymous links for a SharePoint held file&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the ten types of &lt;strong>SharePoint rules&lt;/strong>. Click on the links below to find out more about each rule in detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>