<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda low-code platform for business process automation – Controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/</link><description>Recent content in Controls on Kianda low-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Platform: Control properties</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/properties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/properties/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Each process, form and control (field) will have the properties associated with it displayed in the right-hand pane of the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a> view.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="process-properties">Process properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and then click on a process, you will see the &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> for that process in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Process properties include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the title of the process, for example Quarterly Training Request&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Page layout&lt;/strong> - you can click on &lt;strong>Wide&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/wide-resized.png" alt="Wide button">or &lt;strong>Narrow&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/narrow-resized.png" alt="Narrow button"> to change the process layout.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-properties-trainingprocess.jpg" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, the &amp;lsquo;Training Process&amp;rsquo; has two forms: &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo;. When you open the process, the &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> are shown. If you click on one of the forms within the process, the &lt;a href="#form-properties">&lt;strong>Form properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> associated with that particular form will then be shown in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="form-properties">Form properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you click on a form, the &lt;strong>Form properties&lt;/strong> appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form-properties-trainingprocess.jpg" alt="Form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Form properties include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the form title, for example Training Request&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - click on this checkbox if you want the form to be visible to users&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show info&lt;/strong> - click on this checkbox if you want details (such as the form owner, the design version and when the form was started and completed) to be displayed at the bottom of the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form-properties-show-info-version.jpg" alt="Form information">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Underneath the Form properties you will see &lt;strong>Form submit rules&lt;/strong> - go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to find out more about the rules that can be applied to forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on one particular field (control) in the form - for example a text box - to see the &lt;a href="#field-properties">&lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> associated with that field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="field-properties">Field properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you select any field within a form (by clicking on the field name or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - such as User picker, list or text box - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with that field will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-properties-trainingprocess2.png" alt="Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, the Employee Name field has been selected and the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with it include the &lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> (&lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong> in this case) and the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within the Field properties menu are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show Title&lt;/strong> - show the title of the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - tick this checkbox to make this field mandatory for users to fill out (this will be denoted by an asterix beside the field name)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - tick this checkbox to make the field enabled for users to fill out&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - tick this checkbox to make the field visible to users&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - change the width of the field by clicking on the bar in the Layout box until you see the desired size. Click on the arrow beside Layout to see the Mobile Layout and click on the bar to change the width of the field when viewed on a mobile phone. The layout is split into 12 different bootstrap grid columns (a responsive CSS framework) - for example, a layout set to 6 columns would make the element span half of the screen/canvas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxsize-frame2.png" alt="Changing text box width">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Underneath the Field properties menu, you will see &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> - go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to find out more about the rules that can be applied to fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> associated with processes, forms and fields, find out more about the different categories and types of fields (controls):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/">Input controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/">Layout controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/">Actions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/custom/">Custom controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Platform: Input controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/input/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/input/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Input fields&lt;/strong> are one category of &lt;a href="../">controls&lt;/a> and include the most common data fields used to obtain user input - for example text boxes, lists and tables.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-input-controls">Getting started with Input controls&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start adding Input controls (fields) to your Kianda forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>First, either open an existing process or create a new process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> in the left side menu. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/administration-designer-inputcont.jpg" alt="Opening Designer from left side menu by choosing Administration&amp;gt;Designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Once you have opened your process, select the form you want to work on (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> is shown).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane so the Controls menu expands to show the four categories of Controls (fields): Input, Layout, Actions and Custom.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/open-controls-cat-trainingprocess.jpg" alt="Opening Controls menu to view four categories of Controls">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> to view the eight types of Input fields:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/input-menu-controls.jpg" alt="Input fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The eight types of input fields are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong> - A text box field is a section in your form where users can enter text, for example, an Address field. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Text box control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> - A list field lists information, for example from a SharePoint data source. This is particularly useful for drop-down menus, when you want a user to fill out a form and choose an item from a list. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Number&lt;/strong> - A number field provides an input box that only allows numeric input, such as currencies or percentages. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/">Number control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> - A date field provides a date and time picker that allows users to input both date and time. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/">Date control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>File&lt;/strong> - A file field allows users to upload multiple files. Uploaded files are stored within the configured data structures or folders. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/">File upload control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong> - A table field creates a table for input in a form. This table can be filled by the user, or autofilled as part of a rule. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User picker&lt;/strong> - A user picker field allows users to choose from a list of users. This can be a preconfigured group (like HR Managers) or a list of users - see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/">User picker control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle&lt;/strong> - A toggle field can be used as a toggle or checkbox that allows users to turn on/off components of the form. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/">Toggle control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-add-edit-move-and-delete-input-fields">How to add, edit, move and delete Input fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To insert an &lt;strong>Input field&lt;/strong> into your form click on the field type you want to add from the &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, to add a new text box field, click on &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong> - a pop-up message will appear saying &amp;lsquo;Field added&amp;rsquo; and a new text box with the default name &lt;strong>Text box 1&lt;/strong> will be added to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/insert-text-box-input.jpg" alt="Inserting a text box field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>edit&lt;/strong> whatever type of input field you have added to your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field name or on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then click on the &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> dialog box will automatically open, providing you with a variety of options for editing the field - such as changing the Title of the field - depending on the type of Input field you are working with.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/select-text-box-edit.jpg" alt="Select field to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>move&lt;/strong> an Input field, simply&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it within your form. This example shows how you could move a Text box field in a form:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/move-drag-handle.jpg" alt="Select field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> an Input field from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You can also view and edit an input field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Field Properties&lt;/strong> by selecting the field - for more details, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties/#field-properties/">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the eight types of &lt;strong>Input controls&lt;/strong>. Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these types of input fields in more detail:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platform: Layout controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Layout fields are one category of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">controls&lt;/a> (fields). They are fields that can be used to enhance the layout of your form - for example, responsive panels, dialog boxes and rich text fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-layout-fields">Getting started with Layout fields&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To insert a &lt;strong>Layout field&lt;/strong> into a form, first open an existing process or create a new process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>&amp;gt;&lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> in the left side menu. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/administration-designer-inputcont.jpg" alt="Opening Designer from left side menu by choosing Administration&amp;gt;Designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the form within that process that you want to add the Layout field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Next, click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu and select &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> to view the Layout fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Layout field you want to insert.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/layout-insert.jpg" alt="Layout fields menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>There are 4 types of layout fields:
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong> - The Panel field provides responsive panels to hold elements of your form like text boxes and lists and enables flexible layout options for better design. To learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel/">Panel control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dialog&lt;/strong> - The Dialog field is used to create modal dialogs to alert or prompt form users. For example, a warning message could display to remind the user to complete part of a form before they proceed to the next section. To learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/dialog/">Modal Dialog control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Richtext&lt;/strong> - The Richtext field is used to create rich content in forms, such as an attractive banner or static html, and provides optimum formatting options. To learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">Richtext control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> - The Field Group control can be used to mirror a group of fields from another form or location and reference those fields in your new form, making process design sleeker and more efficient. To learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/field-group/">Field group control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-add-edit-move-and-delete-layout-fields">How to add, edit, move and delete Layout fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-add-layout-fields">How to add Layout fields&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To insert a &lt;strong>Layout field&lt;/strong> into your form, click on the field type you want to add from the &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, to add a new panel to your form, click on &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong> - a pop-up message will appear saying &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field added&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and a panel field with the default name &lt;strong>Panel 1&lt;/strong> will be added to your form (by default, the title of the new panel will not be shown but you can make it visible by selecting the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; checkbox in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> panel to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-insert.jpg" alt="Insert panel field">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-edit-layout-fields">How to edit Layout fields&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To edit whatever type of &lt;strong>Layout field&lt;/strong> you have added to your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field (by either clicking on the field name or on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we have selected the &lt;strong>Panel field&lt;/strong> by clicking the Drag handle button and can then click on the Edit field button to edit it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This will open up the &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> dialog box where you can make various changes (such as changing the Title of the field) and where a variety of options will be available to you, depending on the type of Layout field you have selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-select-to-edit.jpg" alt="Select panel to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-move-layout-fields">How to move Layout fields&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To move a Layout field:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it within your form&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-delete-layout-fields">How to delete Layout fields&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To delete an input field from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-layout-field-properties">How to edit Layout field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Layout field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-field-properties.jpg" alt="Panel field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the &lt;strong>Field Properties&lt;/strong> associated with a &lt;strong>Panel field&lt;/strong> titled &amp;lsquo;Existing Qualifications&amp;rsquo; are shown here and include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - The type of field, in this case a &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - The Title of the field, in this case &amp;lsquo;Existing Qualifications&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field title will be shown in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be a mandatory field that users must complete (denoted by a red asterix next to the field title).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the user will be able to edit or interact with the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be visible in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - The width of the field is denoted by the width of the blue bar. Click on the bar to change the width of the field as it will appear on a PC or mobile phone (to view the Mobile layout, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the four types of &lt;strong>Layout controls&lt;/strong>. Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these types of Layout controls in more detail:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platform: Actions</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/actions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Action fields&lt;/strong> are one category of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">controls&lt;/a> and include the fields that allow user interface actions like buttons or links.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-action-controls">Getting started with Action controls&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are four types of &lt;strong>Action fields&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Button&lt;/strong> - Buttons can be used to allow user interaction and to enable rules to be applied to actions taken by users. Applying rules to buttons can help to create smart, dynamic forms that follow business logic, without the need for coding. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/button/">Button control&lt;/a> to learn more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong> - Link fields can be used to create custom links to forms. These can be external links. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/link/">Link control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Image&lt;/strong> - Image fields can be used to display images, either statically or from file fields. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/image/">Image control&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Signature&lt;/strong> - Signature fields provide a very neat way to electronically sign-off on a form or process. To learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/signature/">Signature control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To add an &lt;strong>Action field&lt;/strong> to a Kianda form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open an existing process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> in the left side menu and clicking on a process, or create a new process in Designer. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/designer-open-process.jpg" alt="Open process in Designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have opened your process, select the form you want to work on (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> is shown).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, a Training Request form has been selected:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/actions-select-form.jpg" alt="Select form">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane so the Controls menu expands to show the four categories of Controls (fields): Input, Layout, Actions and Custom.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Actions&lt;/strong> to see the four types of Action fields: Button, Link, Image and Signature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/actions-menu.jpg" alt="Actions menu in the Controls panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Action field&lt;/strong> type you want to insert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, to insert an &lt;strong>Image&lt;/strong> field:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Image&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;strong>New field - Image&lt;/strong> dialog box opens automatically, giving you a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Image field&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you complete this dialog box and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, the new Image field is inserted into your form. To learn more about the Image field, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/image/">Image control&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/image-dialog2.jpg" alt="Image dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-action-fields">How to edit, move and delete Action fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit whatever type of &lt;strong>Action field&lt;/strong> you have added to your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field (by either clicking on the field name or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit Field&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, giving you a different range of options to make changes to the Action field - such as changing the Title of the field - depending on the type of Action field you are working with.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To move an &lt;strong>Action field&lt;/strong>, simply:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Drag and drop the Action field wherever you want to move it within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the &amp;lsquo;Training Documentation&amp;rsquo; &lt;strong>Link field&lt;/strong> shown here can be moved in the form by selecting the &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button and dragging and dropping it wherever you want to put it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/action-link-example-move.jpg" alt="Move link field example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To delete an &lt;strong>Action field&lt;/strong> from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the Action field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s title or its &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-view-and-edit-action-control-field-properties">How to view and edit Action control Field Properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit an Action control&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the Action field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Field Properties associated with the Action field will be displayed (and can be changed) in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu on the right-hand side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/action-link-field-properties.jpg" alt="Field properties associated with a Link field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with a Link field titled &amp;lsquo;Training Documentation&amp;rsquo; are shown here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - The type of field, in this case a &lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - The Title of the field, in this case &amp;lsquo;Training Documentation&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field title will be shown in the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be mandatory for the form user to complete (and a red star will be shown next to the field title to denote this).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the user will be able to edit the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be visible in the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - The width of the blue bar can be adjusted to change the width of the field as it appears on a PC or mobile phone (to view the Mobile layout, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>​ For more details, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the four types of &lt;strong>Action fields&lt;/strong>. Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at each of these Action fields in more detail:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platform: Custom controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/custom/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom fields&lt;/strong> are a fourth category of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">controls&lt;/a> that are only available to you as a Designer in Kianda if Custom controls have been created by an Administrator or Designer in your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> to a Kianda form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open an existing process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> in the left side menu and clicking on a process, or create a new process in Designer. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/designer-open-process.jpg" alt="Open process in Designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have opened your process, select the form you want to work on (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> is shown).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, a Training Request form in an Education Request Process has been selected:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-form.jpg" alt="Select form to insert Custom field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the area within the form where you want to insert the new &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> - in our example, we will select the first panel in the Training Request form:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-location.jpg" alt="Select panel to insert Custom field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane, and, from the four categories of Controls (Input, Layout, Actions and Custom), click on &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-fields.jpg" alt="Insert Custom field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>This fourth category of Controls will only be available to you if Custom controls have been created by Administrators or Developers in your Kianda workspace&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Custom fields&lt;/strong> available to you will be shown in the expanded &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong> menu - in the example shown here, there are three Custom fields available to the form Designer:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-fields-example.jpg" alt="Insert Custom field examples">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> you want to insert and it will be added to your form at the bottom of the form section you have selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we can click on the first Custom field listed in the &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong> sub-menu - Field widget - the new Custom widget (&amp;lsquo;Field widget 1&amp;rsquo;) is added to the bottom of the panel we had selected and a pop-up message says &amp;lsquo;Field added&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-inserted.jpg" alt="New Custom field inserted">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the new &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> as you want - to do this, select the Custom field (by either clicking on its field title or on its &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) and then click the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-edit.jpg" alt="Edit Custom field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, showing the range of options available for that particular Custom field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-custom-controls-are-created">How Custom controls are created&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Kianda Administrator or Developer can create &lt;strong>Custom controls&lt;/strong> by opening the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> menu from the left-side menu and clicking on &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-developer.jpg" alt="Create a Custom field by clicking on Developer from the Administration menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Developer resources page opens and displays all of the Custom widgets that have been created - these include Custom field widgets, Custom rule widgets and Custom Dashboard widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-widgets.jpg" alt="Create new Custom widget Developer resources page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Only &lt;strong>Custom field widgets&lt;/strong> will be shown in the &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong> controls menu in Kianda Designer - that is, only Custom widgets with a &amp;lsquo;Type&amp;rsquo; of &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create a new Custom Widget, the Developer/Administrator clicks on the &lt;strong>New widget&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-new-widget.jpg" alt="New widget button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, in which the Title, Unique ID, Widget icon and Widget type can be chosen:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-edit-widget2.jpg" alt="Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the Developer/Administrator completes the dialog box and clicks on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, a workspace opens where they can create their Custom widget:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-new-widget-workspace.jpg" alt="Custom widget workspace">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a &lt;strong>Custom field widget&lt;/strong> has been created, Designers will then be able to see and use that Custom field widget in the &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong> section of the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> menu when designing Kianda forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about how to create &lt;strong>Custom field widgets&lt;/strong>, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/low-code#how-to-get-started-as-a-kianda-low-code-developer">Creating a custom field widget&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-custom-fields">How to edit, move and delete Custom fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field title or &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-edit2.jpg" alt="Select Custom field to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from a range of options specific to that particular Custom field. The functionality of the field will depend on what the Custom field was designed to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, we could drag and drop the new Custom field titled &amp;lsquo;Field widget 1&amp;rsquo; so that it comes before the &amp;lsquo;Type of Training&amp;rsquo; List field:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-move.jpg" alt="Custom field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-view-or-edit-custom-control-field-properties">How to view or edit Custom control Field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the Field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or its &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-field-properties.jpg" alt="Field properties associated with a Custom field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>Custom field&lt;/strong> titled &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field widget 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; has been selected and the Field properties associated with this field are shown in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu to the right, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - For Custom field widgets, the &amp;lsquo;Field type&amp;rsquo; will be &amp;lsquo;Field widget&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - The Title of the field, in this case &amp;lsquo;Field widget 1&amp;rsquo;. You can change the title here, in Field properties, or in the Edit field dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the Custom field title will be shown in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be mandatory for the form user.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the user will be able to edit or interact with the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the Custom field will be visible in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - The width of the blue bar can be adjusted to change the width of the Custom field as it appears on a PC or mobile phone (to view the Mobile layout, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more details, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about &lt;strong>Custom controls&lt;/strong>, find out more about how you can use Controls, how you can get started as a Kianda low-code developer, and more about the three other categories of &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/low-code/">What is low code?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/">Input controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/">Layout controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/">Actions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>