<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Dashboard pages</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Dashboard pages on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Chart widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> enables you to create pie charts, bar charts or line charts on your dashboard page. These charts can be used to represent various conditions or values in a process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the Chart widget &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/chart.png" alt="Chart widget">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-chart.jpg" alt="Add chart widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want for your new &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> (instead of the default title that is shown).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White), if you choose to display it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Chart widget to be displayed in the dashboard. This checkbox is selected by default, so de-select it if you don&amp;rsquo;t want the header to be displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong>. Select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can use the menu on the right to either filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as the Chart widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong>: This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select the layout container you want to place your new &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new Chart widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit chart&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens showing the options for your new Chart widget. To learn more about these options and how to complete the Edit chart dialog box so the Chart widget displays certain fields from your form, see Step 3 of &lt;a href="#how-to-edit-chart-widgets">How to edit Chart widgets&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have finished chooseing the options you want in the &lt;strong>Edit chart&lt;/strong> dialog box, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the top dashboard menu to save the insertion of the new Chart widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your new &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> will now be displayed on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is an example of how Chart widgets can look on a dashboard page:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-chart-examples.jpg" alt="Example of dashboard Chart widgets on a dashboard page">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-chart-widgets">How to edit Chart widgets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings"> and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Chart widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/chartpen.png" alt="Chart widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit chart&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to choose from a range of options for your Chart widget. Filter options are shown in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions.png" alt="Conditions button">in the middle of the dialog box, and chart edit fields in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="pages/platform/pages/conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to data and go to &lt;a href="#chart-view-fields">Chart view fields&lt;/a> to read more about changing how a chart looks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editchart.png" alt="Editing a chart widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option on the left is to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The second option &lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> has 3 radio buttons associated with it a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The third option &lt;strong>Connect to List Widget&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if this widget should connect to List widgets you have created for this dashboard page. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to connect the widgets. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then click into the List Widget field and choose from previously created list widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connecttolist.png" alt="Connect to List widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="#chart-view-fields">Chart view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box to make changes to your chart like size, labels and adding a chart legend.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then click on the &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Selecting a data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chart-view-fields">Chart view fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you choose the Chart widget for your dashboard, there are a number of options to configure the chart to make it look the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/pen.png" alt="Pen button"> in the widget you have created, to see the fields used to &lt;strong>edit the chart&lt;/strong>, visible in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/charteditfields.png" alt="Chart edit fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chart type&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Pie chart b) Bar chart c) Line chart&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Labels field&lt;/strong> - click into the field to drill down to the find what you want to use. You can use &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> such as Status and Created, commonly used in dashboards, and use &lt;strong>design fields&lt;/strong> that are part of processes attached to forms, for example fields within the forms Training Request and Training Approval below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/labelsfield.png" alt="labelsfield">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Values field&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Count b) Sum c) Average and click into the field itself to drill down to the fields you want, as with the &lt;strong>Labels field&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chart width&lt;/strong> - use the arrow to choose a numeric value.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chart width&lt;/strong> - use the arrow to choose a numeric value.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chart height&lt;/strong> - use the arrow to choose a numeric value.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Limit label names&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show values&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide legend&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the chart settings, that is the way the chart looks, title and so on, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and go to &lt;a href="#how-to-edit-chart-widget-settings">How to edit Chart widget settings&lt;/a> to find out more about edit options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits to your widget, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you will see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-chart-widgets">How to move Chart widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-chart-widgets">How to delete Chart widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-chart-widget-settings">How to edit Chart widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 2 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, we could choose to reduce the width of the &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> by clicking to the left of the blue bar which denotes layout column width.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Chart widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard Chart widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walk-through widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Conditions</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/conditions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/conditions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Conditions allow you to make forms and dashboards fully dynamic. They are easy to configure in the Kianda platform, using natural language to create triggers for rule execution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conditions can be applied to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart&lt;/a> dashboard widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure you in &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> on your dashboard page by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button for any Tile, List or Chart widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions.png" alt="Conditions button">in the dialog box that opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Add conditions button"> button to add a condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editconditions.png" alt="Edit conditions">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click into the first empty field to choose a field to filter on, this can be a &lt;strong>Common field&lt;/strong> or a &lt;strong>Design field&lt;/strong> as found in a form. Click on the + symbol to drill down to the relevant fields to use. Click on a field to use, for example the Common field, &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;. If you want to replace the field with a different one, click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/x.png" alt="X"> beside the field name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the operator field and choose from a relevant operator to apply, for example &lt;strong>Equals&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Contains&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is blank&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Matches pattern&lt;/strong> and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/operator.png" alt="Condition operators">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a time-based field is chosen then a drop-down list of time-related operators become available, for example &lt;strong>Is Today&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is Between Days&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is Before Today&lt;/strong> and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Depending on the operator chosen, then a value field may be visible where you can either a) type in a value that you want to hone in on, or b) click into the field to drill down to a design field as found in a form. In the example below, we are looking for a particular value called &amp;lsquo;completed&amp;rsquo; against the Common field, &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditionapplied.png" alt="Condition applied">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add condition&lt;/strong> to add further conditions and group together into an expression using the &lt;strong>drop-down list&lt;/strong> of Boolean operators a) And or b) Or&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expression.png" alt="Conditions">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then add further condition groups using the &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Add conditions button"> button to add and apply the &lt;strong>radio buttons&lt;/strong> of Boolean operators a) And or b) Or to tie groups together.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Delete conditions by clicking on the Bin/Trash button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button again for the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box to apply the changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your dashboard by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> that can be applied to Tile, List and Chart widgets, find out more about all of the types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Custom dashboard widgets</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/</guid><description>
&lt;p>There are currently seven pre-defined dashboard widgets that you can add to your dashboard page. However, you can also create and use your own &lt;strong>customised dashboard widgets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> will only be available to add to your dashboard page from the widget menu if custom widgets have been created by an Administrator or Designer in your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> to a Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open the relevant dashboard page. To learn how to create your first dashboard page, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll open a dashboard page called &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; that currently has a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a> on it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-annual-leave-example2.jpg" alt="Annual Leave dashboard page example 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button from the top dashboard menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-edit-button.jpg" alt="Click Edit current page button to go into Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>down arrow&lt;/strong> button in the Dashboard &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong> to view the available &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-custom.jpg" alt="Select the Rich Text button in the Dashboard Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, there are two custom dashboard widgets available - the &amp;lsquo;Expenses dashboard&amp;rsquo; widget and &amp;lsquo;Welcome Banner&amp;rsquo;. We will use the &lt;strong>Welcome Banner&lt;/strong> custom widget for our example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>This eight type of dashboard widget will only be available to you if Custom dashboard widgets have been created by Administrators or Developers in your Kianda workspace&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens with a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-widget-custom.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> (by replacing the default title shown). In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Welcome&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide, or click to the very end of the bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White), if you choose to display it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Custom widget to be shown in the dashboard. In our example, we will de-select the &amp;lsquo;Show header&amp;rsquo; option so that the header is not shown.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong>. Select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can use the menu on the right to either filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as a Custom dashboard widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong> - This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select which layout container you want your new &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> to be placed in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new Custom dashboard widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens showing the options you can choose for that particular &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong>. The options available will be dependent on the functionality of the custom widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished choosing the options you want (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box without saving).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> will now be displayed on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the insertion of the new widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our example of the &amp;lsquo;Welcome banner&amp;rsquo; custom dashboard widget could look like this when inserted and moved to the top of the dashboard page:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Custom widget Welcome banner example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-custom-dashboard-widgets-are-created">How Custom dashboard widgets are created&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Kianda Administrator or Developer can create &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> by opening the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> menu from the left-side menu and clicking on &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-developer.jpg" alt="Create a Custom field by clicking on Developer from the Administration menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Developer resources page opens and displays all of the Custom widgets that have been created - these include &lt;strong>Custom field widgets&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Custom rule widgets&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Custom Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-widgets.jpg" alt="Create new Custom widget Developer resources page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Only &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> will be shown in the Custom drop-down list in the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong> on dashboard pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create a new Custom dashboard widget, a Developer/Administrator needs to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>New widget&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/custom-field-new-widget.jpg" alt="New widget button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, in which they can choose the Title, Unique ID, Widget icon and Widget type for the new custom widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create a new &lt;strong>Dashboard Widget&lt;/strong>, the Developer/Administrator must choose &amp;lsquo;Dashboard widget&amp;rsquo; as the &lt;strong>Widget type&lt;/strong>, as shown in this example:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget.jpg" alt="Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once the Developer/Administrator has completed the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box and clicks on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, a workspace opens where they can create their Custom dashboard widget (and a pop-up message displays saying &amp;lsquo;Success saving the widget&amp;rsquo;):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-workspace.jpg" alt="Custom widget workspace">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two workspaces that are shown, &lt;strong>Widget UI&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Widget Code&lt;/strong>, show the default code that the Developer/Administrator can then add to this in order to create a dashboard widget with the functionality they want.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When they have finished working on the new custom dashboard widget, they need to click on the &lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong> button and a pop-up message will say &amp;lsquo;Widget updated&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> button to close the custom dashboard widget workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new &lt;strong>custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> will now be listed in the &lt;strong>Widgets&lt;/strong> screen in the Developer section:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-listed.jpg" alt="Custom dashboard widget listed in Widgets in Developer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Designers will now be able to see and use the new custom dashboard widget from the &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong> section of the &lt;strong>Dashboard Widgets menu&lt;/strong> when they are adding widgets to dashboard pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-menu.jpg" alt="Custom dashboard widget example in the widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about how to create &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong>, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/low-code#dashboard-widget">Creating a custom Dashboard widget&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-custom-dashboard-widgets">How to edit Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard page:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings"> and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Custom dashboard widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-update-config.jpg" alt="Select Dashboard Link widget Update configuration button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to make whatever changes are available to you for that particular custom dashboard widget (this will depend on the range of options and functionality the Developer/Administrator who created it gave it). These will be the same options as were outlined in Step 6 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-custom-dashboard-widgets">How to move Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Custom widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard page:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the Custom dashboard widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-move.jpg" alt="Custom dashboard widget drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-custom-dashboard-widgets">How to delete Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-delete.jpg" alt="Delete Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-custom-dashboard-widget-settings">How to edit Custom dashboard widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-widget-settings.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 4 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-custom-edit-widget.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could choose to reduce the width of the &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> to be 4 columns wide, by clicking to the left of the existing blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about &lt;strong>Custom dashboard widgets&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Filter widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> can be used to create a filter or filters that enable you to change the information that is displayed on your dashboard, based on criteria you choose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you have an &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; dashboard that contains a List widget that shows the individual annual leave requests (process instances) submitted by employees, you could add a Filter widget to the dashboard and connect the List widget to it. This would add a Filter widget to your dashboard that enables you to filter the annual leave requests in the List widget by employee name.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> to a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open the relevant dashboard page. To learn how to create your first dashboard page, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll open a dashboard page called &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; that has a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a> on it showing the individual records (process instances) for annual leave requests made by employees:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-annual-leave-example3.jpg" alt="Annual Leave dashboard page example 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button from the top dashboard menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-edit-button.jpg" alt="Click Edit current page button to go into Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> button in the Dashboard &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-filter.jpg" alt="Select the Rich Text button in the Dashboard Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens with a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-widget-filter.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> (instead of the default title that is shown). In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Filter by Employee&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide, or click to the very end of the bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White), if you choose to display it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Dashboard widget to be shown. This checkbox is selected by default, so de-select it if you don&amp;rsquo;t want the header to be displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong>. Select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can use the menu on the right to either filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as the Filter widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong>: This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select the layout container you want to place your new &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new Filter widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens showing the options for the Filter widget:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-settings-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit button links dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the options you want for your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Filter type&lt;/strong>: You can choose the way you want the filter options to be displayed for the end user. The options are &lt;strong>Dropdown list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Radio list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Date range&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Free text&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Current user&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dropdown list&lt;/strong> - Select this option if you want the filter options to be shown in a dropdown list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Radio list&lt;/strong> - Select this option if you want the filter options to be shown in a radio list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Date range&lt;/strong> - Select this option if you want the filter options to be shown as date ranges. If you select &lt;strong>Date range&lt;/strong> as the Filter type, you then have two filter options - &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Date and time&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-date-range-options.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter Widget date range filter options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Free text&lt;/strong> - Select this option if you want the filter options to consist of free text.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Current user&lt;/strong> - Select this option if you want to filter by current user. If you select &lt;strong>Current user&lt;/strong> as the Filter type, you then need to choose the &lt;strong>Current user property&lt;/strong> from a drop-down list:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-current-user.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget filter by Current User filter options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Filter options&lt;/strong> - Once you have chosen the &lt;strong>Filter type&lt;/strong> you want - let&amp;rsquo;s say drop-down list - you can then decide whether the options that the end user can filter are &lt;strong>Manual entries&lt;/strong> (that you input by typing them into the box with the &amp;lsquo;Options one per line&amp;rsquo; placeholder text) or are pulled from a &lt;strong>Data source&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you select &lt;strong>Data source&lt;/strong> to pull the filter options from a data source, four additional options will be shown:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-data-source.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Data source options">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> - If you select &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Data source&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; for creating your filter options, next click on the &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> button. The &lt;strong>Select datasource&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-select-datasource.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget select datasource dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the data source you want to use by selecting one of the available Datasources listed on the left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For our example, we will select &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> as our data source and then select the &amp;lsquo;Annual leave request and approval process&amp;rsquo;. We can do this by either&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(a)&lt;/strong> typing the start of this process name into the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; search field and selecting it when it is displayed below it, or&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-datasource-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Select datasource example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(b)&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Processes&lt;/strong> to show the full list of Kianda processes and scrolling and selecting the one we want&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-datasource-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Select datasource Kianda process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you have selected the data source you want to use. The source you selected will now be shown beneath the &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> button in the &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-datasource-shown.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget data source shown in Filter settings dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> - If you want to add a condition to your filter&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Edit_Conditions_button.jpg" alt="Edit Conditions button">and the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box will open&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Add conditions group&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Add a conditions group button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add the condition you want and click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: To see an example of adding a condition to a filter, see the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Add connections&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option further down.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong> - Choose the field you want displayed as the field options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example - setting up a Filter widget to filter annual leave requests by employee name - we chose a Kianda process as the data source for the filter options, so when we click on the Display field, we can then expand the relevant form (Request form) and select the field we want to filter by:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-display-field-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard filter widget select Display field example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> - Choose the value you want displayed as the field options. Typically, the same field will be chosen as both the Display field and Value field (but you could choose different fields as needed).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we will select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Employee Name&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; field from the &amp;lsquo;Request form&amp;rsquo; in the &amp;lsquo;Annual leave request and approval process&amp;rsquo; for both the Display field and Value field:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-display-field.jpg" alt="Dashboard filter select Display field and Value field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Filter mode&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether the filter widget displays options that &lt;strong>start with&lt;/strong> the letters or words the user types into the filter widget search box or shows filter options that &lt;strong>contain&lt;/strong> the letters or words the user inputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default value&lt;/strong> - You can choose a Default value to appear in the Filter widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable query string&lt;/strong> - This option appears for all Filter types except for Date range and Current user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable a query string:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Enable query string&lt;/strong> checkbox.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Insert the &lt;strong>unique field name&lt;/strong> of the field you want to filter by into the box with the &amp;lsquo;Parameter name&amp;rsquo; placeholder text.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-enable-query-string.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Enable query string option">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong> - You can find the unique field name by going to the form that contains the field and clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button to open the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box and copying the unique field name from the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Name (Unique)&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we can find the &lt;strong>unique field name&lt;/strong> we need to enable a query string by&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Opening the Annual Leave process&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Selecting the &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo; field in the Annual Leave Request form - the field we want to filter by in our Filter widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Opening the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box to find the field&amp;rsquo;s unique name:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-query-string-uniquename.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Query string example field unique name">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In our &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box, we can now select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Enable query string&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; checkbox and insert this unique field name into the Parameter name box - we will also select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Auto update URL&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option (which will dynamically construct a URL, meaning that the URL at the top of the page will automatically change when we choose a filter option):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-query-string-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard filter widget Enable query string example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you complete the &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> and then click the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button in the top menu, you will now see that when you select an employee in the Filter widget, the URL at the top updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-query-string-url.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget enable query string Auto update URL example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Setting the filter up like this to automatically update the URL when a filter option is selected enables you to make any of the filter selections a &lt;strong>dashboard favourite&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, we could now choose to make this filter selection - Maddy Leenane&amp;rsquo;s annual leave requests - a favourited dashboard page by clicking on the &lt;strong>Add to favourites&lt;/strong> button in the top menu and completing the &lt;strong>Add to favourite&lt;/strong> dialog box that opens:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-query-string-favourited.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget enable query string auto update URL add to favourites example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Add connections&lt;/strong> - Click on the &lt;strong>Add connections&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-add-connection.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Add connection button"> if you want to &lt;strong>add a filter connection to an existing widget on the dashboard&lt;/strong>, so that the data displayed in that widget is filtered based on the option selected in the Filter widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Filter connection&lt;/strong> dialog box opens - click on the down arrow and select the dashboard widget you want to connect to:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-widget-connection.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget Filter connection dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then choose to add filter conditions to the widget filter connection by&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(a) clicking on the &lt;strong>Add filter conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-add-filter-conditions.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget filter connection Add filter conditions button">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(b) clicking the &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget filter connection Add a conditions group button">in the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box that opens&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-widget-connection-conditions.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget filter connection Edit conditions dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(c) completing the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box to apply conditions to the widget filter connection and then clicking on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we would add a filter condition to the widget filter connection by selecting &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo; in the field on the left and &amp;lsquo;Filter value&amp;rsquo; in the field on the right. This will ensure that the &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo; field will display as the filter value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-widget-connection-conditionex.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget connection filter condition example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed the &lt;strong>Filter connection&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>. The widget you have connected to the new Filter widget will now be shown under &lt;strong>Widget connections&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-widget-connection-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget Widget connections example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished choosing the options you want for your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> dialog box without saving).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the top dashboard menu to save the insertion of the new Filter widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your new &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> will now be displayed on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Our example of a &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> for the &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; dashboard - where the filter allows users to filter the Annual Leave Request records in the existing List Widget by employee name - could look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When the user clicks on the down arrow button in the Filter widget, the names of employees who have submitted an Annual Leave Request are shown in a drop-down list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The user can then select an employee name from the drop-down list and the List widget to the right will automatically update to only show Annual Leave Request records (process instances) submitted by that employee. This is because we used the &lt;strong>Widget connection&lt;/strong> option to connect that List widget to the new Filter widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-example2.jpg" alt="Dashboard Filter widget example connected to a List widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-filter-widgets">How to edit Filter widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings"> and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Filter widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-update-config.jpg" alt="Select Dashboard Link widget Update configuration button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Filter settings&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to make whatever changes you want to the filter using the same range of options as outlined in Step 6 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-filter-widgets">How to move Filter widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could move the new Filter widget to the top left of the dashboard: &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-move.jpg" alt="Move a Dashboard Link widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-filter-widgets">How to delete Filter widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-delete.jpg" alt="Delete Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-filter-widget-settings">How to edit Filter widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-edit-widget-settings.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 4 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-filter-edit-widget.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could choose to reduce the width of the &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> to be 4 columns wide, by clicking to the left of the existing blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Filter widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard Filter widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Link widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> can be used to create a button link on a dashboard page that initiates a new process instance (by bringing the user straight into the first form of a particular process), links to another dashboard or links to an external website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> to a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open the relevant dashboard page. To learn how to create your first dashboard page, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll open a dashboard page called &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; that currently has a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a> on it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-annual-leave-example2.jpg" alt="Annual Leave dashboard page example 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button from the top dashboard menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-edit-button.jpg" alt="Click Edit current page button to go into Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> button in the Dashboard &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-link.jpg" alt="Select the Rich Text button in the Dashboard Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens with a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-widget-link2.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong>. In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Start New Process&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide, or click to the very end of the bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White), if you choose to display it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Dashboard widget to be shown. You will need to select this checkbox if you want the Link widget header to be displayed, as it is not selected by default. If the widget header is not shown, the user will just see the link button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong>. Select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can use the menu on the right to either filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as a Link widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong> - This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select which layout container you want your new &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> to be placed in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new Link widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit button links&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens showing the Link widget title you inserted in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-edit-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit button links dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the title of the &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> or on the &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-edit-icon.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link edit link button"> to open the &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: You can click on the &lt;strong>Add link&lt;/strong> button to add &lt;strong>more link buttons&lt;/strong> to the Link widget. You will be able to edit the options relating to each of these &lt;em>individual link buttons&lt;/em> by clicking on their title or on their &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the options you want for this link button in your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-edit-link-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit link dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options available for your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link text&lt;/strong> - You can insert the text you want to appear on your Link widget button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Process/ Dashboard/ External&lt;/strong> - You can select whether you want the Link widget to link to a new instance of an existing Kianda process, to an existing dashboard or to an external website.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you select to link to a &lt;strong>New Process&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the down arrow in the &lt;strong>Target process&lt;/strong> field to open a drop-down list of Kianda processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the Kianda &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> that you want to open when the user clicks on the Link widget. You can type the start of a process name into the field so the drop-down list is filtered to show processes starting with that letter or word.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we will select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Annual leave request and approval process&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; as the &lt;strong>Target process&lt;/strong> for our new &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong>; this will mean that a new instance of the &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave request form&amp;rsquo; will open when the user clicks on the &amp;lsquo;Start New Process&amp;rsquo; Link widget button on the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you want the process to open in a pop-up dialog box without the user leaving the dashboard page, select the &lt;strong>Show in dialog?&lt;/strong> checkbox. Otherwise, the user will be brought directly into the first form in the process that you have linked to.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you select to link to a &lt;strong>Dashboard&lt;/strong>, the option below it changes to &lt;strong>Target dashboard&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the down arrow in the &lt;strong>Target dashboard&lt;/strong> field to open a drop-down-list of Kianda processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-dashboard.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget linking to a dashboard">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the Kianda &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> that you want to open when the user clicks on the link button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you select to link to an &lt;strong>External&lt;/strong> website, two options display below it - &lt;strong>URL&lt;/strong> and &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Open in new window?&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-external.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget linking to an External website">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the URL you want the user to be brought to when they click on the Link widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Open in new window?&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; checkbox if you want the external website to open in a new window.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>QueryString parameters&lt;/strong> - Complete this field if you want to pass a query string when the user clicks on the link. For example, you may want the current user&amp;rsquo;s email address to be pre-populated in a form you are linking to.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>As an example, let&amp;rsquo;s say that when the user clicks on the link in the Link widget, you want the First Name field of the new Annual Leave Request form they are brought to to be pre-populated with the name &amp;lsquo;John&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To do this, insert the unique name of that field, as well as the value you want that field to be pre-populated with into the &lt;strong>QueryString parameters&lt;/strong> box - in this case that will be &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>firstName=John&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;. [The grey text that appears in the QueryString parameters field when you open the dialog box - param1=value1 is just placeholder text.]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-query-string-parameters.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget query string parameters example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: The unique name of a field can be found by selecting the field in the form it is in and clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button. The field&amp;rsquo;s unique name can then be copied from the &lt;strong>Name (Unique)&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, the unique name of the &amp;lsquo;First Name&amp;rsquo; field in the &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave Request&amp;rsquo; form is &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>firstName&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-unique-name.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget example of field unique name">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For our query string parameter example to work, we now need to add an On load &lt;strong>Set form field rule&lt;/strong> (that is, a rule that is executed when the form is opened that will run a query string to automatically populate a field in the form).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this, we go to Designer, and add a &lt;strong>Set form field&lt;/strong> rule to execute when the form is loaded. In our example, the rule will set the &amp;lsquo;First Name&amp;rsquo; field when the form is loaded:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-query-string-set-form-field.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget query string form on load rule example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the rule has been saved, it can be viewed in the &lt;strong>On load rules&lt;/strong> section of the right side menu when the process is opened:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-query-string-onload.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget query string on load rule example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about the &lt;strong>Set form field&lt;/strong> rule, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/set-form-field/">Set form field rule&lt;/a> or to learn more about Rules in general, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link icon&lt;/strong> - You can choose the icon you want to appear on your Link widget button. Click on the down arrow and select the icon you want to use from the large number of options available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-icon.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget link icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text colour&lt;/strong> - You can choose the colour of the text that appears on the Link widget button. For example, if we choose orange, our Link widget button could look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-button-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget button example with orange text">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link size&lt;/strong> - You can choose the width of the Link widget button, from 1 column wide to 12 columns wide. Change the width by clicking on the blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link visible to administrators only?&lt;/strong> - Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you want to limit the visibility of this particular link button in the Link widget to Kianda Administrators only.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link security (optional)&lt;/strong> - You can limit visibility of this link button - the &amp;lsquo;Start New Process&amp;rsquo; link, in our example - in the Link widget by selecting the user(s) and/or group(s) you want to be able to see it on the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo; to the &amp;lsquo;Link visible to administrators only&amp;rsquo; option, you could then add in other users (in addition to administrators) who you want to be able to see the link button using this &amp;lsquo;Link security&amp;rsquo; option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: If you have multiple button links in your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong>, you can limit the users/groups who can view &lt;em>each&lt;/em> of the link buttons within that Link widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished choosing the options you want for your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the &lt;strong>Edit link&lt;/strong> dialog box without saving).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> will now be displayed on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the insertion of the new widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-widget-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-link-text-widgets">How to edit Link Text widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings"> and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Link widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Select Dashboard Link widget Update configuration button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit button links&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to make whatever changes you want to the link button(s) in the Link widget using the same range of options as outlined in Step 6 of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-link-widgets">How to move Link widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, we could move the new Link widget to the top left of the dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-move.jpg" alt="Move a Dashboard Link widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-link-widgets">How to delete Link widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-delete.jpg" alt="Delete Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-link-widget-settings">How to edit Link widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-edit-widget-settings.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 4 of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-link-edit-widget.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could choose to reduce the width of the &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> to be 4 columns wide, by clicking to the left of the existing blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Link widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard Link widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: List widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> displays the instances of the selected process in a dashboard. The List widget can also be used to connect with any other dashboard widgets to display filtered items.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the List widget &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listwidget.png" alt="List widget">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-list-add.jpg" alt="Add list widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the dashboard title, for example Training Requests&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - control the size of the dashboard, choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you wish to show a header on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong>. Select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can use the menu on the right to either filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as a dashboard List widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong> - This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select which layout container you want your new &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> to be placed in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new List widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - choose from icons for deshtop, tablet, mobile, wifi and flightmode as to when the device can view the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the dashboard to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the widget to display certain fields from your form, that relates to the data you are interested in. Go to &lt;a href="#configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To re-edit the title, colour scheme or other options in Step 2, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box options, allowing you to make changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the widget at any stage, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> beside the cog button, and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button in a list widget you have created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton.png" alt="Chart widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A dialog box opens with filter options in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions.png" alt="Conditions">in the middle of the box, and list view fields in the right-hand pane. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to dashboard widgets and go to &lt;a href="#list-view-fields">List view fields&lt;/a> to read more about how to apply fields to your list view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listconfig.png" alt="Editing options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once a data source is chosen, then there are a number of other options available, see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dataprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong>. You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Data source filter&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="filter-options">Filter options&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you have chosen where the dashboard data will come from then there are a number of other options available.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable sorting&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable sorting in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable filtering&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable filtering in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable search&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable a search in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable &amp;ldquo;Load more&amp;rdquo; mode&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable more data records to be visible. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you can decide on what text should appear on screen, by typing the text in the &lt;strong>Load more button text&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter a number in &lt;strong>Items per page&lt;/strong> for the number items you wish to load at a time. The default value is &amp;lsquo;20&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show &amp;lsquo;Add process&amp;rsquo; button&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to Add process to your dashboard. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you can decide on what text should appear on screen, by typing the text in the &lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;Add process&amp;rsquo; button text&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, the process used to generate the data is added, click on &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> beside the Add &amp;lsquo;Process Name&amp;rsquo; by default if you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to add the input process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show delete button&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to add a Delete button to your dashboard. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then the option &lt;strong>Enable bulk delete&lt;/strong> appears allowing you to choose a) Yes or b) No to enable bulk deletion of records.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable show history&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to show the history of the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable data export&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to allow data export.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sort by - click into the Sort By field and choose from options a) Common fields or b) fields within a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> are fields commonly used in dashboards such as &amp;lsquo;Created&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo; or choose from a field within a form by clicking and drilling down to the field name that you want to sort by, for example a text box field called &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; in a form called &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When a field is chosen then the options for &lt;strong>Sort Direction&lt;/strong> appear as either a) Ascending or b) Descending.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable empty list template&lt;/strong> - click on a) Yes or b) No to enable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="#list-view-fields">List view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box on how to choose fields to filter data.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="list-view-fields">List view fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you choose the List widget for your dashboard, there are a number of ways to select fields that you want to view.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/pen.png" alt="Pen button">n the widget you have created, to see the &lt;strong>List view fields&lt;/strong> visible in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listconfig_frame.png" alt="List view fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> to see a list of commonly used dashboard fields such as &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Created by&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Modified&amp;rsquo;. Click on as many fields as needed to add to the dashboard, for example 3 fields are selected below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/commonfields.png" alt="Common fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> again to close the options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong> to see a list of all the fields used in the design of the forms used in the chosen process. For example the Training Process shown below has 2 forms, &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; and all control fields used in the form design are available to choose as filters for the dashboard. Click on the + symbol to drill down into the form, and click on the relevant fields to use them, for example Name, Type of Training and Management Decision have been chosen below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/designfields.png" alt="Design fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong> again to close the options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on &lt;strong>List fields&lt;/strong> shows you a list of all the fields you have already chosen from &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong>. There is also an option to &lt;strong>Add column&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Add action&lt;/strong>. You can change the order of the fields as they appear in the list from left to right by clicking on the Drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite.png" alt="Drag handle">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listfields.png" alt="List fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the list settings, that is the way the list looks, title and so on, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and go to &lt;a href="#how-to-edit-list-widget-settings">How to edit List widget settings&lt;/a> to find out more about edit options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have completed your changes, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> to save your changes or &lt;strong>X&lt;/strong> to quit without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-list-widgets">How to move List widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-list-widgets">How to delete List widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-list-widget-settings">How to edit List widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 2 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, we could choose to reduce the width of the &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> to be 4 columns wide, by clicking to the left of the existing blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard List widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Rich Text widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> can be used to create custom rich text content on a dashboard page, such as an attractive banner or heading. It can provide optimum formatting options, such as bold and italics and the option to insert images or links.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> to a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open the relevant dashboard page. To learn how to create your first dashboard page, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll open a dashboard page called &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave&amp;rsquo; that currently only has a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a> on it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-annual-leave-example.jpg" alt="Annual Leave dashboard page example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button from the top dashboard menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-edit-button.jpg" alt="Click Edit current page button to go into Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> button in the Dashboard &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-richtext.jpg" alt="Select the Rich Text button in the Dashboard Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens with a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong>. In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Information&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Dashboard widget to be shown.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can determine who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong>. You can select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. You can select Users or Groups in the right-hand menu so that the options shown in the drop-down list are either individual users or Groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit content&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-edit-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Rich Text widget Edit content dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the content you want to appear in your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> by using the available options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the text you want to appear in the body of the &lt;strong>Edit content&lt;/strong> dialog box. You can choose from an wide array of styles and formats, including: &lt;strong>Style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Colour&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Bold&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Underline&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Remove font style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font size&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font family&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Unordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Ordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Paragraph&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also choose to insert a &lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong> or to switch to &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong> (if you click on &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/code.png" alt="Code view button">you can copy HTML code directly into the text).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong> an &lt;strong>Insert Picture&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, allowing you to either browse to select an image file or to insert an image URL (as shown here):&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-image.jpg" alt="Dashboard Rich Text widget insert image dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For our example, we will insert text details relating to the Annual Leave dashboard, format them as we want, and also insert a suitable image:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-edit-content.jpg" alt="Dashboard Rich Text widget Edit content dialog box example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished inserting the content you want in your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> will now be displayed on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the insertion of the new widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Rich Text widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-rich-text-widgets">How to edit Rich Text widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings"> and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Rich Text widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-edit-example.jpg" alt="Select Dashboard Rich Text widget Update configuration button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit content&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to make whatever changes you want to the content of the Rich Text widget using the same range of options as outlined in Step 6 of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-rich-text-widgets">How to move Rich Text widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, we could move the new Rich Text widget to the left of the List widget:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-move.jpg" alt="Move a Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-rich-text-widgets">How to delete Rich Text widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-delete.jpg" alt="Delete Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-rich-text-widget-settings">How to edit Rich Text widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-edit-widget-settings.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Create widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 4 of &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-richtext-edit-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Rich Text widget Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could choose to make increase the width of the &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> to be 7 columns wide, by clicking to the right of the existing blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Rich Text widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard Rich Text widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widget&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough">Walkthrough widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Tile widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Tile widget&lt;/strong> allows you to display a count of instances. This is a really useful way to showcase whole numbers for example total budget requested through Purchase Orders, or the amount of customer queries solved in a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the Tile widget &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/tile.png" alt="Tile widget button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addtilewidget.png" alt="Add tile widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the dashboard title, for example Type of Training&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - control the size of the dashboard, choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you wish to show a header on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - determine who will see the dashboard, choose from a) Users b) Groups&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - choose from icons for deshtop, tablet, mobile, wifi and flightmode as to when the device can view the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the dashboard to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the widget to display certain fields from your form, that relates to the data you are interested in. Go to &lt;a href="#configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To re-edit the title, colour scheme or other options in Step 2, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box options, allowing you to make changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the widget at any stage, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> beside the cog button, and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button in a tile widget you have created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittile.png" alt="Tile widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A dialog box opens with filter options in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="C:%5CKianda%5Cdocs-dev%5Cpages%5Ctile.assets%5Cconditions.png" alt="Conditions">in the middle of the box, and tile view fields in the right-hand pane. Go to &lt;a href="pages/conditions.md">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to data, and go to &lt;a href="pages/tileviewfields.md">Tile view fields&lt;/a> to read more about changing how a tile looks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittilebox.png" alt="Editing a tile widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option on the left is to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The second option &lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> has 3 radio buttons associated with it a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The third option &lt;strong>Show decimals&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if a decimal point is used in the number displayed. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to only show a whole number.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fourth option &lt;strong>Connect to List widget&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if this widget should connect to List widgets you have created for this dashboard page. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to connect the widgets. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then click into the List Widget field and choose from previously created list widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connecttolist.png" alt="Connect to List widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="pages/tileviewfields.md">Tile view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box to make changes to your tile like icons and colours.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then click on the &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Selecting a data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Walk-through widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A dashboard &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> can be used to walk a user through the features of a dashboard or steps in a process by displaying a series of prompts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you have a Procurement dashboard page that displays key information relating to your procurement process (using &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widgets&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widgets&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a> and a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>), it could be useful to insert a Walk-through widget that can bring a new user through the various features of the page or through steps in the procurement process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> to a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open the relevant dashboard page. To learn how to create your first dashboard page, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll open a dashboard page called &amp;lsquo;All Procurement&amp;rsquo; that has several widgets on it displaying various information relating to a procurement process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-all-procurement-example.jpg" alt="Annual Leave dashboard page example 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button from the top dashboard menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-edit-button.jpg" alt="Click Edit current page button to go into Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> button in the Dashboard &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-walkthrough.jpg" alt="Select the Rich Text button in the Dashboard Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens with a range of options for your new &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-widget-walkthrough.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose the options you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can insert the title you want for your &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> (instead of the default title shown). In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Procurement Walk through&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - You can choose how wide you want your &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> to be. You can choose from 1 to 12 columns in width by clicking on the blue bar. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a widget that is 6 columns wide, or click to the very end of the bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six colour options for the header of the widget (Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White), if you choose to display it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> - You can choose whether or not you want the header of your Dashboard widget to be shown. This checkbox is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> selected by default, so select it if you want the widget header to be displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - You can choose who will be able to see the &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong>. You can select single or multiple Users or Groups, or a combination of the two. Use the menu on the right to filter the drop-down list by Users or Groups. To find out more about pre-defined Groups on Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users">Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note - Dashboard page security&lt;/strong>: When a dashboard page is first created, the users(s)/group(s) who will be able to view the dashboard are selected in the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; option in the &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box (see Step 3 in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-create-a-dashboard-page">How to create a Dashboard page&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also edit or update this setting at any point to change who has permission to view a particular dashboard page. This higher dashboard-level security setting will take precedence over the security settings (&amp;lsquo;Visible to&amp;rsquo;) that are applied to the &lt;em>individual widgets&lt;/em> within the dashboard (such as the Filter widget, in this case).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security#widget-security">Widget security&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout container&lt;/strong>: This option will only display if you have already created layout containers for your Dashboard page. Here, you can select the layout container you want to place your new &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A layout container is a simple way to organise, arrange and move the widgets you add to your dashboard. To learn more about layout containers, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#how-to-add-layout-containers-to-a-dashboard-page">How to add layout containers to a Dashboard page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this example, we can select to place our new Filter widget into one of three layout containers - Top, Middle or Bottom:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-select-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add widget dialog box select Layout container">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - You can choose what devices and types of internet connections the dashboard &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> will be visible on - select all the options you want from Desktop, Tablet, Mobile, Wi-Fi and Flight mode as to when the device can view the dashboards. By default, all options are selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> dialog box automatically opens showing the options for the Walk-through widget:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-steps.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit button links dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the options you want for your &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can give your Walk-through a title. In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;Procurement Walk-through&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> - This is where you can add all of the individual walk-through steps that you want to bring the user through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add your first walk-through step:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Add step&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-add-step.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Add step button"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit step&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, allowing you to choose from a range of options for your walk-through step.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the options in the &lt;strong>Edit step&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to add the step to the &lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Repeat these three steps to add as many steps as you want to your Walk-through widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-edit-step-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Edit step dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options for the first step in your Walk-through widget in the &lt;strong>Edit step&lt;/strong> dialog box include:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - Insert a title for this walk-through step. In our example, we&amp;rsquo;ll title our first step &amp;lsquo;Welcome step&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step type&lt;/strong> - You have a choice of three step types: &lt;strong>Popup&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>App Navigation&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Element click&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a. A &lt;strong>Popup step&lt;/strong> is a pop-up dialog box containing whatever content you choose to display (including texts, links or pictures).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. An &lt;strong>App Navigation step&lt;/strong> brings the user to a new URL - for example, it could bring them into the first form of a process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. An &lt;strong>Element click step&lt;/strong> shows the result of clicking on one of the elements in the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="popup-steps">&lt;strong>Popup Steps&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>Popup&lt;/strong> as the step type, you can then complete the &lt;strong>Popup content&lt;/strong> box to insert the content you want to appear in the pop-up walk-through step, including text, images or links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can choose from an wide array of styles and formats, including: &lt;strong>Style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Colour&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Bold&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Underline&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Remove font style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font size&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font family&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Unordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Ordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Paragraph&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong> (which allows you to switch to a code view of the step content) and &lt;strong>Help&lt;/strong> (which displays a range of shortcut keys for different formatting options).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we will make the first step of our walk-through a Popup and will insert the content we want to appear:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-popup.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Popup step example">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="example---pop-up-step">Example - Pop-up step&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This first Popup walk-through step could look like this to the end user when they click on the &lt;strong>Procurement Walk-through&lt;/strong> widget:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-popup-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Popup example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Element selector&lt;/strong> field at the bottom of the &lt;strong>Edit step&lt;/strong> dialog box can be used if you want an element on the page to be highlighted, to show the user where they need to click.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We could add a second step in our walk-through to be another pop-up that explains that the user should click the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>New Procurement Process&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; button to start a new procurement process. This time we can add an &lt;strong>Element selector&lt;/strong> so that the button is highlighted during this step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-element-selector.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget element selector example">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-find-the-name-of-an-element-to-insert">How to find the name of an element to insert&lt;/h5>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Right-click on the element on the page that you want to higlight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our case, we right-click on the New Procurement Process link button on the dashboard (as this is what we want to highlight during this step of the walk-through).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-element-inspect.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Element selector inspect">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Inspect&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Copy the element you want to be highlighted in this walk-through step. In our case, we copy the element relating to the New Procurement Process link button:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-element-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget element example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Paste the name of the element into the &lt;strong>Element selector&lt;/strong> box in the &lt;strong>Edit step&lt;/strong> dialog box. You can choose the position of the pop-up text in relation to the element being highlighted from the &lt;strong>Position&lt;/strong> drop-down menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="example---element-selector">Example - Element Selector&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This Popup step that includes an &lt;strong>Element selector&lt;/strong> could look like this to the end user as the second step in the walk-through:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-element-example2.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget Element selector example Step 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="app-navigation-steps">&lt;strong>App Navigation steps&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>App Navigation&lt;/strong> as the step type, complete the &lt;strong>Destination URL&lt;/strong> field that appears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we will make the third step of our walk-through an App Navigation step type and will title it &amp;lsquo;Go to Procurement form&amp;rsquo;. The URL inserted as the Destination URL will bring the user into the first form of the Procurement process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-app-nav.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget App Navigation example">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="example---app-navigation">Example - App Navigation&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This third App Navigation step in our walk-through example could look like this to the end user - the user is brought to the website we insered as the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Destination URL&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-app-nav-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough App Navigation example">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="element-click-steps">&lt;strong>Element click steps&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>Element click&lt;/strong> as the step type, complete the &lt;strong>Element selector&lt;/strong> field that appears - see &lt;a href="#how-to-find-the-name-of-an-element-to-insert">How to find the name of an element to insert&lt;/a> to find out how to find the code to insert in order to show different clickable elements of the dashboard or process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Auto-start&lt;/strong> - Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you want the Walk-through widget to automatically launch when a user opens the dashboard page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On tour end return to starting page&lt;/strong> - Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you want the user to be returned to the dashboard page once the Walk-through steps have been completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> any of the walk-through steps you added to the &lt;strong>Walkthrough steps&lt;/strong> dialog box by simply clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button to the right of the step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-step-delete.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget delete a walkthrough step">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed the &lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> dialog box - by choosing the options and adding the steps you want - click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The completed &lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> dialog box for our simplified example could look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-steps-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget completed Walkthrough steps dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the top dashboard menu to save the insertion of the new Walk-through widget to the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Your new &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> will now be shown on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Procurement walk-through&lt;/strong> widget could look like this on our All Procurement dashboard:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-example.jpg" alt="Dashboard Walkthrough widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-walk-through-widgets">How to edit Walk-through widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to view the page in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a> (in which the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings">, &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin trash button"> and &lt;strong>Add layout container&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-add-layout-container.jpg" alt="Dashboard Add layout container button"> are available).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Walk-through widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> (Edit) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-update-configuration.jpg" alt="Dashboard update configuration button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-update-config.jpg" alt="Select Dashboard Walkthrough widget Update configuration button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Walk-through steps&lt;/strong> dialog box opens, enabling you to make whatever changes you want to the Walk-through widget using the same range of options as outlined in Step 6 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> but also showing the walk-through steps you created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Making the changes you want and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> will be shown on the Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-move-walk-through-widgets">How to move Walk-through widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> on a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-widget-draghandle.jpg" alt="Dashboard widget drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the widget where you want it to go on your dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, we could move the new &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Procurement Walk-through&lt;/strong> widget to the top right section of the dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-move.jpg" alt="Move a Dashboard Link widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-delete-walk-through-widgets">How to delete Walk-through widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> from your dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Remove widget&lt;/strong> (Bin/Trash icon) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-delete.jpg" alt="Delete Dashboard Rich Text widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Delete widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the widget (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-delete-widget-dialog.jpg" alt="Dashboard Delete widget dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-walk-through-widget-settings">How to edit Walk-through widget settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update or edit your &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your dashboard, click on the &lt;strong>Edit current page&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-current-page.jpg" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu to go into &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages#dashboards-edit-mode">Dashboard Edit mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update widget settings&lt;/strong> (Cog) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-edit-widget-settings.jpg" alt="Dashboard Update widget settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to make changes to any of the available options (the same options as were available in the &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box discussed in Step 4 of &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-walkthrough-edit-widget.jpg" alt="Dashboard Link widget Edit widget dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could change the width of the &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> to be 6 columns wide (the same width as the tiles beside and below it on the dashboard), by clicking on the blue bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made to the widget settings (or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to retain any changes).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The updated &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> will display on your dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu to save the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes">Saving changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make to your &lt;strong>Walk-through widget&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboard-save-button.jpg" alt="Dashboard Save button"> in the dashboard top menu. If you leave the dashboard without saving the changes you have made to a widget, the next time you visit the dashboard it won&amp;rsquo;t include any of the changes made to it since the dashboard page was last saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Dashboard Walk-through widget&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Dashboard widgets&lt;/strong> you can add to your Kianda dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/">Chart widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/">Filter widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/">Link widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/">Rich Text widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/">Tile widget&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>