<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Getting started with Kianda processes</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started with Kianda processes on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Process instance</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/process-instance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/process-instance/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kianda processes are made up of &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong>, which in turn contain &lt;strong>fields&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong>. Fields are used to take in user input, make calculations, display values and so on, and rules are used to execute actions to drive the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Kianda Designer&lt;/strong> is used to create these forms and form elements within a process. Each process in Kianda Designer will have it’s own unique link or URL and this can be shared with other form designers for co-creation, for example, for a process named ‘Training process’ the link is:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://green-itr.kianda.com/admin/designer/training-process">https://green-itr.kianda.com/admin/designer/training-process&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="process-instances">Process instances&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When your process is created in Kianda Designer, you can save the process, and then &lt;strong>submit data&lt;/strong> to that process. When you save or submit data, then an &lt;strong>instance&lt;/strong> of the process is created. Another name for a process instance is a &lt;strong>record&lt;/strong>. This instance is tied to user data or calculated values, or to whatever the process is designed to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The instance has a unique ID which can be seen in a list widget in a &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong>. For example, this List widget displays the individual records of various training requests submitted by employees. The unique ID for each record is shown in the first column. Form owners or those with security access can click on ID ‘training-request-and-feedback-process-26’ to view the training request form completed and submitted by employee Mark Donnelli.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>List widget in a dashboard showing process instances&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-instance.jpg" alt="Process instance example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that each new record generated by a process will have its own unique URL that can be shared with those who have the required security access and need to be involved in that &lt;strong>particular process instance&lt;/strong>. For example, in this case, the training request submitted by Mark (an employee) may be viewed and approved by his line manager:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://green-itr.kianda.com/forms/training-request-and-feedback-process-26">https://green-itr.kianda.com/forms/training-request-and-feedback-process-26&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can create a link on your dashboard – in the example shown above, the &lt;strong>Start new process&lt;/strong> button at the top right of the Training Requests list widget – that enables you to create a &lt;strong>new record&lt;/strong> by bringing you into the relevant form. For information on creating list widgets go to &lt;a href="docs/platform/pages/list/">List widget&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you commit to the process by &lt;strong>submitting or saving information&lt;/strong>, then the result is a new process instance – that is, a new unique record – which will be seen in a list widget in the dashboard, as seen in the image above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping in mind that Designer is used to create processes, and that each ‘run’ of the process design results in a unique process instance or record, will help you later on when designing forms and dashboards. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/">Process settings&lt;/a> for more details on process settings and parameters and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/">Dashboards&lt;/a> for more information on dashboards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process settings</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a number of properties and settings that you can implement to your process and forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Settings and properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settingsprocess.png" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Settings are available from the right-hand pane and give you the ability to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/how-to/reuse-or-clone-process-elements/">Import processes&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>View &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/version-history/">Version history&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Change &lt;a href="#process-settings">Process settings&lt;/a> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Edit form information by selecting a form and clicking on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Change a field to another field by clicking on &lt;strong>Change field&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create a duplicate form by selecting a form, clicking on the &lt;strong>Clone&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clone.png" alt="Clone button"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong>. A version called &amp;lsquo;Form Name Copy&amp;rsquo; is created and available to edit on the canvas. The &lt;strong>Clone&lt;/strong> button can also be used to clone form elements like controls or buttons.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Delete a form by selecting a form, clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the form title and you are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>View and edit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/">Form properties&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="process-settings">Process settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can edit process settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings button"> in the right-hand pane. &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-settings-tabs.jpg" alt="Process settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within process settings, there are four tabs to navigate to:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-general">1. &lt;strong>General&lt;/strong>:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-settings-general.jpg" alt="Process settings general tab">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process ID Settings&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Default or b) Custom and use a combination of [ProcessName]-[UniqueNumber]-[FieldName]&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On load rules execution mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Always b) When in edit mode or c) When open new. The default setting is &lt;strong>Always&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable form assignment notification?&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prevent closing instance with unsaved data?&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable process navigator?&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No. If you select Yes, the Process navigator tab will appear in the right hand panel, allowing you to quickly snap to and view desired form controls and rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-navigator-panel.jpg" alt="Process navigator panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-navigator-selection.jpg" alt="Process navigator selection">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="2-security">2. &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong>:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-settings-security.jpg" alt="Process settings security tab">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable process security&lt;/strong> - if you tick the checkbox, can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to have certain privileges related to the radio button options to create, assign and view as shown below. The default setting is &lt;strong>Security users can create, assign to can update, everyone else can view&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instance delete settings&lt;/strong> - options are a) Any user can delete b) Creator can delete c) &amp;ldquo;Current form owner&amp;rdquo; can delete d) &amp;ldquo;Security users&amp;rdquo; can delete e) &amp;ldquo;Admins only&amp;rdquo; can delete. The default setting is &lt;strong>Creator can delete&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="3-tabs">3. &lt;strong>Tabs&lt;/strong>:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-settings-tabs2.jpg" alt="Process settings tabs tab">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide form tabs&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to hide form tabs, options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide left nav&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to hide navigation elements, options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable mobile navigation?&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Selected tab theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White as a colour when a form is selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Completed tab theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White as a colour when a form is completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="4-anonymous-form">4. &lt;strong>Anonymous Form&lt;/strong>:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-settings-anonymous2.jpg" alt="Link for external users">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable anonymous sharing of forms&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to share forms with people outside your organisation for example a feedback form or GDPR subject access request. Options are a) Yes or b) No. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> there are various options that you can add:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>New link&lt;/strong> to generate a new anonymous form link to share with users and click on &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> to change the link.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Message to display after anonymous submission&lt;/strong> - to add a display message.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hide form topbar&lt;/strong> - checkbox to hide the form topbar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Force authenticated user to log out&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No to force the authenticated user to log out once the form is submitted. If &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> is selected, you can choose to &lt;strong>Redirect authenticated user to&lt;/strong>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Process URL&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Workspace Home&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The result is a globally available link to allow external users to create a &lt;strong>new instance&lt;/strong>. You can use the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/anonymous-form-link/">&lt;strong>Anonymous form link Rule&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> to generate a new anonymous link at runtime that will point to an &lt;strong>existing process instance&lt;/strong> that can be shared with external users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the process settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit process"> to go back to the process list, the Save button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> to save your work, the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview"> to preview what you have created and the &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/publish.png" alt="Publish button"> to publish your work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To learn more about rules and controls that can be applied to forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">&lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To learn more about properties, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/">&lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process properties</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Every process, form and control, such as text boxes and lists, will have &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> visible in the right-hand pane of the &lt;a href="platform/form_designer2.md">Designer&lt;/a> view.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="process-properties">Process properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; click on a process &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, you will see the properties for the chosen process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following properties are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Title - the title of process for example Quarterly Training Request&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Page layout - you can click on &lt;strong>Wide&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/wide-resized.png" alt="Wide button"> or &lt;strong>Narrow&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/narrow-resized.png" alt="Narrow button"> to change the layout.
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/formlayout_resized.png" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the image above, the process &amp;lsquo;Quarterly Training Request&amp;rsquo; has 2 forms &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo;. Clicking on one of these forms will show the &lt;a href="#form-properties">Form properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="form-properties">Form properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you click on a form, the &lt;strong>Form properties&lt;/strong> appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/formproperties_resized.png" alt="Form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following properties are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Title - the form title, for example Training Request&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Visible - click on this checkbox if you want the form to be visible to users&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Show info - click on this checkbox if you want to show information, for example who are the form owners, the design version and when the form was started and completed. This information will pop up at the bottom of the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/forminfo_resized.png" alt="Form information">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Underneath form properties you will see &lt;strong>Form submit rules&lt;/strong>, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to find out more about Form rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on a control field, for example a text box, in the form to see &lt;a href="#field-properties">Field properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="field-properties">Field properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you click on any field, such as User picker, list or text box, the field properties appear in the right-hand pane.
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/fieldproperties_resized.png" alt="Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong>, in the example above, &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong>, is shown along with the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the field, in the example above, this is Employee Name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within properties are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show Title - show the title of the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Required - tick this checkbox to make this field mandatory for users to fill out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled - tick this checkbox to make the field enabled for users to fill out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visible - tick this checkbox to make the field visible to users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Layout - change the width of the field by clicking on the bar in the Layout box until you see the desired size. Click on the arrow beside Layout to see the Mobile Layout and click on the bar to change the width of the text box for mobile use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxsize-frame.png" alt="Changing text box width">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Underneath field properties you will see &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong>, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to find out more about Field rules.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process common fields</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/common-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/common-fields/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Within every process, there are forms and forms contain &lt;strong>fields&lt;/strong>. The fields you add in, such as a text box, list or button are called &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong>. For example as seen in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/#field-properties">Field properties&lt;/a> you can change properties for a textbox field, like making the field &lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> for form users as shown in the image below for the Training Request form field called &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settingsprocess.png" alt=".">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These design fields are also apparent when creating &lt;strong>dashboards&lt;/strong>, for example &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> widgets. In the example below we can see the &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong> highlighted that are found in the Training Request form. These highlighted fields like &lt;strong>Employee Name&lt;/strong> will appear in the list widget in the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-fields-example.jpg" alt="Example of design fields in a list widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking on &lt;strong>List fields&lt;/strong> in list widget shown above will &lt;strong>show all the fields&lt;/strong> that will appear in the widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/list-field-defaults.jpg" alt="List field example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that non Design fields are also included in the fields to display, namely &lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Process Name&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong> fields. These fields are part of the set of &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> associated with all Kianda processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="common-fields">Common fields&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The non-design fields associated with all Kianda processes are listed below. It is useful to keep these fields in mind when designing forms, as they can be used to retrieve, store or display values from &lt;strong>process instances&lt;/strong> for example &lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> which is the status of a process instance. Using these &amp;lsquo;internal values&amp;rsquo; could be useful where the status of one process could be used as a condition to trigger the start of another process, for example using the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/start-a-process/">&lt;strong>Start a process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The common fields associated with process instances are:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Explanation&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>process instance ID&lt;/strong>, labelled as &amp;lsquo;process-name-number&amp;rsquo;, for example &amp;lsquo;safety-inspection-8&amp;rsquo;. This ID is part of the URL that brings you to the process instance/record held on the system when information is either submitted or saved. For example clicking on the process instance ID &amp;lsquo;safety-inspection-8&amp;rsquo; in a dashboard brings you to the form for example &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://green-itr.kianda.com/forms/safety-inspection-8'">https://green-itr.kianda.com/forms/safety-inspection-8'&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Unique ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is a &lt;strong>system generated ID&lt;/strong> for each process instance, a 32 letter and number generated value.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the status for the process instance, that is either a &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>form name&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Completed&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;. Completed indicates that all forms in a process have been submitted, while &amp;lsquo;form name&amp;rsquo; indicates what the active form is in the process, that is, where the process is &amp;lsquo;at&amp;rsquo;. For example in a process of two forms, a Request form and an Approval form. Once the Request form has been submitted then the status for a process is &amp;lsquo;Approval form&amp;rsquo; indicating that this form needs to be completed.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Version&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>process instance version number&lt;/strong> that starts as 1.0. If a process instance is updated, for example if a process design is updated and published and process instances are updated with the change, then the next version of the instance will be 2.0.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Process Version&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>process design version&lt;/strong>, that is the version of the process design that has been used as a template for the process instance.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Process Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>Unique ID name&lt;/strong> that comes from the process design that is the template for the process instance. The ID is created when the process is created. The ID field autofills from the title of the process as shown in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/#creating-your-first-process">Create your first process&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Process Title&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>Process title&lt;/strong> that comes from the process design title, created when the process is created or updated, for example see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/#creating-your-first-process">Create your first process&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Created&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is a &lt;strong>date and time stamp&lt;/strong> when the process instance is created.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Created by&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>user name&lt;/strong> of the user who &lt;strong>created&lt;/strong> the process instance.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>date and time stamp&lt;/strong> when the process instance is modified, for example after a process design is published and existing process instances are updated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Modified by&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>user name&lt;/strong> of the user who &lt;strong>modified&lt;/strong> the process instance.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Assign to&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is the &lt;strong>user name&lt;/strong> of the user who a process is &lt;strong>assigned&lt;/strong> to. Process designs may have a static option for reassignment in their design so that process instances can be reassigned using &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-quick-action/#how-to-get-started">Quick actions&lt;/a>. Alternatively the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/assign-form/">Assign form&lt;/a> rule can be used to dynamically assign form ownership to another user. That user is named in the &lt;strong>Assign to&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Security users&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>These are the named security users, defined using &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/#process-settings">&lt;strong>Process settings&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> by selecting &lt;strong>Enable process security&lt;/strong> and naming &lt;strong>Process security users&lt;/strong> which can be &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> and/or &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To learn more about design controls that can be applied to forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">&lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To learn more about how common fields are displayed in dashboards in a list widget go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">&lt;strong>List widget&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process navigator</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/navigator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/navigator/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process navigator&lt;/strong> can be found in each &lt;strong>process design&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane. The navigator is used to help you navigate to &lt;strong>fields&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong> that are present within you process. By clicking on a field for example, you will be navigated specifically to where the field is within your process while also &lt;strong>highlighting&lt;/strong> the field with a &lt;strong>border&lt;/strong> for a &lt;strong>short period&lt;/strong> of time. You can also do the same for &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong>, once you click on a rule in the navigator, you will be brought to the form where the rule is located and it will highlight the specific field that the rule is attached to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The very useful &lt;strong>feature&lt;/strong> of the &lt;strong>process navigator&lt;/strong> is its &lt;strong>search bar&lt;/strong>. With big processes that contain many &lt;strong>forms, fields and rules&lt;/strong> can be overwhelming and time consuming to look for a particular filed or rule. You can simply &lt;strong>type&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the filed/rule and options will appear under the Process Navigator&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-turn-on-the-process-navigator">How to turn on the process navigator&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default the &lt;strong>process navigator&lt;/strong> is turned &lt;strong>off&lt;/strong> within each process design. To turn the process navigator on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>First, navigate to the desired process by going to &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; click on desired process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> of the process found on the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/designer-settings.png" alt="Process settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the General tab of the &lt;strong>Process Settings&lt;/strong> dialog box, select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> on the &lt;strong>Enable process navigator&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> on the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click process &lt;strong>save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Process and form properties"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-the-process-navigator">How to use the process navigator&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you have your process navigator turned on, you will be able to see it on the &lt;strong>right-hand pane&lt;/strong> underneath the &lt;strong>rules tab&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-navigator-tab.png" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-navigate-to-a-fieldrule">How to navigate to a field/rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Process navigator tab&lt;/strong> to expand it. This will allow you to see all forms that are present within your process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Expand&lt;/strong> a form in which the desired field is located by clicking on the plus, or simply type in the name of the field into the process navigator search bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/navigator-expand-from.jpg" alt="expand form in process navigator">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the field you wish to &lt;strong>navigate&lt;/strong> to. The navigator will &lt;strong>jump straight&lt;/strong> into the form that the field is in and the field itself will be &lt;strong>highlighted&lt;/strong> for a &lt;strong>brief period&lt;/strong> of time. See the image below for an example when navigating to a &lt;strong>Comments&lt;/strong> field within a process design:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/navigator-field-highlight.jpg" alt="Filed highlight from a process navigator">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-search-for-a-filedrule">How to search for a filed/rule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The very useful &lt;strong>feature&lt;/strong> of the &lt;strong>process navigator&lt;/strong> is its &lt;strong>search bar&lt;/strong>. With big processes that contain many &lt;strong>forms, fields and rules&lt;/strong> can be overwhelming and time consuming to look for a particular filed or rule. You can simply &lt;strong>type&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the filed/rule and options will appear under the Process navigator.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the provided search textbox of the process navigator, type in the &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> of the filed or rule your trying to navigate to.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you start typing, fields and rules will start to &lt;strong>show&lt;/strong> that &lt;strong>contain&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>text&lt;/strong> within the search textbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/navigator-search.jpg" alt="Search function of the process navigator">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the above image you can see that when the word &lt;strong>date&lt;/strong> is entered, all fields and rules that contain the word &lt;strong>date&lt;/strong> will show in the process navigator. You can then click on the desired field/rule for the navigator to navigate you to the location.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To learn more about design controls that can be applied to forms go to &lt;a href="http://localhost:1313/docs/platform/controls/">&lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>