<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda low-code platform for business process automation – Layout controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/</link><description>Recent content in Layout controls on Kianda low-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Platform: Field group control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/field-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/field-group/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> control is a convenient way to mirror a group of fields that are in another form within your process and reference those fields in your new form, making process design sleeker and more efficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in an Education Request Process - where employees can request training in a &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form and their manager can either approve or reject that request in a &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; form - we may want to mirror some of the fields from the first form in the process, &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo;, into the second form &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo;. We will keep this example in mind as we learn more about using the &lt;strong>Field group control&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process - in our case, we will open the Education Request Process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible) - we will select the &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; form. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-example1.jpg" alt="Select form to insert Field group control">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our &lt;strong>Training Approval&lt;/strong> form contains two Panels - the first Panel currently only contains the Richtext field titled &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo;, the second Panel contains fields related to the approval decision. Panels are sections within your form - to learn more, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel/">Panel control&lt;/a>. We will use the &lt;strong>Field group control&lt;/strong> to add fields from the &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form to the first panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu, then select &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> to view the range of Layout controls and click on &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-insert.jpg" alt="Insert field group">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>New field - Field group&lt;/strong> dialog box will open with a range of options you can choose from for your new Field group:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-dialog2.jpg" alt="New field group dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the title of the Field group from the default title of &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field group 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the field and inherits a camel case version of the entered Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user to complete the Field group - if you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help-icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom CSS class name&lt;/strong> - You can type the name of a CSS class to allow the Field group to inherit specific styles defined in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Select fields to group or mirror&lt;/strong> - You can choose one or more fields from the current process to group or mirror by clicking on the field or fields to select them. You can expand forms (listed with a plus sign beside them) to view all of the fields within them by clicking on the form title in the list. Select as many fields as you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we will select three fields in the &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form that we want to be shown on the &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; form - Employee Name, Type of Training and Reason:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-select-fields-mirror.jpg" alt="Select fields to mirror in Field group">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Grouped fields&lt;/strong> - The field(s) you select will automatically be grouped together in the &lt;strong>Grouped fields&lt;/strong> section at the bottom of the dialog box - click on Grouped fields so that it expands to show the list of fields you have chosen:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-grouped-fields.jpg" alt="Field group grouped fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fields you have chosen being &amp;lsquo;grouped&amp;rsquo; together will mean that you will be able to edit them and move them around your form as a group (rather than as individual fields).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there is a field or fields you do not want to be grouped, simply click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash icon&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-blue-bin.jpg" alt="Grouped fields blue bin icon"> to the right and that field will no longer be grouped with the others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also change the order of the fields within the Field group by simply clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>drag handle&lt;/strong> button and dragging and dropping the field where you want it to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-grouped-move.jpg" alt="Move field within Field group">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that selected fields grouped under the current field group are not copied only referenced.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed the &lt;strong>New field - Field group&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> and the new &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> will be added to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>By default, the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the new Field group will not be shown (unless you choose to display it, by selecting the &lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> checkbox in the Field properties menu to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, our new Field group contains the three fields we chose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-move.jpg" alt="Move field group">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-field-groups">How to edit, move and delete Field groups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-select-to-edit.jpg" alt="Select field group to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Edit field - Field group&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from the same range of options as appear in the &lt;strong>New field - Field group&lt;/strong> dialog box (as already discussed in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/field-group#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-edit-dialog2.jpg" alt="Field group edit dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form. Note that the grouped fields are available to move and edit as a group within the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the group by clicking on the group&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm (or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-field-group-properties">How to edit Field group properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-group-field-properties.jpg" alt="Field group Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the &lt;strong>Field Properties&lt;/strong> associated with a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong> field titled &amp;lsquo;Field group 1&amp;rsquo; are shown here and include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - The type of field, in this case a &lt;strong>Field group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - The Title of the field, in this case &amp;lsquo;Field group 1&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the Field group title will be shown in the form. In this case, the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox has &lt;em>not&lt;/em> been selected, so it won&amp;rsquo;t be shown in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the field will be mandatory for form users to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the user will be able to edit or interact with the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - If this is selected, the Field group will be visible in the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - The width of the blue bar can be adjusted to change the width of the Field group as it appears on a PC or mobile phone (to view the Mobile layout, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Field group control&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Layout fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/dialog/">Modal dialog control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel/">Panel layout control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">Richtext control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Platform: Modal dialog control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/dialog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/dialog/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Modal dialog field&lt;/strong> allows you to design pop-up dialog messages that alert or provide reminders or warnings to form end-users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can apply a &lt;strong>rule&lt;/strong> - to a field, form or button - so that the pop-up Dialog displays to the user when you want it to, for example, when the user clicks a certain button. Rules allow actions based upon conditions resulting from user interaction with fields. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to learn about the different categories of rules that can be applied. One such rule that can be used in conjunction with the &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> is the &lt;strong>Show, hide or disable&lt;/strong> rule - to learn more, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/hide-or-disable/">Show, hide or disable&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in a simple Training Request form that employees can complete if they want to request training, it could be useful to insert a Dialog field so that a reminder message pops up when the employee clicks on the Save or Submit buttons, to remind them to check that they have completed all fields before they submit their form. We will keep this example in mind as we learn more about Dialog fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view a &lt;strong>video&lt;/strong> example of how to create a Modal dialog field, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/how-to/create-a-modal-dialog/">&lt;strong>How to create a modal dialog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Modal dialog field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible). Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> to view the range of Layout controls and click on &lt;strong>Dialog&lt;/strong>. A pop-up message will appear saying &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field added&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and a Dialog field will be added to the bottom of your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-insert.jpg" alt="Insert Dialog field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, the Dialog field will &lt;em>not&lt;/em> be displayed in the form to users (as denoted by the eye symbol with the line through it &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/eye-symbol.jpg" alt="Eye symbol with line through it">). This is because, as already mentioned, Dialog fields are typically used in conjunction with a &lt;strong>rule&lt;/strong> being applied to a field or button - such as the &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> buttons - so that the pop-up message is only shown to users in &lt;em>certain circumstances&lt;/em>, rather than being displayed in the form all the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example of the Training Request form, we may only want the Dialog to display when the user clicks on either &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, to remind them to check that they have completed all fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-set-the-heading-for-the-dialog">How to set the heading for the Dialog&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>title of the Dialog field&lt;/strong> will display as the heading at the top of the pop-up Dialog message. By default, the title of the new Dialog field is &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Dialog 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To change the title of a Dialog field:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the new Dialog field (by either clicking on the drag handle &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> or clicking in the area of the Dialog field) so that the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> panel to the right.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>For example, we could decide to give our pop-up Dialog message a heading of &amp;lsquo;Reminder&amp;rsquo;. To learn more about editing the Field properties associated with Modal dialog fields, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/dialog#how-to-edit-modal-dialog-field-properties">How to edit Modal dialog field properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-title.jpg" alt="Changing the Dialog title">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-insert-body-text-for-the-dialog">How to insert body text for the Dialog&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To create the body of the pop-up Dialog, you can insert any of the field types from the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> menu, such as a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">text box&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">list&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">table&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">richtext&lt;/a>. First, select the &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> (so that the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible) and then go to the Controls menu and click on the field type you want to insert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> is a very flexible option to use for the body of the pop-up message as it gives you the most options - such as formatting and styling the text or inserting images or links. We will use a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> to step through how to add text to the body of the Dialog field for our Training Request form.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> and then insert a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> into it by clicking &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt;&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> &amp;gt;&lt;strong>Richtext&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane. To learn more about Richtext fields, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">Richtext control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-insert-richtext.jpg" alt="Insert richtext into Dialog field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>New field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box will open:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-dialog2.jpg" alt="Richtext dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the title of the Richtext field from the default &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Richtext 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;. &lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: It is the &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> title that will show as the heading of the pop-up Dialog, not the Richtext title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the field and inherits a camel case version of the entered Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Helptext&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user to complete the field - if you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help-icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted. This option is not as relevant to the Dialog field as it is to other fields, as the Dialog field is not a field the user needs to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom CSS class name&lt;/strong> - You can type the name of a CSS class to allow the Richtext to inherit specific styles defined in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Richtext&lt;/strong> - Type the text that you want to be shown as the main body text in the pop-up Dialog into this field and format it as you want - there are options to highlight text, change the font style and font colour, bold, underline, increase or decrease font size, use a bulleted or numbered list, format the text to align left/centre/right, insert a table or a link, insert an image or to switch to code view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from five colour options for the colour that will appear in the background behind the Dialog richtext body text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For our example of the Training Request form, we will insert text to remind the employee completing the form to check that they have completed all fields before submitting it and will choose an orange background colour:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-richtext-example.jpg" alt="Example richtext for Dialog field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed the &lt;strong>New field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>. You will now see the body text of your Dialog field in the Richtext field you added to it:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-example.jpg" alt="Dialog example">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>To preview how the pop-up Dialog will look tp users, either click on the Dialog &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-preview-button.jpg" alt="Dialog field preview button"> or click on the eye symbol &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/eye-symbol.jpg" alt="Eye symbol">:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-example-preview.jpg" alt="Preview example of Dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="11">
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to close the preview.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-modal-dialog-fields">How to edit, move and delete Modal dialog fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As we go through the options available for editing, moving or deleting a Modal dialog field in a form, we will keep in mind our example of the &amp;lsquo;Reminder&amp;rsquo; pop-up Dialog in the Training Request form.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-edit-a-modal-dialog-field">How to edit a Modal dialog field&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Modal dialog field&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the Dialog field (by either clicking on the drag handle &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> or clicking in the area of the Dialog field).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-select-to-edit.jpg" alt="Select Dialog to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field - Dialog&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from a range of options (we already changed the Dialog field title to &amp;lsquo;Reminder&amp;rsquo; so this name will be shown in the dialog box name):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-dialog-box2.jpg" alt="Edit Modal Dialog field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within the &lt;strong>Edit field - Dialog&lt;/strong> dialog box include:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the title of the Modal Dialog field here. We already changed it to &amp;lsquo;Reminder&amp;rsquo; from the default &lt;strong>Dialog 1&lt;/strong> in the &amp;lsquo;Title&amp;rsquo; field in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user. If you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help-icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted. This option is less relevant for the Dialog field as it is for other field types, as the Dialog field is not a field the user needs to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom CSS class name&lt;/strong> - You can type the name of a CSS class to allow the Dialog to inherit specific styles defined in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; button&lt;/strong> - Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you do not want the user to see an &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; button at the bottom of the Dialog message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide &amp;ldquo;Close&amp;rdquo; button&lt;/strong> - Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you do not want the user to see a &amp;lsquo;Close&amp;rsquo; button at the bottom of the Dialog message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable dismiss (X button right top)&lt;/strong> - Choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> means an X button (that the user can click on to dismiss the pop-up message) will be shown at the top right of the Dialog.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dialog size&lt;/strong> - You can choose from the &lt;strong>Default&lt;/strong> size or &lt;strong>Large&lt;/strong> size for your Dialog message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have finished editing the &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Edit field - Dialog&lt;/strong> dialog box, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To see how your form or Dialog field will look on a mobile, view it in &lt;strong>Mobile preview&lt;/strong> by using the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> option which can be opened by clicking the play button icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview">. You also have the options to see how it will look on a PC or tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-move-a-modal-dialog-field">How to move a Modal dialog field&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To move a Modal dialog field:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Drag and drop it wherever you want to move it within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-example-move.jpg" alt="Move a Dialog field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-delete-a-modal-dialog-field">How to delete a Modal dialog field&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To delete a Modal dialog field from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select it (by either clicking on the Panel field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm the deletion (or click &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-modal-dialog-field-properties">How to edit Modal dialog field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Modal dialog field&lt;/strong>, select the Dialog field (by clicking on the drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">or clicking in the area of the Dialog field) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dialog-field-properties.jpg" alt="Panel field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>Dialog field&lt;/strong> titled &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Reminder&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; has been selected and the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with it are shown in the Field properties menu to the right:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - The title of the Modal Dialog field. In this case, &amp;lsquo;Reminder&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - How wide the Modal Dialog field will be on a PC and mobile phone, denoted by the width of the blue bar. You can change the width by clicking on the blue bar.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Modal dialog control&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Layout fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/field-group/">Field group control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel/">Panel layout control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">Richtext control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Platform: Panel layout control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/panel/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Panel field&lt;/strong> is section within a form. Panels hold other elements of your form, such as &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">text box fields&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">list fields&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">tables&lt;/a>, and enable flexible layout options that result in a better end-user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a good idea when first creating a form to insert a panel for each section of your form and then insert the fields you require into each of these panels. One advantage of having related fields contained within a panel is that you can then easily move that panel (and all of the fields within it) to another location within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in a &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form, you may decide to insert two panels - one panel to contain the details relating to the employee requesting the training and a second panel to contain the details of the training course being requested.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible). Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> to view the range of Layout controls and click on &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A pop-up message will appear saying &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Field added&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and a panel field with the default name &lt;strong>Panel 1&lt;/strong> will be added to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-insert-blank-form.jpg" alt="Insert panel field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, the title of the new panel will not be displayed in your form, but you can make it visible by selecting the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; checkbox in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> panel to the right) - to learn more about editing the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with Panels, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel#how-to-edit-panel-field-properties">How to edit Panel field properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-panels">How to edit, move and delete Panels&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As we go through the options available for editing a Panel in a form, we will keep in mind the example of adding two panels to a &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form - one titled &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; and one titled &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-edit-a-panel">How to edit a Panel&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-edit.jpg" alt="Select Panel to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field - Panel&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from a range of options:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-edit-dialog.jpg" alt="Edit Panel dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the title of the Panel from the default &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Panel 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, after inserting two panels into our form, we could edit each of them in turn and change their titles to &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to have the title of a Panel display in your form, you need to take one further step - select each panel and then select the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; checkbox in the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> panel to the right. Now the titles of the two Panels will be shown - here we have selected the first panel in order to display the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox associated with it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-show-title.jpg" alt="Show Panel title">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will learn more about the Field properties associated with Panels in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel#how-to-edit-panel-field-properties">How to edit Panel Field properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name (unique)&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the Panel field and inherits a camel case version of the entered Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user to complete the Panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our example, we could insert this help text to assist the user in completing the &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; panel:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-help-text.jpg" alt="Panel help text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help-icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the Panel title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-help-text-shown.jpg" alt="Panel help text displayed">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom CSS class name&lt;/strong> - You can type the name of a CSS class to allow the panel to inherit specific styles defined in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Card design?&lt;/strong> - This option allows you to add a border radius to your panel, which rounds the edges. If you select the &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> radio button, you can choose between defining:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The total border radius in pixels by clicking the all corners button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/card-design-all-symbol.jpg" alt="Card design all symbol"> and entering a value into the input field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Each corner&amp;rsquo;s border radius individually in pixels by clicking on the individual corners button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/card-design-individual-symbol.jpg" alt="individual corners button"> and entering values for each corner in the four input fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/card-design-individual-pixels.jpg" alt="individual corners border radius">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature can give your forms an added level of unique styling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/card-detail.jpg" alt="card detail">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - Here you can decide how wide you want your Panel to be in your form - choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click at the far right side of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/layoutcolumns.png" alt="Panel width">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from six different colour options: navy, green, blue, amber, red, white. By default, the colour is set to white.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable panel security&lt;/strong> - If you want to restrict who can see the contents of the Panel, choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>. Two additional options will then be shown - &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Add security&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Allow anonymous link&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-enable-security.jpg" alt="Enable Panel security">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To limit who can view the Panel contents, click the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Add security&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; button. A new row is displayed, within which you can select the user(s) or groups who will be able to vie the Panel:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-add-security.jpg" alt="Panel add security">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;strong>Field security&lt;/strong>, you can choose from &lt;strong>three options in terms of who will be able to view the Panel you are inserting&lt;/strong>: User or group, User picker field or Form owner(s).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(i) If you choose to limit the Panel visibility to a &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>User or group&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, you can then select the user(s) or groups you want to be able to see it in the &amp;lsquo;Select user(s) or groups&amp;rsquo; box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(ii) If you choose to limit the Panel visibility to a &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>User picker field&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, you then select the User picker field in the &amp;lsquo;Select a userpicker field&amp;rsquo; box:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-security-user-picker.jpg" alt="Panel security visibility limited to User picker field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will limit the visibility of the Panel to the user(s) selected in that User picker field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(iii) If you choose to limit the Panel visibility to &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Form owner(s)&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, you then select the form in the &amp;lsquo;Select a form&amp;rsquo; box - only the owner(s) of the selected form will be able to view the Panel you are inserting:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-security-form-owner.jpg" alt="Panel security visibility limited to Form owner">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second main option in terms of Panel security is &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Allow anonymous link&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-security-link.jpg" alt="Panel allow anonymous link">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, this will mean that the Panel will be visible when the form is accessed via an anonymous link.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>, anyone accessing the form from an anonymous link will not be able to see the Panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Anonymous links can be useful if, for example, you want members of the public to complete your form without needing to log into Kianda. To learn more about how you can create anonymous links to a form that can be shared with external users, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/anonymous-form-link/">Anonymous form link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you are finished editing the &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-add-fields-to-a-panel">How to add fields to a Panel&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Once you have inserted a Panel and completed the &lt;strong>Edit field - Panel&lt;/strong> dialog box, you can then start to add the elements you need into the Panel - such as text boxes, lists, tables, number fields or date fields. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> to see the full list of fields available and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to learn about different categories of rules that can be applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add fields to your Panel:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the Panel (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) so that the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on whatever type of field you want to insert from the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> menu in the left-hand pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s take the example of our first Panel, titled &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Employee Details&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;. To add a Text box field to this Panel we can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the Panel by clicking on the &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; field Drag handle.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> menu to insert a Text box. A pop-up message says &amp;lsquo;Field added&amp;rsquo; and a new Text box, titled &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Text box 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, is added to the &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; panel:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-insert-fields.jpg" alt="Insert text box field into a Panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>You can then edit this new Text box field as needed - in our example, we will rename it as &amp;lsquo;First Name&amp;rsquo;. To learn more about Text box fields, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Text box control&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>By adding two text box fields (titled &amp;lsquo;First Name&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Surname&amp;rsquo;) and a date field (titled &amp;lsquo;Date of Birth&amp;rsquo;) to our &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; Panel, and then adding the fields we need to the &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo; Panel, our &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; form - with its two Panels - could look like this when viewed on a user&amp;rsquo;s mobile phone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-example-mobile.jpg" alt="Panel example on mobile phone">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To see how your form or field will look on a mobile, view it in &lt;strong>Mobile preview&lt;/strong> by using the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> option which can be opened by clicking the play button icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview">. You also have the options to see how it will look on a PC or tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-move-a-panel">How to move a Panel&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To move a Panel, simply:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the Panel field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop it wherever you want to move it within your form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-move.jpg" alt="Move a Panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-delete-a-panel">How to delete a Panel&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To delete a Panel from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select it (by either clicking on the Panel field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">), click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Remember that deleting a Panel will result in all of the fields contained within that Panel also being deleted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-panel-field-properties">How to edit Panel Field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Panel&lt;/strong>, select the Panel field (by clicking on the field title or drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/panel-field-properties2.jpg" alt="Panel field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with the &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo; Panel include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - the type of field. In this case, Panel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the title of the Panel field (default name &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Panel 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; unless you change it). In this case, &amp;lsquo;Employee Details&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - this is selected, which means that the Panel title will be shown in the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - this is selected, so the Panel will be visible to form users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - the width of the blue bars can be adjusted to change the width of the Richtext field on PC or mobile. To view the mobile width, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right of the Layout option.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Panel control&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Layout fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/field-group/">Field group control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/dialog/">Modal dialog control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext/">Richtext control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Platform: Richtext control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/richtext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/controls/layout/richtext/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Richtext fields&lt;/strong> can be used to create custom rich text content in forms, such as an attractive banner. They provide optimum formatting options, such as bold and italics, or the option to insert images or links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, we may want to insert some colourful headings into a Training Approval form within an Education Request process (where employees can request training in a Training Request form and their manager then either approves or rejects this request in a Training Approval form).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process - in our case, we will open the Education Request process. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/">Create First Process&lt;/a> to learn how to create your first process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the form within that process to which you want to add the &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible). We will select the &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; form:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-example-select-form.jpg" alt="Select form to insert Richtext field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Training Approval form contains two panels (as indicated above), neither of which currently has a heading. For the first panel, we will insert a Richtext heading titled &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo; and, for the second panel, we will insert a Richtext heading titled &amp;lsquo;Approval Decision&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To insert a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> into the first panel in the form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select that panel by clicking on the drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu and select &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> to view the range of Layout controls.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Richtext&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-insert.jpg" alt="Insert Richtext field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>New field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box will open with a range of options you can choose from for your new Richtext field:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-dialog2.jpg" alt="Richtext dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the title of the Richtext field from the default title of &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Richtext 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the field and inherits a camel case version of the entered Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user - if you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help-icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Custom CSS class name&lt;/strong> - You can type the name of a CSS class to allow the Richtext to inherit specific styles defined in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Richtext&lt;/strong> - Here you can insert the text you want to appear and can choose from an wide array of styles and formats, including &lt;strong>Style,&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Colour&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Bold&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Underline&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Remove font style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font size&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font family&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Unordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Ordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Paragraph&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong>. You can also choose to insert a &lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong>, if you click on the &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/picture-button.jpg" alt="Picture button">you will be redirected to the &lt;strong>File storage&lt;/strong> area where you can search for existing images stored in the Kianda file system. Here you can create a folder, upload a file and delete files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/storage-files-upload.jpg" alt="Storage files management area">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also switch to &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong>. For example, if you click on &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/code.png" alt="Code view button">you can copy HTML code directly into the text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Type in the text you want to use into the body of the Richtext box - in our example, we will insert the text &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo; (the title we want to use for the first panel in our form), bold it, choose font size 14 and a blue colour scheme:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-example-body-text.jpg" alt="Example of Richtext body text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can click on the &lt;strong>Help&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/help.png" alt="Help button"> to get a list of over 20 keyboard shortcuts that you can use to style your text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-help-shortcuts.jpg" alt="Richtext help">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis-16401854043731.png" alt="Ellipsis button"> if you want to add an expression - see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/expression-builder/">Expression builder&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - You can choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your rich text background.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed the &lt;strong>New field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> and the new &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> will be added to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, it is inserted at the bottom of the panel we added it to. The same steps can be repeated in order to insert a Richtext heading in the second panel, titled &amp;lsquo;Approval Decision&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-inserted.jpg" alt="Richtext field inserted">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, the Richtext &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> will not be shown (unless you choose to display it, by selecting the &lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> checkbox in the Field properties menu to the right).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-richtext-fields">How to edit, move and delete Richtext fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-select-to-edit.jpg" alt="Select Richtext field to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from the same range of options as appear in the &lt;strong>New field - Richtext&lt;/strong> dialog box (as already discussed in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/richtext#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-edit-dialog2.jpg" alt="Richtext field edit dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In our example, we can move the new Richtext heading to the top of the first panel in the Training Approval form:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-move.jpg" alt="Move a Richtext field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong> from your form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the field (by clicking on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-preview-your-richtext-field">How to preview your Richtext field&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To see how your Richtext field or fields will look to a user on a PC or mobile phone:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Save your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Desktop preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/desktop.png" alt="Desktop preview button"> to see how the form will look when viewed on a PC or click on the &lt;strong>Mobile preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/mobile.png" alt="Mobile preview button"> to see how it will look on a mobile phone.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From our example, the new Richtext headings - &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Approval Decision&amp;rsquo; - could look like this when a user views the form on their mobile phone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-preview-mobile.jpg" alt="Richtext previewed on a mobile phone">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-richtext-field-properties">How to edit Richtext field properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Richtext field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the title or drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite-frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/richtext-field-properties.jpg" alt="Richtext field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> associated with the &amp;lsquo;Training Details&amp;rsquo; Richtext field include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong> - Richtext&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the title of the Richtext field (default name &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Richtext 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; unless you change this)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show title&lt;/strong> - this is not selected, which means that the Richtext title will not be shown in the form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - this is not selected, so the Richtext field is not a mandatory field for the user to complete&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - the field is enabled so the user can edit it (not relevant for a richtext heading which the user will not interact with)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - this is selected, so the Richtext field will be visible to users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - the width of the blue bar can be adjusted to change the width of the Richtext field on PC or mobile. To view the mobile width, click on the expand button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expand-icon.jpg" alt="Expand button"> to the right of the Layout option.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Richtext control&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Layout fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/field-group/">Field group control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/dialog/">Modal dialog control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/layout/panel/">Panel layout control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>