<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda low-code platform for business process automation – Administration</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on Kianda low-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Platform: Subscription</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/subscription/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/subscription/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane or on the top right toolbar depending on the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/#general-settings">chosen orientation&lt;/a>, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. This function allows you to update the look and feel of your workspace, set regional, mobile and single sign-on settings and design the login page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For &lt;strong>developers&lt;/strong> who wish to &lt;strong>customise and style&lt;/strong> their Kianda workspace and processes, there are options to support you in achieving a high level of design that is instantly recognisable for users. These options include creating a &lt;strong>custom branding style&lt;/strong>, customised &lt;strong>login page&lt;/strong> and option to control how your platform will look on &lt;strong>mobile devices&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To view, use the Subscription function as an administrator:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The main Subscription page opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/subscription-main.jpg" alt="Subscription view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this view you can typically make changes to six areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> allows you to change the look and feel for your workspace, for example adding company logos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong> allows you to design the login page for your workspace, for example to change background and font colours and add taglines.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to set your operational &lt;strong>time zone&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>regional settings&lt;/strong>, such as English Ireland for language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to customise how the Kianda workspace will appear as a mobile app.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscription Details&lt;/strong> allows you to view your company details and enable a Global SMTP Mail connector for sending automated emails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Storage Files&lt;/strong> allows you upload, delete and view public and private files within your subscription. You can also create folders to organise your files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These areas are covered in more detail in the sections below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a particular area to edit details or click on the &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/open-wizard-btn.jpg" alt="Open wizard button"> button to use a wizard to edit &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Details on each area are available below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="look-and-feel">Look and Feel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can access this section by clicking on &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> or by clicking on &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> in the main &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively you can access this section by clicking on the &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> shortcut found in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/">&lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/look-and-feel.jpg" alt="Look and feel">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Logo sizes are 200 x 65px for a full-sized logo and 45 x 45px for a collapsed logo. You can also select a colour scheme under Themes and preview the results under Workspace preview on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Details for each of the areas within the page - &lt;a href="#logos">Logos&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#layout">Layout&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#themes">Themes&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#css">CSS&lt;/a> are available below. Make sure to click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="logos">Logos&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a logo for your company:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> beside &lt;strong>Logo Url&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. The recommended size is 200px x 65px.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To add a logo that will appear when the left-hand side menu is collapsed, click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> beside &lt;strong>Collapsed Logo URL&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. The recommended size is 45px x 45px.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="layout">Layout&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The options for your workspace layout are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Boxed&lt;/strong> - moving the slider across to enable a boxed layout, that is the workspace appears in a box in the browser, with space appearing around the box and content is centred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/boxed-layout.jpg" alt="Boxed layout">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>RTL&lt;/strong> - moved the slider across to enable a right-to-left (RTL) layout, that is text, layout, icons and so on are right-hand based.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disable Zoom on Mobile&lt;/strong> - move the slider across to enable the &amp;lsquo;disable zoom on mobile&amp;rsquo; option, which means that the zooming option is disabled on mobile web pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome page&lt;/strong> - click on the &lt;strong>Change&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-button.jpg" alt="Change button"> to change the Welcome page for users of your Kianda workspace. The &lt;strong>Update welcome page&lt;/strong> dialog box opens where you can click on the drop-down list under &lt;strong>New welcome page&lt;/strong> to choose a new welcome page, from the Home page and dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/update-welcome-page.jpg" alt="Update welcome page dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save changes or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Click on a &lt;strong>Theme&lt;/strong> of choice. Options range from two-tone layouts, to those with a dark left-hand side menu as shown in the middle of the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/themes.jpg" alt="Themes">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="css">CSS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section you can modify the &lt;strong>Global CSS File&lt;/strong> to make changes to the look and feel of the site as well as processes. If you have an existing CSS file, you can access the existing CSS details by clicking on the on the &lt;strong>ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expression.jpg" alt="Ellipsis button"> to open a CSS Editor and add to those details, or click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a CSS file to add in customised styling. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure to click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="design-login-page">Design Login Page&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section allows you to design the login page, choose background and font colours and complete fields for Taglines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-login-page.jpg" alt="Design login page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Login Page Logo Url&lt;/strong> - add/change a logo for the login page to Kianda by clicking on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo on your PC or network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Background Color&lt;/strong> - to create a background colour for the login page, you can either click on the colour itself and select a colour in the main view, or using the slider, or type in an RGB, HSL or HEX value in the fields above, or click in the box beside it to add in a HEX value for a colour, for example #BFBFBF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/background-color.jpg" alt="Background Color">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Font Color&lt;/strong> - as with the Background Color, to create a font colour, choose an appropriate colour using the colour box itself or type in a value in the field beside the colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tagline 1&lt;/strong> - type in the first tagline that will appear under your company logo on the login page. A maximum of 25 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tagline 2&lt;/strong> - type in the second tagline that will appear under your company logo on the login page. A maximum of 20 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/taglines.jpg" alt="Taglines">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="regional-settings">Regional Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here you can set your operational time zone and regional settings, such as English Ireland, from the dropdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/regional-settings.jpg" alt="Regional settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regional settings&lt;/strong> - choose a language setting from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Time zone&lt;/strong> - choose a time zone from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chosen options are reflected in the text below the fields, for example &lt;strong>date and time format&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mobile-settings">Mobile Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here you can customise how the Kianda workspace will appear to users on mobile devices. You can choose your App name, App short name, Splash Screen Colour, and Theme Colour and upload a mobile size icon (note the icon size is 512 x 512 px).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/mobile-settings.jpg" alt="Mobile settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>App name&lt;/strong> - add/change a name to set a custom app name for your app/workspace that reflects your business. A maximum of 45 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>App short name&lt;/strong> - add/change a shortened name for your app/workspace, for user in areas without space for longer text strings. A maximum of 12 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Splash Screen Color&lt;/strong> - to set the introductory screen colour that appears while your application loads (splash screen), you can either click on the colour itself and select a colour in the main view, or using the slider, or type in an RGB, HSL or HEX value in the fields above, or click in the box beside it to add in a HEX value for a colour, for example #037dd3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/splash-screen-color.jpg" alt="Splash screen color">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Theme Color&lt;/strong> - as with the Splash Screen Color, choose an appropriate colour for the mobile app theme font using the colour box itself or type in a value in the field beside the colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mobile Icon&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. This will be displayed on the home screen of your users&amp;rsquo; mobile devices. The recommended size is 512px x 512px.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes, click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="subscription-details">Subscription Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>General settings include details like your company name, subscription ID, renewal date and business identity (your workspace URL, for example, green-itr.kianda.com). You can also enable a Global SMTP Mail Connector to enable email flow to/from your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within general settings, administrators can set who the Global Administrator is, or the main administrator for the workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/subscription-details2.png" alt="Subscription details">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="company-details">Company details&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Company Name&lt;/strong> - add in your company name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business identity&lt;/strong> - the business identity for your company workspace is automatically added in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Country&lt;/strong> - choose a country from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>City&lt;/strong> - enter a city into the text field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Address&lt;/strong> - add in your company address.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Renewal date&lt;/strong> - your subscription renewal date is automatically added in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscription Id&lt;/strong> - your company subscription identity is automatically generated. This is needed when you need to perform authorisation to use Instance API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plan Id&lt;/strong> - your plan Id is automatically added in. For example free, premium and enterprise.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="general-settings">General settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable Global SMTP Mail Connector&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to set a global Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP) connector used to send emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The global connector will ignore all other connectors and will no longer use &lt;a href="mailto:no-reply@kianda.com">no-reply@kianda.com&lt;/a> as a sender. To enable this you must have an email connector set up in advance. To learn more about email connectors go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/">Email connector&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition you can choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>Enable save to Sent Items&lt;/strong> so that sent email are automatically saved in a &amp;lsquo;Sent items folder&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/general-settings.png" alt="Enabling Global SMTP Mail Connector">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show administration menu on top menu?&lt;/strong> - selecting &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo; positions the administration menu on the top right toolbar beside the My profile section, and is then removed from the left hand navigational pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-admin-menu.png" alt="new admin menu" style="zoom:80%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Load widgets offline first?&lt;/strong> - selecting &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo; will prompt the platform to load widgets in offline mode first. This is an optional flag that enables dashboard and process widgets to be loaded faster from the offline cache. It can be useful if you consistently interact with your environment when you are in areas of poor network connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Global Administrator&lt;/strong> - change the global administrator of your company&amp;rsquo;s Kianda platform from the list of users that are in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Global JavaScript&lt;/strong> - allows you to create a JavaScript file with custom functions as helper or action functions allowing you to perform any functionality you may want. The file is accessible globally and will load when the application first starts. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-javascript-file/">Global JavaScript file&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="storage-files">Storage files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can access this section by clicking on &lt;strong>Storage Files&lt;/strong> in the main &lt;strong>Administration &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/strong> page. Here you can see all public and private files that are in your platforms storage. You can search for files using the search box and navigate between &lt;strong>Public&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Private&lt;/strong> files using the provided tabs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/storage-files.jpg" alt="Single Sign-On Details">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="upload-files">Upload file(s)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To upload a file to Storage files, click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/upload-file.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/storage-file-upload.jpg" alt="upload file">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A file explorer will open in which you can select multiple files to upload to you platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="create-folder">Create folder&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To create a folder, click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-storage-create-folder.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-folder.jpg" alt="create folder">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The folder will appear alphabetically in the main view where you can see all your files. To upload a file into folder, first, you need to click on the folder name to open it and then click on &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/upload-file.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any time, you can go to left-hand side menu and click on &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> to edit any of the settings for the headings above.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platform: Recycle bin</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/recyclebin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/administration/recyclebin/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane, or on the top right toolbar depending on the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/#general-settings">chosen orientation&lt;/a>, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The recycle bin holds deleted process instances, dashboard pages and process designs. Deleted items are held for 30 days and are permanently deleted after this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view items in the Recycle bin:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for an item by typing in key words into the &lt;strong>Search items&lt;/strong> box for example &amp;lsquo;Office&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view existing deleted items in the &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong> main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/recycle-bin-view2.jpg" alt="Recycle bin main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deleted items are listed by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Item type&lt;/strong> - this is the type of deleted item, for example a widget, process instance, datasource or page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Item details&lt;/strong> - the name of the deleted item, for example the name of a process instance and the unique name (ID) for that process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deleted date&lt;/strong> - the date the item was deleted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deleted by&lt;/strong> - the name of the user who deleted the item.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the example above there is one process design, four dashboard pages and three process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To restore an item click on the &lt;strong>Restore item&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore-bin-item.jpg" alt="Restore recycle bin button"> beside the item name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you click on the button you will get a pop-up confirmation asking you to confirm that you want to restore that item.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore-item.jpg" alt="Restore item">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> if you wish to restore the item or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to exit. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the item is restored, for example a datasource appears again within the Datasource management main view when you click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane. To learn more about this, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources">Data sources&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-restored.jpg" alt="Datasource restored">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and form go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read about other parts of the platform go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/">Administration&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>