<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Troubleshooting</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Version history and auditing</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a number of built-in features in Kianda that your organisation can take advantage of to monitor processes in detail and troubleshoot as needed. Your Kianda workspace cleverly allows you to manage &lt;strong>process design&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>process instance versioning&lt;/strong> so that &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> can see what has happened at specific moments during process execution and roll-back to earlier versions if needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The features you can use for troubleshooting are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#design-version-history">Design version history&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#process-instance-version-history">Process instance version history&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="design-version-history">Design version history&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> allows &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> or those with the &lt;strong>design business process&lt;/strong> role, to update process designs. The platform keeps a record of all versions previously created. The &lt;strong>current or active version&lt;/strong> of a process is always visible in the right-hand pane, for example V1.0 for the &amp;lsquo;Inspection Process&amp;rsquo; as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/published-version.jpg" alt="Process version history">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>first version&lt;/strong> of a process is always &lt;strong>0.1&lt;/strong> and each time the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">is clicked, the version will increment to 0.2 and so on. Once the process is &lt;strong>published&lt;/strong> the version changes to &lt;strong>1.0&lt;/strong> and increments to 2.0 and so on with each publication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking on the &lt;strong>Design version history&lt;/strong> button itself opens the &lt;strong>Version history details&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version-history-details-eg.jpg" alt="Version history details example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here you can see when a process design was modified and by whom. Clicking on the version number itself releases details of changes made, for example forms, fields and rules that were added, modified or removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version-history-details-example.jpg" alt="Version history details example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any time an older version of the design can be reinstated by clicking on the &lt;strong>Restore&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore.png" alt="Restore button"> beside a particular version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This level of detail provides a precise way to monitor what is happening with a process design and to control which version should be the current version in an easy-to-use interface. The &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/version-history/">Version history&lt;/a> page provides a step-by-step guide on how to view version history.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="process-instance-version-history">Process instance version history&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process instances&lt;/strong> can be accessed from a list widget in a dashboard page linked to the process design. Access to the dashboard and list widget can be set using security settings, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security/#dashboard-security">Dashboard security&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-instance-example.jpg" alt="Process instance example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example by clicking on a process ID like &amp;lsquo;inspection-process-10&amp;rsquo; as seen in the list widget above, we can then see the actual record/process instance held in the system. In the Inspection process example below, a &amp;lsquo;Request form&amp;rsquo; has had information submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/../content/docs/process-instance-view.jpg" alt="Process instance view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> have access to the process instance history feature highlighted above, to manage process instance versions. By clicking on the &lt;strong>process history&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Rule debugger</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Rule debugger&lt;/strong> is a troubleshooting feature that allows you to visualise each rule being executed in your process design within the preview window. It provides an insight into the logical flow of a process logical and serves as an important troubleshooting feature if your process does not work as expected. As well as this, it states what rule is being executed and on what field it is acting upon, alongside any associated conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-example.jpg" alt="Rule debugger in action example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Rule Debugger&lt;/strong> can be turned on at any point, for example when starting a new process or using the Previewer. We look at the Previewer in the steps below, however you can also access this feature via [XYYYYYYYYYYYYZ].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before getting started, you must open a process design of your choice that features rules that require debugging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access the rule debugger feature:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to the left-hand pane of the designer screen and click on the &lt;strong>Run and preview process&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="run and preview process button" style="zoom:150%;" />.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview-process-left-hand-pane.png" alt="Left hand pane clicking the preview button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the preview window, click on the &lt;strong>Enable / Disable Rule debugging&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-btn.png" alt="rule debugger button"> in the top right corner of the window.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-preview2.png" alt="rule debugger in the preview window" style="zoom:80%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Begin entering data into your process as expected until the rule debugger modal dialog appears in the bottom right of the preview window. This appears as soon as the first rule is encountered in the design&amp;rsquo;s logical workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-modal.png" alt="Rule debugger dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rule debugger dialog displays information such as the &lt;strong>Rule&lt;/strong> currently being executed, any &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> associated with the rule and the &lt;strong>Field&lt;/strong> the rule is being enacted upon. Three buttons are also displayed, allowing you to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Execute rule&lt;/strong> - executes the &lt;strong>currently displayed rule&lt;/strong> on the currently displayed field, along with any conditions specified where you have two or more rules attached to a field, form or process. Once all the rules are executed for that field, then the dialog box will disappear and the system awaits further data input into the form&amp;rsquo;s fields until the next rule or block of rules attached to a field are met.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resume&lt;/strong> - resumes the execution of all rules in a block where there are two or more rules attached to a field, form or process. The rule debug dialog will only then reappear when new data is entered into another field in the process flow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Stop debug&lt;/strong> - exits the debugging mode and the rule debug dialog box disappears. You will receive no more messages about current rule execution, but will still be in the process preview window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can alter the conditions on the currently displayed rule (if any), by clicking on the &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> filter button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions-filter-btn.png" alt="Conditions filter button image">. This will display another modal dialog box, which gives you the option to change the condition being applied to the rule, add further conditions, remove some conditions and more - allowing for the troubleshooting of different use cases within your process. To learn more about this, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-conditions.png" alt="Conditions dialog for rule debugger">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To exit the debugging process, you can click on the &lt;strong>Stop debug&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/stop-debug-btn.png" alt="stop debug button">, or alternatively click on the &lt;strong>Enable / Disable Rule debugging&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-btn.png" alt="rule debugger button" style="zoom:80%;" />, or click on the &lt;strong>Exit preview mode&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exit-preview-window-btn.png" alt="exit window preview button" style="zoom:80%;" />.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Rule debugger&lt;/strong>, find out more about other troubleshooting features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/">Custom widget debugging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/">Rule diagnostics&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing">Version history and Auditing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Rule diagnostics</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> is a troubleshooting feature within Kianda that allows you to view a nested list of all forms, fields and rules - the purpose being that you can choose to &lt;strong>manually trigger&lt;/strong> these rules for diagnostic purposes, as well as &lt;strong>toggle field visibility&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>re-assign forms&lt;/strong>, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rule diagnostics feature is available for troubleshooting specific &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Process instances&lt;/a> where as the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger">Rule debugger&lt;/a> feature focuses more so on troubleshooting a process design pre-publishing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before getting started, you must open a process instance that you would like to perform rule diagnostics on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access the rule diagnostics feature:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your chosen process instance, click on the &lt;strong>Process history&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-button.jpg" alt="process history button" style="zoom:150%;" /> in the top right-hand corner of the screen. This will open the Process history modal dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-btn2.png" alt="Process history">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the process history dialog, navigate to the &lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> tab. From here, you can view a nested list of all forms, fields and rules. In the example below, you can view rules and fields across three different forms in the process, as well as expand the onload rules. You can search for a specific element in your process by utilising the search bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-modal1.png" alt="rule diagnostics tab">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are many possibilities for testing your process instance, however in this example we will try to troubleshoot the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/send-email/">Send email rule&lt;/a> to ensure that the line manager receives the correctly formatted email during this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this, we will drill down into the following path: &lt;em>Asset request&lt;/em> form &amp;gt; &lt;em>Submit&lt;/em> button &amp;gt; &lt;em>Rules&lt;/em> &amp;gt; &lt;em>Email Line Manager&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expanding-process-instance.png" alt="Drill down into line manager">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Beside the &lt;em>Email Line Manager&lt;/em> rule, click on the orange &lt;strong>Trigger&lt;/strong> bolt button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trigger-btn.png" alt="trigger bolt button" style="zoom:150%;" /> to &lt;strong>manually trigger&lt;/strong> the rule. This is a powerful feature as you do not need to fill out an entire process from start to finish to troubleshoot this. You will then see a &lt;em>Rule executed&lt;/em> alert at the top of the page, and the specific rule should perform as expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/request-assets-email.png" alt="Request assets email sent to the line manager" style="zoom:67%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are other features you can troubleshoot in the &lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> tab such as clicking:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle form visibility&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/toggle-visibility-btn.png" alt="toggle visibility button"> - to hide or show the selected form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make editable&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editable-btn.png" alt="Editable button"> - make the current field/form editable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Re-assign form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/re-assign-btn.png" alt="re-assign button"> - to assign the form to a different person&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Go to form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/go-to-form-btn.png" alt="go to form button"> - snaps to the selected form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle field enable&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/toggle-field-enable-btn.png" alt="toggle field enable"> - to enable/disable the selected field&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As well as this, the &lt;strong>Rule executed status&lt;/strong> can be seen beside each rule - a green tick &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/green-tick.png" alt="green tick"> for executed, and a grey tick &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/grey-tick.png" alt="grey tick"> for not executed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-diagnostics-other-btns.png" alt="Rule diagnostics other buttons">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the current form in your process instance, you can click on the &lt;strong>Change current active form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-current-active-form-btn.png" alt="change current active form button"> below the form list. This will allow you to troubleshoot different forms and how they behave when changed to the active form in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/current-form-screen.png" alt="other debug features">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also choose to &lt;strong>Enable rule debugging&lt;/strong> by choosing the &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> radio button, also below the nested list. This will enable the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger">Rule debugger&lt;/a> feature, however instead of executing within a process design preview window, it will enact upon your selected process instance. The rule debugger modal dialog will appear in the bottom right-hand corner of the screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-within-rule-diagnostics.png" alt="Rule debugger modal dialog within rule diagnostics">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When finished troubleshooting, click the &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> button to close the process history dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Rule Diagnostics&lt;/strong>, find out more about other troubleshooting features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/">Custom Widget Debugging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/">Rule Debugger&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing">Version History and Auditing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Custom widget debugging</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>