<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Troubleshooting</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Rule debugger</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Rule debugger&lt;/strong> is a troubleshooting feature that allows you to visualise each rule being executed in your process design within the preview window. It provides an insight into the process&amp;rsquo; logical flow, and serves as an important troubleshooting feature if your process does not work as expected. As well as this, it states what rule is being executed and on what field it is acting upon, alongisde any associated conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before getting started, you must open a completed process design of your choice that features rules that require debugging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access the rule debugger feature:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to the left-hand pane of the designer screen and click on the &lt;strong>Run and preview process&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="run and preview process button" style="zoom:150%;" />.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview-process-left-hand-pane.png" alt="Left hand pane clicking the preview button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the preview window, click on the &lt;strong>Enable / Disable Rule debugging&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-btn.png" alt="rule debugger button"> in the top right corner of the window.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-preview2.png" alt="rule debugger in the preview window" style="zoom:80%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Begin entering data into your process as expected until the rule debugger modal dialog appears in the bottom right of the preview window. This appears as soon as the first rule is encountered in the design&amp;rsquo;s logical workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-modal.png" alt="Rule debugger dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rule debugger dialog displays information such as the &lt;strong>Rule&lt;/strong> currently being executed, any &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> associated with the rule and the &lt;strong>Field&lt;/strong> the rule is being enacted upon. Three buttons are also displayed, allowing you to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Execute rule&lt;/strong> - executes the currently displayed rule on the currently displayed field, along with any conditions specified. Depending on the flow of your process, either another rule will appear, or the dialog box will disappear and await further data input into the form&amp;rsquo;s fields. The next rule will be paused to allow for an incremental troubleshooting experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resume&lt;/strong> - resumes the execution of all rules in a chain. The rule debug dialog will only then reappear when new data is entered into another field in the process flow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Stop debug&lt;/strong> - exits the debugging mode and the rule debug dialog box disappears. You will receive no more messages about current rule execution, but will still be in the process preview window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can alter the conditions on the currently displayed rule (if any), by clicking on the &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> filter button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions-filter-btn.png" alt="Conditions filter button image">. This will display another modal dialog box, which gives you the option to change the conditon being applied to the rule, add further conditions, remove some conditons and more - allowing for the troubleshooting of different use cases within your process. To learn more about this, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-conditions.png" alt="Conditions dialog for rule debugger">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To exit the debugging process, you can click on the &lt;strong>Stop debug&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/stop-debug-btn.png" alt="stop debug button">, or alternatively click on the &lt;strong>Enable / Disable Rule debugging&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-btn.png" alt="rule debugger button" style="zoom:80%;" />, or click on the &lt;strong>Exit preview mode&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exit-preview-window-btn.png" alt="exit window preview button" style="zoom:80%;" />.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Rule debugger&lt;/strong>, find out more about other troubleshooting features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/">Custom widget debugging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/">Rule diagnostics&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing">Version history and Auditing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Rule diagnostics</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-diagnostics/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> is a troubleshooting feature within Kianda that allows you to view a nested list of all forms, fields and rules - the purpose being that you can choose to manually trigger these rules for diagnostic purposes, as well as toggle field visibility, re-assign forms, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rule diagnostics feature is available for troubleshooting specific &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Process instances&lt;/a> where as the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger">Rule debugger&lt;/a> feature focuses more so on troubleshooting a process design pre-publishing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before getting started, you must open a process instance of any status that you would like to perform rule diagnostics on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access the rule diagnostics feature:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On your chosen process instance, click on the &lt;strong>Process history&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-button.jpg" alt="process history button" style="zoom:150%;" /> in the top right-hand corner of the screen. This will open the Process history modal dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-btn2.png" alt="Process history">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the process history dialog, navigate to the &lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> tab. From here, you can view a nested list of all forms, fields and rules. In the example below, you can view rules and fields across three different forms in the process, as well as expand the onload rules. You can search for a specific element in your process by utilising the search bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-history-modal1.png" alt="rule diagnostics tab">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are many possibilities for testing your process instance, however in this example we will try to troubleshoot the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/send-email/">Send email rule&lt;/a> to ensure that the line manager receives the correctly formatted email during this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this, we will drill down into the following path: &lt;em>Asset request&lt;/em> form &amp;gt; &lt;em>Submit&lt;/em> button &amp;gt; &lt;em>Rules&lt;/em> &amp;gt; &lt;em>Email Line Manager&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expanding-process-instance.png" alt="Drill down into line manager">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Beside the &lt;em>Email Line Manager&lt;/em> rule, click on the orange &lt;strong>Trigger&lt;/strong> bolt button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trigger-btn.png" alt="trigger bolt button" style="zoom:150%;" /> to manually trigger the rule. This is a powerful feature as you do not need to fill out an entire process from start to finish to troubleshoot this. You will then see a &lt;em>Rule executed&lt;/em> alert at the top of the page, and the specific rule should perform as expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/request-assets-email.png" alt="Request assets email sent to the line manager" style="zoom:67%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are other features you can troubleshoot in the &lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong> tab such as clicking:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle form visibility&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/toggle-visibility-btn.png" alt="toggle visibility button"> - to hide or show the selected form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make editable&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editable-btn.png" alt="Editable button"> - make the current field/form editable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Re-assign form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/re-assign-btn.png" alt="re-assign button"> - to assign the form to a different person&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Go to form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/go-to-form-btn.png" alt="go to form button"> - snaps to the selected form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle field enable&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/toggle-field-enable-btn.png" alt="toggle field enable"> - to enable/disable the selected field&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As well as this, the &lt;strong>Rule executed status&lt;/strong> can be seen beside each rule - a green tick &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/green-tick.png" alt="green tick"> for executed, and a grey tick &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/grey-tick.png" alt="grey tick"> for not executed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-diagnostics-other-btns.png" alt="Rule diagnostics other buttons">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the current form in your process instance, you can click on the &lt;strong>Chance current active form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-current-active-form-btn.png" alt="change current active form button"> below the nested list. This will allow you to troubleshoot different forms and how they behave when changed to the active form in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/current-form-screen.png" alt="other debug features">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also choose to &lt;strong>Enable rule debugging&lt;/strong> by choosing the &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> radio button, also below the nested list. This will enable the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger">Rule debugger&lt;/a> feature, however instead of executing within a process design preview window, it will enact upon your selected process instance. The rule debugger modal dialog will appear in the bottom right-hand corner of the screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rule-debugger-within-rule-diagnostics.png" alt="Rule debugger modal dialog within rule diagnostics">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When finished troubleshooting, click the &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> button to close the process history dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>Rule diagnostics&lt;/strong>, find out more about other troubleshooting features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/">Custom widget debugging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/rule-debugger/">Rule debugger&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing">Version history and Auditing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Custom widget debugging</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/custom-widget-debugging/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Version history and auditing</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/troubleshooting/version-history-and-auditing/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>