<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Data connectors</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/</link><description>Recent content in Data connectors on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Active directory</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/active-directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/active-directory/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: DocuSign</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/docusign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/docusign/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the data connectors within Kianda that you can connect to is &lt;strong>DocuSign&lt;/strong>. DocuSign enables organisations to manage electronic agreements by offering electronic signatures also know as &lt;strong>eSignatures&lt;/strong>. eSignatures are a way to sign different types of documents electronically on many different devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the DocuSign data connector when a process your have created requires you to send individual documents or envelopes to get them signed &lt;strong>electronically&lt;/strong>. With the connector you can access different types of &lt;strong>templates&lt;/strong> that you have created within your DocuSign account, &lt;strong>download&lt;/strong> documents, access already existing envelopes to see their &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>summary&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-you-get-started">Before you get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In advance of using the DocuSign data connector, you must have an account with DocuSign. This account is used to authorise a connection between your Kianda subscription and your DocuSign account itself, so that the DocuSign &lt;strong>Application Programming Interface (API)&lt;/strong> can be used. There are two types of accounts that you can create in DocuSign. An &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account and a &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account. Take note which account you have created as this information will be used to create a different connection within Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>DocuSign&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>DocuSign details&lt;/strong> page, where you can start setting up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/docusign-details.jpg" alt="DocuSign details page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your DocuSign connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DocuSign Environment&lt;/strong> - indicates which environment you have your account created in. There are two types of accounts that you can create in DocuSign. A &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account and an &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account. If you have an ordinary account and your trying to connect to DocuSign, you need to select the &lt;strong>Live&lt;/strong> option, and if your account is a developer account, then select the &lt;strong>Demo&lt;/strong> option. This is important as the authentication of the account is different for those two types of account.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Demo&lt;/strong> - indicates that your DocuSign account is a &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Live&lt;/strong> - indicates that your DocuSign account is an &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> - allows you to &lt;strong>authorize&lt;/strong> the connection with your DocuSign account and Kianda. When you click this button, a DocuSign window will open allowing you to log in into your DocuSign to &lt;strong>authenticate&lt;/strong> your account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added File system details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="docusign-functions">DocuSign functions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use the DocuSign data connector within Kianda, there are &lt;strong>default functions&lt;/strong> that are invoked from DocuSign&amp;rsquo;s API. These functions enable you to access a number of DocuSign&amp;rsquo;s functionalities. You can use each DocuSign function by using the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> set of rules, to learn more about Data rules go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>. With each DocuSign function you use, data needs to be passed into the function know as &lt;strong>payload&lt;/strong> and data is also returned, known as &lt;strong>response&lt;/strong>. When using the Data rules, you are presented with &lt;strong>Input mapping&lt;/strong> which is equivalent to the &lt;strong>payload&lt;/strong>, this is used to pass data into the function, for example when you need a document signed, you need to pass in a document file to be signed, in other words, the document file you pass in is the &lt;strong>payload&lt;/strong>. The &lt;strong>Results mapping&lt;/strong> is equivalent to the &lt;strong>response&lt;/strong>, this is used to populate your form fields when a DocuSign function returns data, for example &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of an envelope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a list of all functions available when using the DocuSign data connector. To learn more about the &lt;strong>payload&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>response&lt;/strong> for the available functions go to the &lt;a href="https://developers.docusign.com/docs/esign-rest-api/reference/">DocuSign API Reference&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>sendDocument&lt;/strong> - allows you to send one or more documents to a recipient to get them signed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>sendEnvelope&lt;/strong> - allows you to send a document to a recipient using one of your DocuSign templates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>listTemplates&lt;/strong> - retrieves the &lt;strong>templateID&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>templateName&lt;/strong> of all templates from your DocuSign account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>getEnvelope&lt;/strong> - retrieves information from an envelope using an &lt;strong>envelopeID&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>getEnvelopeSummary&lt;/strong> - retrieves a summary of an envelope using an &lt;strong>envelopeID&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>listEnvelopeDocuments&lt;/strong> - retrieves any documents that are contained within an envelope using an &lt;strong>envelopeID&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>downloadDocument&lt;/strong> - allows you to download a specific document using a &lt;strong>documentID&lt;/strong> from an envelope using an &lt;strong>envelopeID&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>listTemplateSigners&lt;/strong> - retrieves the name, role and &lt;strong>recipientID&lt;/strong> of all signers from a template using a &lt;strong>templateID&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>getSigningUrl&lt;/strong> - retrieves a URL to a signature made on an envelope using an &lt;strong>envelopeID&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="example-use-case-of-docusign-function">Example use case of DocuSign function&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Take the function &lt;strong>listTemplates&lt;/strong> as an example. The &lt;strong>listTemplates&lt;/strong> function &lt;strong>returns (response)&lt;/strong> an &lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> and the &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> of all templates that you have created in your DocuSign account. To use this function effectively, you can use the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule with combination of the &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> input. The &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule will access all templates and map the results into the table. For each template in your DocuSign account, the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule will add a table row with the appropriate &lt;strong>Template IDs&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Template Names&lt;/strong> of each template, here is the steps to achieve this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To show case the functionality explained above, we will apply the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule to a &lt;strong>button&lt;/strong> but it can be applied to a form field, a form or a process (the rule will be executed when the process loads). Each time we press this button, a table will be populated with a list of &lt;strong>Template IDs&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Template Names&lt;/strong> from our DocuSign account.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create a button in your process, to learn how to create a button go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/button/">Button control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create a table with two columns and call them &lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>. To learn how to create a table and add columns go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Apply the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule to the button by following the steps from &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/find-items/">Find items rule&lt;/a>. When following the steps of the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule, make sure to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>Map results to table&lt;/strong> option and select the table you created. This way the &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong> rule will create as many rows as there is templates in your DocuSign account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>listTemplates&lt;/strong> function does not require any &lt;strong>payload (Input mapping)&lt;/strong>, so delete all fields from the &lt;strong>input mapping&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>listTemplates&lt;/strong> as your data source from your DocuSign connector.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the appropriate column field from your table and results field from your data source in the &lt;strong>Results mapping&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/docusign-find-items.jpg" alt="Find items rule ">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SharePoint service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Dropbox</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/dropbox/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Dropbox&lt;/strong> data system connector allows you to the Dropbox cloud file system as a data source for your Kianda forms or dashboards. Dropbox is a personal cloud based file system with many subscriptions including team subscriptions. This allows you to store files online and share them with your team or use it as a backup. This means that as your processes are running they will use the information from the cloud file system or depending on the process, update or delete information at the Dropbox cloud file system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the Dropbox connector when you want a process within your Kianda subscription to have &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong> to your Dropbox cloud file directory. You can &lt;strong>extract&lt;/strong> files from Dropbox into Kianda by using a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field control. Set the datasource of the List field to be your Dropbox connector allowing you to access files from you Dropbox account, to learn more about the List field go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>. You can also use the Dropbox data connector within the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> set of rules, these rules allow you to perform &lt;strong>Create, Read, Update&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong> (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations. To learn more about the Data rules, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-getting-started">Before getting started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In advance of using the Dropbox data connector, you must have an account with Dropbox. The account is used to authorise a connection between your Kianda subscription and your Dropbox account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>Dropbox&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>Dropbox data connector&lt;/strong> page, where you can start setting up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dropbox.jpg" alt="File system detail page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your Dropbox connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> - allows you to &lt;strong>authorize&lt;/strong> the connection with your Dropbox account and Kianda. When you click this button, a Dropbox window will open allowing you to log in into your Dropbox to &lt;strong>authenticate&lt;/strong> your account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - represents the current status of the connection.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector were not fully completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>test failed&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector are incorrect and the connection has failed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong> - means that the connector has successfully connected and its ready to be used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Dropbox authentication window will open. Enter your login details to &lt;strong>authenticate&lt;/strong> the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added the Dropbox details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>Dropbox details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="dropbox-parameters">Dropbox parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use the &lt;strong>Dropbox&lt;/strong> datasource, there are &lt;strong>default parameters&lt;/strong> invoked from the files that you can access. For example when you create a &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> filed in a Kianda form and use Dropbox as its datasource, these Dropbox parameters will appear in &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field in the &lt;strong>Edit field dialog box&lt;/strong>, see &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> for example in the image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dropbox-parameters.jpg" alt="File system parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The File system parameters that appear in those three dropdown fields are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - name of the file including the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NameNoExtension&lt;/strong> - name of the file without the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Path&lt;/strong> - displays the full path to the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Extension&lt;/strong> - displays just the extension of the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was last modified.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Created&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was created.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderName&lt;/strong> - name of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderPath&lt;/strong> - path of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>Dropbox connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Email connector</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In your company&amp;rsquo;s Kianda platform you can connect an emailing service such as Outlook or Gmail. This allows you to send automated emails from a specified email account such as support@ or info@. The email connector feature It is mostly used when applying the &lt;strong>Send email&lt;/strong> rule, which allows you to set a &lt;strong>From&lt;/strong> field. For example setting up a payroll &lt;strong>Email connector&lt;/strong> would be used to send automated emails to employees with their payslips attached. To learn more about send email rule go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/send-email/">Send email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>Email&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>Email connection details&lt;/strong> page where we can start setting up the email connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/email-connector-settings.jpg" alt="Sharepoint datasources">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose a &lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> for your email connector. This is used to distinguish between different email connectors on your platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the following example we will use an outlook office 365 IMAP to set up the connector. Fill in the following details:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>IMAP server&lt;/strong> - the IMAP server address of your provider. &lt;strong>outlook.office365.com&lt;/strong> in this example&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>IMAP server port&lt;/strong> - the IMAP port your provider listens to. Port number is &lt;strong>993&lt;/strong> in this example.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use SSL&lt;/strong> - IMAP security of your provider. Outlook uses SSL therefore we need to &lt;strong>enable&lt;/strong> it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Username / email&lt;/strong> - the email provider credentials. In this example we are creating a support@ connector.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - the password to access your email account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable mail send from&lt;/strong> - allows you to fill in details used to send emails.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about IMAP settings and how to obtain them, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/#imap-settings">IMAP settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/email-connector-imap.jpg" alt="IMAP settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Enable mail send from&lt;/strong>, you are prested with SMTP details. Fill out the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMTP server&lt;/strong> - the SMTP server address of your provider. In this example it is &lt;strong>smtp.office365.com&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMTP server port&lt;/strong> - the SMTP port your provider listens to. In this example it&amp;rsquo;s port &lt;strong>587&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use SSL&lt;/strong> - IMAP security of your provider. Outlook uses SSL therefore we need to &lt;strong>enable&lt;/strong> it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Email Address&lt;/strong> - Used to send test email to ensure emails are delivered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use same credentials as above&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> - selecting this will ensure to use the same credentials as stated in the above IMAP settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> - selecting this will enable you to use different credentials for the SMTP server.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To learn more about IMAP settings and how to obtain them, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/#smtp-details">SMTP settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added Email details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>Email details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button">to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the datasource management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="imap-settings">IMAP settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Internet Message Access Protocol, or IMAP, is &lt;strong>a standard email retrieval (incoming) protocol&lt;/strong>. It stores email messages on a mail server and enables the recipient to view and manipulate them as though they were stored locally on their device(s). These settings are needed to connect to your emailing service and authentication of ownership. In order to activate your email connector we need to fill out the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: some email providers need IMAP settings enabled as they are disabled by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>IMAP server&lt;/strong> - IMAP server is an address for a given mailing service, it usually comes in the form of &lt;strong>imap.yourdomain.com&lt;/strong>. For example Google&amp;rsquo;s IMAP is &lt;strong>imap.gmail.com&lt;/strong>. To access your IMAP address, contact your email provider or email server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>IMAP server port&lt;/strong> - Indicates which port your IMAP server listens to. The IMAP server typically listen to a well known port &lt;strong>143&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>993&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>SSL/TSL&lt;/strong> functionality. The port information can be found by contacting your email provider.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use SSL&lt;/strong> - Secure Socket Layer (SSL) is a standard technology for keeping the internet connection secure and safeguarding. Contact your email provider to find out if &lt;strong>SSL&lt;/strong> is required when accessing IMAP server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Username/ email&lt;/strong> - The credentials used to access your emailing account. Indicates which email will be used to send mail.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - The credentials used to access your emailing account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable mail send from&lt;/strong> - With this option you can choose the ability to send email &lt;strong>OUT&lt;/strong> to others using the connected emailing service. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, you need to fill in &lt;strong>SMTP details&lt;/strong>. To find out more got to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/#smtp-details">SMTP detail&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="smtp-details">SMTP details&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Simple Mail Transfer Protocol or SMTP, is &lt;strong>a standard email outgoing (sending) protocol&lt;/strong>. It is used for sending email messages from one email account to another via the internet. The SMTP server checks whether the two emails are valid and proceeds with sending of the email. To be able sending of email using your email provider, the following details need to be filled out:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMTP server&lt;/strong> - SMTP server is an address for a given mailing service, it usually comes in the form of &lt;strong>smtp.yourdomain.com&lt;/strong>. For example Google&amp;rsquo;s SMTP is &lt;strong>smtp.gmail.com&lt;/strong>. To access your IMAP address, contact your email provider or email server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMTP server port&lt;/strong> - Indicates which port your SMTP server listens to. The SMTP servers typically listen to port &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong> if unencrypted or &lt;strong>465&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>SSL&lt;/strong> encryption. The port information can be found by contacting your email provider.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Email address&lt;/strong> - Used to send test email to ensure emails are delivered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use same credentials as above&lt;/strong> - By choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, you will be using the same credentials to log into your SMTP server as you are to the IMAP server. If your SMTP server credentials are different, select &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> to be presented with:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SMTP Username&lt;/strong> - The credentials used to access your SMTP provider.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - The credentials used to access your SMTP provider.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-a-global-smtp-mail-connector">Setting up a Global SMTP mail connector&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As mentioned above, you can create multiple &lt;strong>Email connectors&lt;/strong> and use them to send emails using different email accounts such as support@ or info@. You can also choose to ignore all &lt;strong>email connectors&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;a href="mailto:no-reply@kianda.com">no-reply@kianda.com&lt;/a> emails by enabling one &lt;strong>Global SMTP connector&lt;/strong> which forces all sent email to come from one single connector. To set a &lt;strong>Global SMTP connector&lt;/strong>, you need &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> rights in your Kianda platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: to set up a global SMTP mail connector, you need to have an &lt;strong>Email connector&lt;/strong> set up, see the steps under &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> on how to set up an email connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Subscription Details&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under General settings, select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> on the &lt;strong>Enable Global SMTP Main Connector&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>SMTP Email&lt;/strong> connector dropdown box appears. Select your desired email connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Enable save to &amp;ldquo;Sent Items&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> option select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> if you want your email to save all emails sent and select &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> to not save. If you select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, the emails will be saved in the &lt;strong>Sent Items&lt;/strong> folder in your email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/email-connector-global-settings.jpg" alt="Global settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: File system</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/file-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/file-system/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> data connector allows you to use your local file system as a data source for your Kianda forms or dashboards. This means that as your processes are running, they will use the information from the local file system or depending on the process, update or delete information at the local file system location. Kianda has the ability to extract files, navigate subfolders and write new files into the directory, this includes local file and internet file systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using this type of datasource is useful when you want Kianda to have access to your directory, to extract and read files as well as writing files to the directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, where you can start setting up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-system-details.jpg" alt="File system detail page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your file system connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Root folder path&lt;/strong> - type in manually the file path to the folder of your connector, for example C:\Documents\GreenITR. The connector will be able to access data only in this folder and folders within.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>File search pattern&lt;/strong> - this options can be used to limit the type of files for interaction, by using file extensions. For example typing in &lt;code>*.txt&lt;/code> will only output the .txt files within the folder path, it will ignore all other path endings and will not display them. To set pattern you need to type in &lt;code>*&lt;/code> followed by &lt;code>.extenstion&lt;/code> for example &lt;code>*.txt&lt;/code> , &lt;code>*.docx&lt;/code> or &lt;code>*.pdf&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Search options&lt;/strong> - this only allows you to search the files of the top directory that is set in the &lt;strong>Root folder path&lt;/strong> or all other files of other directories within.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For example selecting if &lt;strong>Top Directory Only&lt;/strong> is selected, you will be able to see only the files that are in &lt;strong>Root folder path&lt;/strong> while ignoring folders, meaning that no subdirectories can be navigated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If &lt;strong>All Directories&lt;/strong> is selected, you will be able to see files that are in &lt;strong>Root folder path&lt;/strong> and all files from within each folder, or subfolders.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is enabled and cannot be changed, the cloud connect is needed to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between the &lt;strong>local file system&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. This lightweight app will sit on the PC or server where the files reside. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> website. You must choose the correct &lt;strong>PC connection&lt;/strong> which &lt;strong>contains the folder&lt;/strong> specified in the &lt;strong>Root folder path&lt;/strong>, otherwise the connection will fail.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added File system details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="file-system-parameters">File system parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use a &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> datasource, there are &lt;strong>default parameters&lt;/strong> invoked from the files. For example when you create a &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> in a Kianda form using a File system datasource, these File system parameters will appear in &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field in the &lt;strong>Edit field dialog box&lt;/strong>, see &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> for example in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-system-parameters.jpg" alt="File system parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The File system parameters that appear in those three dropdown fields are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - name of the file including the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NameNoExtension&lt;/strong> - name of the file without the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Path&lt;/strong> - displays the full path to the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Extension&lt;/strong> - displays just the extension of the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was last modified.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Created&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was created.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderName&lt;/strong> - name of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderPath&lt;/strong> - path of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>File system service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: FTP</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/ftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/ftp/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the data connectors that you can connect to is &lt;strong>File Transfer Protocol (FTP)&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>FTP&lt;/strong> is a standard communication protocol used for the transfer of computer files from one system to another over the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>FTP&lt;/strong> data connector allows you to use an &lt;strong>online&lt;/strong> file system as a data source for your Kianda forms or dashboards. This means that as your processes are running they will use the information from the online file system or depending on the process, update or delete information at in the online file system location. Kianda has the ability to &lt;strong>extract&lt;/strong> files, &lt;strong>navigate&lt;/strong> subfolders and &lt;strong>write&lt;/strong> new files into the online directory. Any operation performed using the FTP data connector will directly change files within the online file system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the FTP connector when you want &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>modify&lt;/strong> data or files within any &lt;strong>folder&lt;/strong> in your FTP server. You can perform Create, Read, Update and Delete (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations on any files within the FTP server that you have access to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>FTP&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>FTP details&lt;/strong> page, where you can start setting up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ftp-details.jpg" alt="File system detail page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your FTP connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTP Server&lt;/strong> - the &lt;strong>server name&lt;/strong> of the server you want to access or the &lt;strong>IP address&lt;/strong> where the server is hosted. When you are running a &lt;strong>local&lt;/strong> server on your machine you can use your &lt;strong>own&lt;/strong> IP address as the server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTP root folder&lt;/strong> - name of the root folder that is specified in your server. Note that the root folder that you specify here must be &lt;strong>exactly&lt;/strong> the same as on the FTP server. For example If your root folder on the FTP server is &lt;code>/Files&lt;/code>, you must also specify that the &lt;strong>FTP root folder&lt;/strong> is &lt;code>/Files&lt;/code>. It is possible to successfully connect the FTP connector if you specify a different &lt;strong>FTP root folder&lt;/strong> than on the server but you will not be able to access the files properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTP port&lt;/strong> - enter the port on which your server listens on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use SSL&lt;/strong> - check this box if your FTP server has SSL security.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTP username&lt;/strong> - enter the username you use to connect to your FTP server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTP password&lt;/strong> - enter the password you use to connect to your FTP server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is disabled, the cloud connect is used to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between a &lt;strong>locally run FTP server&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>. Check this option if you want to connect to a server that is running on your local machine. When &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> is enabled, a &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> option appears.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> subscription. This option is used to select the PC &lt;strong>connection&lt;/strong> that &lt;strong>runs&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>local FTP server&lt;/strong> that you want to connect to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ftp-connectors.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added File system details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="ftp-parameters">FTP parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use a &lt;strong>FTP&lt;/strong> datasource, there are &lt;strong>default parameters&lt;/strong> invoked from the files. For example when you create a &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> in a Kianda form using a FTP datasource, these FTP parameters will appear in &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field in the &lt;strong>Edit field dialog box&lt;/strong>, see &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> for example in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-system-parameters.jpg" alt="File system parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The FTP parameters that appear in those three dropdown fields are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - name of the file including the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NameNoExtension&lt;/strong> - name of the file without the extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Path&lt;/strong> - displays the full path to the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Extension&lt;/strong> - displays just the extension of the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was last modified.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Created&lt;/strong> - displays the date and time when the file was created.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderName&lt;/strong> - name of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ParentFolderPath&lt;/strong> - path of the folder that contains the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>FTP service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Google drive</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/google-drive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/google-drive/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Kianda Cloud Connect</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> is a piece of software that &lt;strong>establishes a connection&lt;/strong> between your &lt;strong>local machine&lt;/strong> and your &lt;strong>Kianda subscription&lt;/strong>. This lightweight app will sit on your PC or server where files reside that you need to use in Kianda processes. It allows the data to &lt;strong>travel&lt;/strong> from your local machine to the Kianda Cloud Connect service, and then the Kianda Cloud Connect service sends data to your Kianda subscription. This data transfer works both ways depending on what operation you are performing for example &lt;strong>Deleting&lt;/strong> a file or &lt;strong>Creating&lt;/strong> one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda Cloud Connect authenticates with a user created in Kianda, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/">User management&lt;/a> for more details on users and send information to and from Kianda using port 80. See details below on how to set up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloading-kianda-cloud-connect">Downloading Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can download &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> software in any details page of data source that might use it, for example in a &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> data connector:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, where you can click on &lt;strong>Download Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-system-download-KCCjpg.jpg" alt="File system detail page">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on Download Kianda Cloud Connect will automatically download a zipped folder. Extract the contents of the folder and open the &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> Windows Installer Package. You will need administrative privileges on your device in order to install the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cloud-connector-msi.jpg" alt="Cloud Connect package">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the Windows Installer Package &lt;strong>CloudConnect.msi&lt;/strong> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Security on the device may prevent you from installing the app. If the below window appears click on the &lt;strong>More Info&lt;/strong> link and then click &lt;strong>Run Anyway&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/windows-defender.jpg" alt="Windows Defender message">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Welcome to Kianda Cloud Connect Setup Wizard&lt;/strong>, follow the installation wizard to install the application. Click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Select Installation Folder&lt;/strong> window, pick a folder where you want to install the software. Click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Confirm Installation&lt;/strong> window, click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> in the administrator dialog box to give Kianda Cloud Connect access to your PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Installation Complete&lt;/strong> window click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong>. Once installed the application will be available on your desktop as an app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-cloud-app.jpg" alt="Kianda Cloud Connect app">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Double-click the icon to open the application, then follow the steps below to connect your PC to Kianda Cloud Connect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="connecting-your-pc-to-kianda-cloud-connect">Connecting your PC to Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>establish a connection&lt;/strong> between your &lt;strong>Kianda subscription&lt;/strong> and your l&lt;strong>ocal machine&lt;/strong>, you need to login using a &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>username&lt;/strong> (email) and &lt;strong>password&lt;/strong>. Note that the &lt;strong>user&lt;/strong> you are trying to establish a connection with &lt;strong>must be an administrator&lt;/strong> and needs to be a &lt;strong>unique username&lt;/strong> (email). The username you want to establish the connection &lt;strong>&lt;u>cannot&lt;/u>&lt;/strong> be used in &lt;strong>more than one Kianda subscriptions&lt;/strong> as Kianda Cloud Connect will not be able to tell which subscription you want to connect to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-cloud-connect-app.jpg" alt="Kianda Cloud Connect">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To establish a connection fill out the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Machine Identity&lt;/strong> - automatically sets the identity using the name of your local PC or server that the application has been installed on. This field is an un-editable value that &lt;strong>cannot&lt;/strong> be changed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Kianda Username&lt;/strong> - type in the username/email of the user from your &lt;strong>Kianda subscription&lt;/strong> you want to establish a connection with. This username must be &lt;strong>unique across all Kianda subscriptions&lt;/strong> and must be an &lt;strong>administrator&lt;/strong>. For example you &lt;strong>cannot establish a connection&lt;/strong> with a &lt;a href="mailto:connector@domain.com">connector@domain.com&lt;/a> if this email is used in more than one subscription, as Kianda Cloud Connect will not be able to determine which subscription to make a connection with. For more information on users go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/">Users and groups&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Kianda Password&lt;/strong> - type in the password used to login, for the user in the &lt;strong>Kianda Username&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - the colour shown denotes if the connection is active, as a &lt;strong>green&lt;/strong> colour, or inactive as a &lt;strong>red&lt;/strong> colour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable Local Server&lt;/strong> - this allows Kianda to pass through the current server and connect to a local server or offline server/PC. Click the checkbox to enable this, followed by the ellipsis button to continue. Then add in the &lt;strong>Local URL&lt;/strong> and click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once the username and password have been entered, click on the &lt;strong>Login&lt;/strong> button to establish a connection. It is recommended to have a specific user account that is used solely for the purpose of connecting the data connector to the Kianda subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If the connection succeeded, in the &lt;strong>Cloud Connection&lt;/strong> dialog box, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to complete the connection. Once the connection has been made the log in the dialog box will be populated with messages confirming the login has occurred. A dialog box will open confirming that the connection has been successfully established. When the connection has been established successfully, Kianda Cloud Connect will automatically connect to your subscription when the PC is turned on therefore you do not need to login when the PC is turned on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cloud-connection-established.jpg" alt="Cloud connection established successfully">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Clear&lt;/strong> to clear the connection log in the body of the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>All established connections will be visible in the &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect Connector&lt;/strong> section in any of the datasource connectors that use it, for example &lt;strong>File system&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>SQL Server&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-cloud-connect-connector.jpg" alt="Kianda Cloud Connect Connectors section">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The connector is now established and can be used when designing processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To find out more about how to build processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: MySql</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/mysql/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a &lt;strong>MySQL Server&lt;/strong> datasource. MySQL is a relational database management system (&lt;strong>RDBMS&lt;/strong>) used to manage structured collections of data. This data can consist of anything from a simple to do list to a more complex organisation network. Using the MySQL server as your datasource, you can perform any Create, Read, Update and Delete (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations using the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules provided in the Kianda platform, to learn more about data rules go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>. Using the MySQL server connector, you have access to all tables within your database from your server, keep in mind that you can perform CRUD operations on data within a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> of the database, but you &lt;strong>cannot&lt;/strong> create or delete &lt;strong>tables themselves&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the MySQL Server connector when you want &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>modify&lt;/strong> data within a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> in your MySQL server. You can connect the MySQL server connector to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field as its datasource, meaning you can access information from a table and display the information that are stored in the table. For example if your MySQL server contains tables such as &lt;strong>Employees&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Purchases&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Standing Orders&lt;/strong>, you will be able to connect the list field to one of those tables giving you CRUD access to its data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a table &lt;strong>Employees&lt;/strong> as an example, if this employee table contains data about the employees in your company such as name, phone number, email address and home address. You can &lt;strong>create&lt;/strong> a new employee by providing necessary information, you can &lt;strong>read&lt;/strong> (display) employee data, &lt;strong>update&lt;/strong> employees information for example when a home address has changed and you can &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> an employee from the table. Those are the CRUD operations you can perform on MySQL server through a process within Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-getting-started">Before getting started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When establishing a connection using MySQL data connector, you are creating a connection with a &lt;strong>Database&lt;/strong> from a server, not the &lt;strong>server&lt;/strong> itself. Before continuing make sure that your MySQL server has a &lt;strong>database&lt;/strong> you can connect to. A database can represent type of data you want to access and with in this database, you need to create a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> representing the actual data you will have CRUD access to. For example creating a database of your company name such as &lt;strong>GreenITR&lt;/strong>, and within this database you can create tables to represent your &lt;strong>Employees&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Purchases&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Standing Orders&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>MySQL&lt;/strong> from the list of datasources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>MySQL Server details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/mysql-details.jpg" alt="SQL Server details page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your MySQL server connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Server&lt;/strong> - the name of the server you want to access or the IP address where the server is hosted. When you are running a local server on your machine you can use &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> as the server name. If you are connecting to a public server, enter in the name of the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Database&lt;/strong> - the name of the database from your server that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> - username used to log into the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - password used to log into the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is disabled, the cloud connect is used to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between a &lt;strong>locally run MySQL server&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>. Check this option if you want to connect to a server that is running on your local machine. When &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> is enabled, a &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> option appears.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> subscription. This option is used to select the PC &lt;strong>connection&lt;/strong> that &lt;strong>runs&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>local MySQL server&lt;/strong> that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - represents the current status of the connection.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector were not fully completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>test failed&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector are incorrect and the connection has failed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong> - means that the connector has successfully connected and its ready to be used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added the MySQL server details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>MySQL Server details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SQL Server connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Office 365</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/office-365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/office-365/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a connector to Office 365. Kianda has the ability to read users’ profiles, extract data, update users and groups and enable Single Sign-On (SSO). The Office 365 datasource can be used for example to automatically import users using a scheduled task within Kianda or with individual Kianda processes to update the configuration of users and groups within Office 365.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have an Office 365 subscription, you can create an Office 365 data connector so that Kianda can access data and manipulate data at that data source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: To create this datasource you need to have an &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong> role in Kianda. You also need to be an &lt;strong>administrator in Office 365&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An Office 365 data connector can be configured by users with the role &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. These users can access the datasource management function, found under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/open-data-sources.jpg" alt="Opening data sources from Administration">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the main view you will see any existing data sources that have been created. From this view, you can click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a data source to see details or &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> a data source by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin/trash button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and a range of data source connectors will appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-range.jpg" alt="Data source list">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Office 365&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Office 365 data connector&lt;/strong> screen opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/office365-data-connector.jpg" alt="Office365 data connector">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill in the first set of fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name –&lt;/strong> this is the name of the data source. Use an appropriate name, as this will be used within your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Read all users&amp;rsquo; full profiles –&lt;/strong> by default, this is enabled and cannot be disabled. This allows Kianda processes to read all user profiles that exist in Office 365.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Read and write users &amp;amp; groups&lt;/strong> - by checking this option it will allow Kianda the rights to read users and group information and update information, performing &amp;lsquo;write operations&amp;rsquo; in Office 365, such as assigning a user license and adding users to groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable Azure OpenID Connect Single-Sign-On&lt;/strong> - checking this checkbox enables a user to sign into Kianda using their Office 365 login. For more details see the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/sso/">SSO page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After these details have been completed, you will need to &lt;a href="#authorize-the-connection">Authorize the connection&lt;/a> as the datasource will have a &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of &lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> until authorised. When authorized for use, the status will be &lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="authorize-the-connection">Authorize the connection&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Before the datasource can be used it will need to be authorised. Click on the &lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/authorize.jpg" alt="Authorize button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A pop up appears asking you to sign in to your Office365 account. You must be an &lt;strong>administrator in Office 365&lt;/strong> to complete authorization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/office365-login.jpg" alt="Office 365 Login">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enter your &lt;strong>email&lt;/strong> and click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then enter your &lt;strong>password&lt;/strong> and click on &lt;strong>Sign in&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/password-office365.jpg" alt="Office365 password">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to Stay signed in.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If your details are correct and you are an administrator, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong> and the status changes to &lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/office365-ready.jpg" alt="Office 365 connector ready">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> button changes to &lt;strong>Re-Authorize&lt;/strong>. If authorization is removed from within Office 365, the datasource will need to be re-authorized from within Kianda. In addition, Microsoft security policy requires the connection to Office 365 to be re-authorized every 6 months. To re-authorize, click on the &lt;strong>Re-Authorize&lt;/strong> button and repeat steps 2 to 5 above.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button">to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the datasource management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="office-365-parameters">Office 365 parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use an Office 365 datasource, there are &lt;strong>default options&lt;/strong> that can be passed as parameters, for example when using conditions with Office 365 data connectors. These are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User List&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group List&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find Users&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find Groups&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create Group&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add User to Group&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remove User From Group&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Licence Plan List&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assign Licence to User&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remove Licence from User&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>Office 365 connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Oracle database</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/oracle-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/oracle-database/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is an &lt;strong>Oracle&lt;/strong> datasource. Oracle is a relational database management system (&lt;strong>RDBMS&lt;/strong>) used to manage structured collections of data. This data can consist of a collection of data from a simple to do list to a more complex organisation network. The Oracle database is a structured format consisting of rows and columns. Using the Oracle connector as your datasource, you can perform any &lt;strong>Create&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Read&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong> (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations using the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules provided in the Kianda platform, to learn more about data rules go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>. Using the Oracle connector, you have access to all tables within your database from your server, keep in mind that you can perform CRUD operations on the data from a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> of the database, but you &lt;strong>cannot&lt;/strong> create or delete &lt;strong>tables themselves&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>Oracle&lt;/strong> from the list of datasources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>Oracle details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/oracle-details.jpg" alt="SQL Server details page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your Oracle server connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Data Source&lt;/strong> - this field is used to provide the name of your host that you want to connect to. When accessing a public Oracle server, the host name must follow a URL style format, for example &lt;code>https:/{host}:{port}&lt;/code>. When connecting to a server that is run on your local machine, you can use &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> as well as the &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> .&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Schema&lt;/strong> - the name of the database from your server that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> - username used to log into the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - password used to log into the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is disabled, the cloud connect is used to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between a &lt;strong>locally run Oracle server&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>. Check this option if you want to connect to a server that is running on your local machine. When &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> is enabled, a &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> option appears.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> subscription. This option is used to select the PC &lt;strong>connection&lt;/strong> that &lt;strong>runs&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>local Oracle server&lt;/strong> that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - represents the current status of the connection.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector were not fully completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>test failed&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector are incorrect and the connection has failed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong> - means that the connector has successfully connected and its ready to be used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added the Oracle details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>Oracle details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SQL Server connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: PowerShell</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/powershell/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the data connectors within Kianda that you can connect to is &lt;strong>PowerShell&lt;/strong>. With the PowerShell connector you are able to use PowerShell scripts from within Kianda. You can call your scripts with the &lt;strong>Data rules&lt;/strong> that are available in Kianda, use &lt;strong>input mapping&lt;/strong> to pass &lt;strong>parameters&lt;/strong> to your PowerShell script and &lt;strong>receive&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>outcome&lt;/strong> of the script using results mapping. To learn more about input and result mapping visit one of the Data rules, for example &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/create-item/">Create Item&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the DocuSign data connector when a process your have created requires you to send individual documents or envelopes to get them signed &lt;strong>electronically&lt;/strong>. With the connector you can access different types of &lt;strong>templates&lt;/strong> that you have created within your DocuSign account, &lt;strong>download&lt;/strong> documents, access already existing envelopes to see their &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>summary&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-you-get-started">Before you get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In advance of using the DocuSign data connector, you must have an account with DocuSign. This account is used to authorise a connection between your Kianda subscription and your DocuSign account itself, so that the DocuSign &lt;strong>Application Programming Interface (API)&lt;/strong> can be used. There are two types of accounts that you can create in DocuSign. An &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account and a &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account. Take note which account you have created as this information will be used to create a different connection within Kianda.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Salesforce</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/salesforce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/salesforce/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the data connectors that you can connect to is &lt;strong>Salesforce&lt;/strong>. Salesforce provides customer relationship management software and applications focused on sales, customer service, marketing automation, and analytics. The Salesforce data connector allows you to access information from your Salesforce account which can then be used within your Kianda subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-you-get-started">Before you get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In advance of using the Salesforce data connector, you must have an account with Salesforce which is used to obtain information for a successful connection. If you have an account with Salesforce, all you need to create within the Salesforce application is a &lt;strong>Connected App&lt;/strong>. These connected apps within Salesforce enable external applications to integrate together using its APIs. The connected app will provide you with a &lt;strong>Consumer Key&lt;/strong> and a &lt;strong>Consumer Secret&lt;/strong>. These consumer information are used to establish the connection between your Connected app in Sales force and your Kianda subscription, to learn how to acquire the Consumer Key and Consumer Secret go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/salesforce/#acquiring-consumer-key-and-consumer-secret">Acquiring Consumer Key and Consumer Secret&lt;/a>. In order to successfully connect your Connected App and Kianda, the &lt;strong>settings&lt;/strong> of the Connected App in your salesforce account need to be &lt;strong>configured&lt;/strong>, to learn how to configure your Connected App in Salesforce go to &lt;a href="">Configuring Salesforce Connected App&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use a connected app to integrate external applications with the Salesforce API, such as a process that pulls in order status data from your Salesforce organisation into your Kianda subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>Salesforce&lt;/strong> from the list of data sources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be automatically brought to the &lt;strong>Salesforce details&lt;/strong> page, where you can start setting up the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/salesforce-details.jpg" alt="File system detail page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in the name for your Salesforce connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Client Id&lt;/strong> - used to identify the &lt;strong>Connected App&lt;/strong> created in your salesforce account. In salesforce this Client ID is called &lt;strong>Consumer Key&lt;/strong> and can be found in your Connected App &lt;strong>settings&lt;/strong>. To learn more about on how to find the &lt;strong>Consumer Key&lt;/strong> in sales force go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/salesforce/#finding-consumer-key-and-consumer-secret">Finding Consumer Key and Consumer Secret&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Client Secret&lt;/strong> - used to identify the &lt;strong>Connected App&lt;/strong> created in your salesforce account. In salesforce this Client ID is called &lt;strong>Consumer Secret&lt;/strong> and can be found in your Connected App &lt;strong>settings&lt;/strong>. To learn more about on how to find the &lt;strong>Consumer Secret&lt;/strong> in Salesforce go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/salesforce/#finding-consumer-key-and-consumer-secret">Finding Consumer Key and Consumer Secret&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Salesforce Environment&lt;/strong> - indicates which environment you have your account created in. There are two types of accounts that you can create in Salesforce. A &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account and an &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account. If you have an ordinary account and your trying to connect a salesforce app, you need to select the &lt;strong>Live&lt;/strong> option and if your account is a developer account, then select the &lt;strong>Sandbox&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Live&lt;/strong> - indicates that your Salesforce account is an &lt;strong>ordinary&lt;/strong> account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sandbox&lt;/strong> - indicates that your salesforce account is a &lt;strong>developer&lt;/strong> account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> - allows you to authorize the connection with your Connected App and Kianda. When you click this button, a Salesforce window will open allowing you to log in into Salesforce to authenticate your account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added File system details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>File system details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="acquiring-consumer-key-and-consumer-secret">Acquiring Consumer Key and Consumer Secret&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Log into your Salesforce account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the top right-hand side of the screen, click on the &lt;strong>cogwheel&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Setup&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the left-hand pane go to &lt;strong>Apps &amp;gt; App Manager&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the list of apps, find your &lt;strong>Connected App&lt;/strong> that you want to connect with Kianda and click on the &lt;strong>drop-down&lt;/strong> list on the right-hand side. Select &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under API (Enable OAuth Settings), click on &lt;strong>Manage Consumer Details&lt;/strong>. A &lt;strong>Verify Your Identity&lt;/strong> window opens.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter in the &lt;strong>Verification code&lt;/strong> that was sent to your email that you used to sign up to Salesforce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Verify&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once verified, your will be brought to a page where you can find the &lt;strong>Consumer Key&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Consumer Secret&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="configuring-salesforce-connected-app">Configuring Salesforce Connected App&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before starting going through the steps below you must ensure that you have a Connected App created in your Salesforce account, to learn how to do that go to &lt;a href="https://help.salesforce.com/s/articleView?id=sf.connected_app_create.htm&amp;amp;type=5">Create a Connected App&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Log into your Salesforce account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the top right-hand side of the screen, click on the &lt;strong>cogwheel&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Setup&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the left-hand pane go to &lt;strong>Apps &amp;gt; App Manager&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the list of apps, find your &lt;strong>Connected App&lt;/strong> that you want to connect with Kianda and click on the &lt;strong>drop-down&lt;/strong> list located on the right-hand side. Select &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From your Connected App screen, click on &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Scroll down to &lt;strong>API (Enable OAuth Settings)&lt;/strong>. Check the Enable OAuth Settings checkbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Callback URL&lt;/strong> text box enter &lt;code>https://app.kianda.com/index.html&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On a second line of the &lt;strong>Callback URL&lt;/strong> text box enter &lt;code>https://{company}.kianda.com/index.html&lt;/code> where &lt;code>company&lt;/code> is the name of your company&amp;rsquo;s subscription, for example &lt;code>https://green-itr.kianda.com/index.html&lt;/code>. The &lt;strong>Callback URL&lt;/strong> should look as follows when the company&amp;rsquo;s name is &lt;code>green-itr&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/salesforce-callback.jpg" alt="Callback textbox">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Selected OAuth Scopes&lt;/strong> section, move all of the scopes from &lt;strong>Available OAuth Scopes&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Selected OAuth Scopes&lt;/strong> window by selecting them and clicking &lt;strong>Add&lt;/strong>. Here you can add scopes that you want your Connected App to have access to from within Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From your Connected App screen, click on &lt;strong>Manage&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the manage connected app screen, click on &lt;strong>Edit Policies&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>OAuth Policies&lt;/strong> section, go to &lt;strong>Permitted Users&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>All users may self-authorize&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>IP Relaxation&lt;/strong> select the &lt;strong>Relax IP restrictions&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SharePoint service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SAP connector</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sap/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a &lt;strong>SAP&lt;/strong> datasource. SAP is an enterprise resource planning software which allows you centralises data between all areas of your business and manage them in one SAP system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Data in the SAP system are represented with schemas and tables. Each &lt;strong>schema&lt;/strong> represents an &lt;strong>area&lt;/strong> of your business and &lt;strong>tables&lt;/strong> represent &lt;strong>data&lt;/strong> within that business area. Using SAP as your datasource, you can perform Create, Read, Update and Delete (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations on &lt;strong>tables&lt;/strong> within your SAP system using the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">&lt;strong>Data rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> provided in the Kianda platform. When using the SAP connector, keep in mind that you can perform CRUD operations on data within a &lt;strong>tables&lt;/strong> of the system, but you &lt;strong>cannot&lt;/strong> perform CRUD operations on &lt;strong>tables themselves&lt;/strong>, this mean are unable to &lt;strong>create&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> tables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SAP connector also has the ability to use Business Application Programming Interface (&lt;strong>BAPI&lt;/strong>) functions through Kianda. This allows you to perform particular business tasks in your SAP system by calling BAPI functions using the Data rules provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the SAP connector when you want &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>modify&lt;/strong> data within a standard SAP or custom &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> in your SAP system. You can connect the SAP connector to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field as its datasource, meaning you can access information from a table and display the information that is stored in the table. Take a standard SAP table &lt;strong>MARA&lt;/strong> as an example, using this table you can display information on your Kianda forms using the data within the MARA table. You can also display information of your custom made tables within your SAP system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-getting-started">Before getting started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You need to create a Kianda Cloud Connect connection with your device which will be used in the settings when filling out the SAP connector settings. To learn how to create a connection with you device using Kianda Cloud Connect, visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>SAP&lt;/strong> from the list of datasources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>SAP system details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sap-details.jpg" alt="SAP Details page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Application server&lt;/strong> - enter in the IP address that your SAP system is run on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instance number&lt;/strong> - enter in the Instance number that you want to connect to from your SAP server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>System ID&lt;/strong> - enter in the ID of your SAP system. A system ID has three characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Client&lt;/strong> - enter in the Client your want to connect to from your SAP system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Username&lt;/strong> - enter a username used to connect to your SAP system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - enter in the password used to connect to your SAP system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAP BAPIs&lt;/strong> - enter in BAPI functions that you want access too when performing BAPI functionalities on your SAP system. Each BAPI must be on a separate line with no spaces, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sap-bapi.jpg" alt="SAP BAPIs">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAP Tables&lt;/strong> - enter in SAP tables you want to have access to when performing CRUD operations from your SAP system. Each table must be on a separate line with no spaces, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sap-tables.jpg" alt="SAP tables">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is disabled, the cloud connect is used to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between your &lt;strong>local device&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>. This option must be enabled to successfully establish a connection between a SAP system and Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> subscription.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - represents the current status of the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector were not fully completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>test failed&lt;/strong> - means that the details of the connector are incorrect and the connection has failed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong> - means that the connector has successfully connected and its ready to be used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added the SAP system details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>SAP system details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="sap-table-parameters">SAP Table parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use a &lt;strong>SAP&lt;/strong> datasource, unlike some of the other data connectors in Kianda, SAP does not have &lt;strong>default&lt;/strong> parameters. When you connect a SAP connector as your datasource, you can choose which &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>BAPI&lt;/strong> you want to use when performing CRUD operations. For example when connecting a SQL datasource to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field and selecting a table you want to use, the parameters will depend on what &lt;strong>data&lt;/strong> are present in the &lt;strong>tables&lt;/strong>. Take standard SAP Table &lt;strong>MARA&lt;/strong> as an example. We have an &lt;strong>Employee&lt;/strong> table which we select when connecting a datasource to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field, to learn how to a datasource to a list field go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sap-mara.jpg" alt="Connecting MARA table to list field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list of parameters displayed in the the &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field will match the columns that we have in the &lt;strong>Employee&lt;/strong> table, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sap-mara-list-field.jpg" alt="columns in a table">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sap-bapi-functions">SAP BAPI functions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to use &lt;strong>BAPI functions&lt;/strong> from your SAP system &lt;strong>effectively&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> within Kianda can be used. Data rules allow you to &lt;strong>send&lt;/strong> data as well as &lt;strong>receive&lt;/strong> it. For example if your BAPI function needs data when calling it, you can use any of the Data rules for example &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/create-item/">Create item rule&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> to send data using the &lt;strong>input mapping&lt;/strong> section or when receiving data you can use the &lt;strong>on success mapping&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a BAPI function which retrieves a list from your SAP system as an example. You can use the on success mapping to store the list in a Kianda field. If for example this BAPI function takes an argument where you want to specify how many items from the list it retrieves, you can input that information in to the input mapping section of the data rules. To learn more about on success mapping go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/success-error-mapping/#on-success-mapping">On Success Mapping&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SAP system connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SharePoint connector</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sharepoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sharepoint/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A SharePoint data connector allows you to use SharePoint data sources as part of your Kianda forms or dashboards. This means that as your processes are running they will use the information at the data source or depending on the process, update information at a data source location.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> from the list of datasources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>SharePoint details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sharepoint-connector.jpg" alt="Sharepoint datasources">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - the name of the data source, for example SharePoint HR&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Site URL&lt;/strong> - this is the link to your SharePoint data&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint version&lt;/strong> - choose from a) SharePoint Online (also known as SharePoint in Microsoft 365) b) SharePoint 2016 or c) SharePoint 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Site for example a particular SharePoint website or b) Site Collection, a collection of SharePoint sites&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authentication mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) SharePoint Online Authorisation and b) System User Credentials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) SharePoint Online Authorisation then click on &lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/authorize.png" alt="Authorize button"> in this instance you will need SharePoint administration rights&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) System User Credentials then fill out your username and password. In this instance you do not need SharePoint administration rights.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added SharePoint details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>SharePoint details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button">to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the datasource management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="sharepoint-parameters">SharePoint parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use a SharePoint datasource, there are &lt;strong>default parameters&lt;/strong> invoked from SharePoint. For example when you create a &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> in a Kianda form using a SharePoint datasource, these SharePoint parameters will appear in &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field in the &lt;strong>Edit list dialog box&lt;/strong>, see &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> for example in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-list-params.jpg" alt="SharePoint parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The SharePoint parameters that appear in those three dropdown fields are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Created&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Created By&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified By&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Version&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Server Relative URL&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Item Child Count&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Folder Child Count&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Label setting&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Retention label&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Retention label Applied&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Label applied by&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>App created By&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>App modified By&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Compliance Asset ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Telephone Code&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All custom columns in the datasource will also appear at the &lt;strong>bottom&lt;/strong> of this list. For example in a SharePoint list, a column named &lt;strong>Location&lt;/strong> will also be listed in the Display, Value and Sort by fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sharepoint-list-field.jpg" alt="SharePoint list example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This customised name &amp;lsquo;Location&amp;rsquo; appears in the dropdown list, for example the &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong> for the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/location-sharepoint-field.jpg" alt="Customised column name example in SharePoint">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SharePoint service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To see how SharePoint parameters are used in a form, for example with a &lt;strong>list&lt;/strong> field, go to &lt;a href="//docs/platform/controls/input/list/#how-to-get-started">List control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SOAP</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/soap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/soap/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a connector to Simple Object Access Protocol (SOAP) messaging services. Kianda has the ability to execute a command within the service whatever the function may be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You will want to create a SOAP Service datasource when you want Kianda to have access to your SOAP Service operations and execute them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A SOAP Service data connector can be configured by users with the role &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. These users can access the datasource management function, found under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/open-data-sources.jpg" alt="Opening data sources from Administration">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the main view you will see any existing data sources that have been created. From this view, you can click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a data source to see details or &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> a data source by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin/trash button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and a range of data source connectors will appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-range.jpg" alt="Data source list">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>SOAP Service&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out the details in the &lt;strong>SOAP Service details&lt;/strong> page:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/soap-detail.jpg" alt="SOAP service detais">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: The &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of the datasource will be &lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> until it has been fully configured. When set up it will be &lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - this is the name of the data source. Use an appropriate name, as this will be used within your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Service URL&lt;/strong> - this will be the URL of the service.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Service WSDL URL&lt;/strong> - this will be the URL of the service including the Web Services Description Language (WSDL). WSDL describes the structure, contents and limitations of the elements of XML passed between the web service and client.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authentication Mode&lt;/strong> - there are three options available:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Anonymous&lt;/strong> - the message initiator is anonymous and the responder is authenticated, no credentials needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Basic&lt;/strong> - provides basic authentication and requires credentials to be entered.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Windows&lt;/strong> - provides authentication using Windows login and requires credentials to be entered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/windows-authentication.jpg" alt="Windows authentication">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added SOAP service details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>SOAP service details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button">to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the datasource management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SOAP Service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SQL Server connector</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sql-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sql-server/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a Structured Query Language &lt;strong>(SQL) Server&lt;/strong> datasource. Using the SQL server as your datasource, you can perform any Create, Read, Update and Delete (&lt;strong>CRUD&lt;/strong>) operations using the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> rules provided in the Kianda platform, to learn more about data rules go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/">Data rules&lt;/a>. Using the SQL server connector, you have access to all tables within your database from your server, keep in mind that you can perform CRUD operations on data within a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> of the database, but you &lt;strong>cannot&lt;/strong> create or delete &lt;strong>tables themselves&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can use the SQL Server connector when you want &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>modify&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>retrieve&lt;/strong> data within a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> in your SQL server. When connecting a SQL server datasource to a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List field&lt;/a>, you can only connect and display information from a &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong>, not the information of the &lt;strong>server&lt;/strong> itself. For example if your SQL server contains &lt;strong>tables&lt;/strong> such as &lt;strong>Employees&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Purchases&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Standing Orders&lt;/strong>, you will be able to connect the list field to &lt;strong>only one&lt;/strong> of those tables giving you CRUD access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-getting-started">Before getting started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When establishing a connection using the SQL data connector, you are creating a connection with a &lt;strong>Database&lt;/strong> from a server, not the &lt;strong>server&lt;/strong> itself. Before continuing make sure that your SQL server has a &lt;strong>database&lt;/strong> you can connect to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to successfully establish this connection with your server, a user is needed to access the server by logging in. This user that you use to connect to the server must be a &lt;strong>sysadmin&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Kianda home page, click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and choose &lt;strong>SQL Server&lt;/strong> from the list of datasources provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>SQL Server details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sql-server-details.jpg" alt="SQL Server details page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - type in a name for your SQL server connector. This is used to distinguish between different data connectors on your platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Server&lt;/strong> - the name of the server you want to access or the IP address where the server is hosted. When you are running a local server on your machine you can use &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> as the server name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Database&lt;/strong> - the name of the database from your server that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trusted connection&lt;/strong> - enable windows trusted connection. Only available when using with Kianda cloud connector, enabling this will automatically enable the &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> option. this option will use the connector service credentials to connect to the destination datasource. Having this option enabled will automatically hide the &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> - username used to log into the server. Note that in order to log into a server with a username and password, the user must be a &lt;strong>system admin&lt;/strong> for the connection to be successful.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password&lt;/strong> - password used to log into the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - by default this option is disabled, the cloud connect is used to &lt;strong>create a connection&lt;/strong> between a &lt;strong>locally run SQL server&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> itself. To learn more about &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> and how to create a connection between Kianda and your PC, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>. Check this option if you want to connect to a server that is running on your local machine. When &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> is enabled, a &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> option appears.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> - displays all available connector PC&amp;rsquo;s that have a &lt;strong>connection established&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> subscription. This option is used to select the PC &lt;strong>connection&lt;/strong> that &lt;strong>runs&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>local SQL server&lt;/strong> that you want to connect to.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added the SQL server details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>SQL Server details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the data source management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="connecting-to-a-local-server">Connecting to a local server&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here we will go step by step on how to create a connection between your locally run SQL Server and your Kianda subscription. Follow the steps below to create this connection:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sql-server-example.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Connect to a SQL server using &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> as the name of the server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the SQL details page by following steps 1 and 2 from &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sql-server/#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose a Display name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Server&lt;/strong> text box type in &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Database&lt;/strong> text box type in the name of your database you want to connect from your server. For this example we will connect to a &lt;strong>GreenITR&lt;/strong> database from our server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable the &lt;strong>Trusted connection&lt;/strong> checkbox.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable the &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> checkbox.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> radio checklist, select the PC that you are running the local server on, For this example we are using &lt;strong>PC31&lt;/strong>. To establish a connection between your Kianda subscription and your PC go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/kianda-cloud-connect/">Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A notification &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong> shows up. Now you are ready to use the SQL connector that is run on your local machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="sql-server-parameters">SQL Server parameters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you use a &lt;strong>SQL Server&lt;/strong> datasource, unlike some of the other data connectors in Kianda, SQL Server does not have &lt;strong>default&lt;/strong> parameters. When you connect a SQL server as your datasource, you can choose which &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong> you want to use when performing CRUD operations. For example when connecting a SQL datasource to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field and selecting a table you want to use, the parameters will depend on what &lt;strong>columns&lt;/strong> are present in the &lt;strong>table&lt;/strong>. Take GreenITR database from the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sql-server/#connecting-to-a-local-server">Connecting to a local server&lt;/a> example. We have an &lt;strong>Employee&lt;/strong> table which we select when connecting a datasource to a &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong> field, to learn how to a datasource to a list field go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sql-server-employee.jpg" alt="Connecting employee table to list field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list of parameters displayed in the the &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> field will match the columns that we have in the &lt;strong>Employee&lt;/strong> table, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sql-server-columns.jpg" alt="columns in a table">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next-idea-iconimages18png">What’s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>SQL Server connector&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. To find out more about how to design processes go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: REST Web Service</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/rest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/rest/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the datasources available in Kianda is a connector to a &lt;strong>REST API&lt;/strong>. Kianda has the ability to perform &lt;strong>GET, POST, PUT&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>DELETE&lt;/strong> operations if they are supported by the webservice. The REST API datasource can support multiple REST methods, all of which can be called independently. Data from the webservice can be pulled into your Kianda workspace and manipulated, or data from Kianda can be pushed to the webservice to be used by other systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can create a REST API datasource when you want your Kianda processes and forms to have access to a REST API.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A REST API data connector can be configured by users with the role &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. These users can access the datasource management function, found under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the left-hand side menu, go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the main view you will see any existing data sources that have been created. From this view, you can click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a data source to see details or &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> a data source by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin/trash button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-main-view.jpg" alt="Data sources main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new data source, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> in the main view. A range of data source connectors will appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-range.jpg" alt="Data source list">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a REST Service data source click on &lt;strong>REST Service&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>REST Service details&lt;/strong> screen opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-service-details.jpg" alt="REST Service details">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill in the first set of fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name –&lt;/strong> This is the name of the data source. Use an appropriate name, as this will be used within your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Rest server base URL –&lt;/strong> This is the base URL of the REST API. Ensure there are no trailing characters, for example &lt;a href="https://api.mywebsite.com">https://api.mywebsite.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable Certificate Authentication –&lt;/strong> By default this option is set to &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. By Selecting &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> this will display two new fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Certificate (.pfx) –&lt;/strong> This is a file field which you can use to upload your authentication certificate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Certificate password –&lt;/strong> Enter the password of the certificate here so the Kianda platform will be able to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-cert-authentication.jpg" alt="Enable Certificate Authentication">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under the Service details section, is a the &lt;strong>REST Methods&lt;/strong> section. If there are any existing methods created, for example to find and retrieve particular information using HTTP GET, the method will be listed here. Go to &lt;a href="#rest-methods">REST Methods&lt;/a> to find out more about how to add a method. To find out more about Kianda REST APIs, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/apis/">APIs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under the REST Methods on the REST Service details page, there is a check box to &lt;strong>Use Kianda Cloud Connect?&lt;/strong> If you check this checkbox it gives you an option to Download Kianda Cloud Connect. Click on &lt;strong>Download Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> to download a zip file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-cloud-connect.jpg" alt="Kianda Cloud Connect">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added REST Service details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>REST Service details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connection-test-succeeded.jpg" alt="Connection test succeeded message">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the event of an error, you will receive a message that relates to the error, for example a null or incorrect URL as shown in the example below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-connection-error.jpg" alt="REST test connection error">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button">to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here is an example of a data connector for a REST Service called &amp;lsquo;Cat facts&amp;rsquo;. We will use this example to create a &lt;a href="#rest-methods">REST method&lt;/a>, see section below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-service-example-catfacts.jpg" alt="REST Service example">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rest-methods">REST Methods&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A list of current REST Methods that have been created in Kianda will appear, listed by &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Path&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>HTTP Method&lt;/strong>, where:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - is the name of the method, for example to get a list of course attendees, which could be called &amp;lsquo;Course Attendees&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Path&lt;/strong> - is the address that allows you to access the API, also called &lt;strong>endpoints&lt;/strong>, for example &lt;strong>/instances&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>/processes&lt;/strong> are endpoints for Kianda REST APIs that allow you to perform methods on process instances and process designs respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>HTTP Method&lt;/strong> - is the type of operation that can be performed on the data, namely &lt;strong>POST&lt;/strong> (create), &lt;strong>GET&lt;/strong> (read). &lt;strong>PUT&lt;/strong> (update). &lt;strong>PATCH&lt;/strong> (partial update) and &lt;strong>DELETE&lt;/strong> (delete).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These details are shown in the example below, a data connector called &amp;lsquo;REST Service for HR&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-method-example.jpg" alt="Existing REST Methods">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can edit details of the existing REST Methods by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit/Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-method.jpg" alt="Edit REST Methods"> or delete a method by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/delete-method.jpg" alt="Delete REST Method">.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-add-a-new-rest-method">How to add a new REST Method&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>+Add REST Method&lt;/strong> button. The &lt;strong>REST Method editor&lt;/strong> dialog box appears.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-method-editor.jpg" alt="REST Method editor">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out the fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display Name –&lt;/strong> this is the name you want to attribute to the REST Method.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>HTTP Method –&lt;/strong> this is the HTTP Method of the REST Method.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Url Path –&lt;/strong> this is the rest of the URL that will be concatenated with the &lt;strong>Rest server base URL&lt;/strong>. For example /rest/GetUserDetails.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Request headers –&lt;/strong> Request headers can be manually added here that need to be sent as part of the request, for example, Authorization. These values can be hard coded or passed into the &lt;strong>Request header&lt;/strong> from the &lt;strong>process.&lt;/strong> Click on &lt;strong>Add header&lt;/strong> to add a request header.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Request body –&lt;/strong> This section is for the &lt;strong>Request body&lt;/strong> that will be used during the request. These values can be hard coded or passed into the &lt;strong>Request body&lt;/strong> from the &lt;strong>process.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Content type –&lt;/strong> Here you can define the &lt;strong>Content type&lt;/strong> of the body. The options are &lt;strong>JSON&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Form Data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Response headers –&lt;/strong> Here you can define any response headers you wish to capture in the response that you want to use in Kianda. Click on &lt;strong>Add header&lt;/strong> to add a response header.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Response body –&lt;/strong> Here you can define the response body that the request will receive. Include or remove fields as needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save your changes, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="#example-of-rest-method-use-in-kianda">Example of REST Method use in Kianda&lt;/a> below which can be used as a service with the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="example-of-rest-method-use-in-kianda">Example of REST Method use in Kianda&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Take an example of &lt;a href="https://catfact.ninja/fact">https://catfact.ninja/fact&lt;/a> a well-known API that provides an endpoint to retrieve random facts about cats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a simple &lt;strong>GET&lt;/strong> method is used to retrieve facts using an API client, then parameters are returned showing the &amp;lsquo;fact&amp;rsquo; and the &amp;rsquo;length&amp;rsquo; of the fact as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/catfact-ninja-send.jpg" alt="Catninja GET example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowing what parameters are available we can use the steps in &lt;a href="#how-to-add-a-new-rest-method">How to add a new REST Method&lt;/a>,:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>+Add REST Method&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-rest-method.jpg" alt="Add REST Method"> from the &lt;strong>REST Service details&lt;/strong> page, and add in details using the &lt;strong>REST Method editor&lt;/strong> where:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display Name&lt;/strong> - this is the name of your method that will be called upon in a process, for example &amp;lsquo;Cat fact&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>HTTP Method&lt;/strong> - &lt;strong>GET&lt;/strong> is used to retrieve values&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Url Path&lt;/strong> - the path that is attached to the base URL, for example &lt;strong>/fact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add Header&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-header.jpg" alt="Add Header button"> to add request headers, for example for authentication.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Request body&lt;/strong> - this is the part of the request that is sent to a function where a function processes the request and sends back the &lt;strong>Response body&lt;/strong>. For our &amp;lsquo;catfact ninja&amp;rsquo; example we will use the parameters &amp;lsquo;fact&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;length&amp;rsquo; for &lt;strong>mapping values to form fields&lt;/strong> in Kianda processes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/catfact-ninja-response-body.jpg" alt="Catfact ninja response body">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save the details and then click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-button.jpg" alt="Save button"> in the &lt;strong>REST Service details&lt;/strong> screen to save the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The method will appear under &lt;strong>REST Methods&lt;/strong> in the details screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/rest-method-get-catfact.jpg" alt="REST Method example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next section shows how data at the data source can be used in a Kianda process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="using-a-rest-method-in-a-kianda-process">Using a REST Method in a Kianda process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To see how &amp;lsquo;catfacts&amp;rsquo; are mapped into Kianda processes, create a new process, add fields and a rule that uses the REST Method created above.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process by going to the left-hand side menu &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new button"> and fill out details for the process, such as a &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kianda Designer opens and in the first form, &lt;strong>form1&lt;/strong>, add in a new text box by going to the left-hand pane and click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong>. This field will hold the value of the &amp;lsquo;fact&amp;rsquo; from catfacts. To read more about Input controls go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/">Input controls&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add a button to initiate the call from catfacts by going to the left-hand pane &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Actions&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Button&lt;/strong>. Give the button a &lt;strong>title&lt;/strong> for example &amp;lsquo;Get Cat Fact&amp;rsquo;, and choose &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>Show in form body&lt;/strong> so the button appears at the bottom of the form. To read more about Action controls go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/">Actions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/get-cat-fact-button.jpg" alt="Get cat fact button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To dynamically populate the textbox with a fact, we need a rule. Click on &amp;lsquo;Get cat fact&amp;rsquo; button to add a rule. Then go to &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Find items&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Give the rule a title, and under &lt;strong>Action&lt;/strong>, click on &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong> to select the data source created using the steps in &lt;a href="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>. Select the method &amp;lsquo;Cat fact&amp;rsquo; created using the steps above in &lt;a href="#example-of-rest-method-use-in-kianda">Example of REST Method use in Kianda&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/select-datasource-catfacts.jpg" alt="Selecting datasource example catfact">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to close the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you want to add headers to the request use the &lt;strong>Input mapping&lt;/strong> for example requests headers for authentication, otherwise click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button to delete the input mapping fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Results mapping&lt;/strong> select the textbox from your form for the &lt;strong>Form field&lt;/strong> and under &lt;strong>Data source field or text&lt;/strong> navigate to &amp;lsquo;fact&amp;rsquo; from the &lt;strong>responseBody&lt;/strong> as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/results-mapping-example.jpg" alt="Results mapping example for &amp;amp;lsquo;facts&amp;amp;rsquo;">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Error mapping if desired. Click on the links to read more about &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/success-error-mapping/">Error mapping&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/find-items/">Find items rule&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Save the process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-button.jpg" alt="Save button"> and preview the process by clicking on &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview button">. In the previewed instance, click on the &amp;lsquo;Get Cat Fact&amp;rsquo; button to populate the textbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your &lt;strong>REST Service&lt;/strong> is now set up and ready to be used in your &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. Check out the following article on how to implement a &lt;strong>REST Service&lt;/strong> in order to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/rest/rest-access-token/">refresh an Access token&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about APIs, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/apis/">APIs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about processes and forms, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Application designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>