<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – B2B Portals</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/</link><description>Recent content in B2B Portals on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Shared process</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-process/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Shared Process&lt;/strong> is a &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> which you create within your own subscription with the intention to share with your B2B Portal. This &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong>, as with all &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>, can be used to review data, create new instances, update or delete instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within a shared process, you can also create a &lt;strong>Shared Dashboard&lt;/strong> which is a dashboard created within your own subscription with the intention to share with your B2B Portal. This &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong>, as with all dashboards, can be used to review data, access &lt;strong>Shared Processes&lt;/strong> by creating new instances, updating or deleting instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using the &lt;strong>Shared Process&lt;/strong> feature will allow users within the &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong> to have access to a process you have created. By sharing this &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> you will give your &lt;strong>partner&lt;/strong> the opportunity to work on the process by updating, creating and deleting instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It terms of dashboards, it is necessary to share your &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> with your &lt;strong>B2B&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Portal&lt;/strong> when sharing &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>widgets&lt;/strong> with your Client. Before you can share a &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> you must first create one. This &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> can be one that you have already created, however, we recommend creating a unique dashboard that will be used specifically for sharing with B2B Portals. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/">Dashboards&lt;/a> to learn more about how to create dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following sections will step through how to share a process (steps 1-3) and share a dashboard (step 4) and how to conclude and update partners (steps 5-6).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Log into your subscription and navigate to the &lt;strong>Invite Partner&lt;/strong> section located within &lt;strong>Administration.&lt;/strong> Your role needs to be &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Manage partner&lt;/strong> to view &lt;strong>Invite Partner&lt;/strong>. Using one of these roles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to &lt;strong>Invite Partner&lt;/strong> within the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-function.jpg" alt="Invite partner function">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Shared processes&lt;/strong> section, click on the &lt;strong>Share a process&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/share-a-process.jpg" alt="Share a process button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Create a Shared Process&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit Shared Process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Populate the fields as desired:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - provide a title for the shared process&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructions for partner&lt;/strong> - provide instructions for the selected partner&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>plus symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-process.jpg" alt="Add shared process"> to add a selected process design to share. Then click on the dropdown list to search for a process to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add the selected shared process. To change the selected shared process properties by clicking on the &lt;strong>Cog/Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> or delete the selected shared process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-selected-prop.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the **Cog/Settings **button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> a &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> dialog box appears, as shown above, for example Training Request properties. You can check radio buttons for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner to create a new process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to create new process instances from the chosen shared process design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A field &lt;strong>Partner user group allowed to create new instances&lt;/strong> appears, where you can define the group(s) in the partner organisation, that can create these new process instances. This is the first level of security for processes and dashboards. If you leave the field blank, then anyone in the partner organisation can create process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner delete a process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to delete new process instances from the chosen shared process design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Partner process form visibility mode - choose from &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong>, then the invited partner(s) can view only assigned form versus all forms, if &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong> is chosen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> then a pop-up appears to &lt;strong>Confirm removal&lt;/strong>, choose from &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-removal.jpg" alt="Confirm removal of selected shared process">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add further selected processes to share.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Add partner group&lt;/strong> button to add one or more partner groups. Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete partner groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are a set of dashboard parameters under the field &lt;strong>Add partner group&lt;/strong>. These are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Dashboard template&lt;/strong> click on the dropdown list to select an existing dashboards to share with the selected processes. If you choose to share a dashboard then you can select parameters:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard name in partner&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Use your company name &amp;lsquo;Name of your organisation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Same as selected dashboard&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make welcome page&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then the selected dashboard becomes the welcome page for the partner if no other welcome page is configured.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard security&lt;/strong> - choose from created partner groups within this field to ensure that &lt;strong>only users&lt;/strong> in these partner groups can access the dashboard. This is the method to set security on the dashboard specifically.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have completed configuring or modifying the &lt;strong>Shared Process&lt;/strong> you will need to send the shared process to your partner. To do this press the &lt;strong>Send Update&lt;/strong> button which appears in the main view of the &lt;strong>Shared processes&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/send-update-partner.jpg" alt="Send Update">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you have successfully creating a shared process and dashboard, these will be available in the B2B Portal for partners, for example when your partner users log into the B2B Portal they will be able to see the newly shared dashboard. From here they will be able to see the widgets within the dashboard and interact with the Processes. Go to the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/secure-data-access/">Secure Data Access&lt;/a> to read more about security in shared processes and data sources.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Partner profile</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/partner-profile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/partner-profile/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Within the &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong> your client’s administrator will be able to create as many &lt;strong>Partner Profiles&lt;/strong> (&lt;strong>users&lt;/strong>) as they wish. By creating these &lt;strong>users&lt;/strong>, they will have the ability to access the &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong> and interact with the &lt;strong>Dashboards&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Processes&lt;/strong> shared with them. For more information on how &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong> users access shared data go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/data-access/">Data access&lt;/a>, as well as &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-dashboard/">Shared dashboards&lt;/a> for information on dashboards, and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-process/">Shared process&lt;/a> for information on processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your client will need to add &lt;strong>Partner Profiles&lt;/strong> in order for their employees to have access to the &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong>. At this point your subscription will need to have been created and Administrators created. If this has not happened yet, please get in touch with your Account Manager or &lt;a href="mailto:support@kianda.com">Kianda Support&lt;/a> to begin the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to begin a user with an &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> role or &lt;strong>Manage partner&lt;/strong> role will need to log into your subscription. Using one of these roles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to &lt;strong>Invite Partner&lt;/strong> within the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Within this page click on the &lt;strong>Invite Partner&lt;/strong> Button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> dialog box populate the fields with the details of the person you want to share your &lt;strong>Processes&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Dashboards&lt;/strong> with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-dialog.jpg" alt="Invite partner dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fields in this box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Partner organisation&lt;/strong> - provide the name of the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact first name&lt;/strong> - provide the first name of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact last name&lt;/strong> - provide the surname of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact email&lt;/strong> - provide the email of a contact&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Shared process selection&lt;/strong> - in the dropdown list choose a shared process created using the steps listed in &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>More fields&lt;/strong> to see more fields these include: &lt;strong>Partner country&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Partner city&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Partner logo&lt;/strong> which you can add by clicking on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> and browsing your PC or network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage. Clicking on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> will save the partner and will result in an invitation being sent to their email address, similar to the one below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-email.jpg" alt="Invite partner email example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>As a partner click on the &lt;strong>Accept&lt;/strong> button. Then you are linked to a greeting page asking you to sign up to Kianda if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a login. Click on the &lt;strong>Sign up&lt;/strong> button if you don’t have a subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-greenitr.jpg" alt="Accept invite example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="accepting-a-partner-invite-without-a-subscription">Accepting a partner invite without a subscription&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>If you do have a subscription please continue to the section detailing what to do after when &lt;strong>login&lt;/strong> is clicked &lt;a href="#accepting-a-partner-invite-with-a-subscription">Accepting a partner invite with a subscription&lt;/a>, otherwise create a subscription, by entering your &lt;strong>Firstname&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Lastname&lt;/strong>, your &lt;strong>email&lt;/strong>, a &lt;strong>password&lt;/strong> and a &lt;strong>phone number&lt;/strong>. Click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> when you are ready to continue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sign-in-partner.jpg" alt="Signin to Kianda as an invited partner example">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>In the next page configure the name of the subscription for the &lt;strong>B2B Portal.&lt;/strong> Enter your &lt;strong>Company name&lt;/strong>, an &lt;strong>Identity&lt;/strong> that will form the beginning of your URL, the &lt;strong>Company Size&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Industry&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Address&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Country&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>City&lt;/strong>. Click &lt;strong>Start Trial&lt;/strong> when ready to proceed. This will create and automatically log you into your subscription.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-partner-signup.jpg" alt="Signin to Kianda as an invited partner example">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Return back to the email you received. Click on the &lt;strong>Accept Invite&lt;/strong> button again. Now that your subscription is created and you are logged in the &lt;strong>invite&lt;/strong> will be changed and will instead ask you to &lt;strong>Accept Invite&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/accept-invite-2.jpg" alt="Accept invite as a partner example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Accept Invite&lt;/strong> button. You will be redirected to the Home page of the Subscription. You will now see the contents of the &lt;strong>Shared Process&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/see-shared-dashboard.jpg" alt="Shared process example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="accepting-a-partner-invite-with-a-subscription">Accepting a partner invite with a subscription&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you &lt;strong>already have a subscription&lt;/strong> you can choose to &lt;strong>Login&lt;/strong> instead of Signing up. By logging in you can log into your subscription and you will be given the option to accept the invite. Please note that you will need to be an &lt;strong>administrator&lt;/strong> in your portal in order to accept the invite.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Accept Invite&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-greenitr.jpg" alt="Accept invite example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be redirected to the Home page of the Subscription. You will now see the contents of the &lt;strong>Shared Process&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Within your subscription you will be able to see if an invited partner has accepted their &lt;strong>invitation&lt;/strong> based on the &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Pending&lt;/strong> means they have not accepted the &lt;strong>invite&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>active&lt;/strong> means they have accepted the &lt;strong>invite&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/pending-invites.jpg" alt="Invite partner status">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once an invite is accepted, your client’s/invited partner&amp;rsquo;s employees can now access the B2B Portal and interact with the Dashboards and Processes that have been shared with them. For more information on how &lt;strong>B2B Portal&lt;/strong> users access shared data go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/data-access/">Data access&lt;/a>, as well as &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-dashboard/">Shared dashboards&lt;/a> for information on dashboards, and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/shared-process/">Shared process&lt;/a> for information on processes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Secure Data Access</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/data-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/b2b-portals/data-access/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access to the B2B Portal is controlled through standard user and group creation, dashboard security and through how the Shared Processes and Dashboards are defined.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>B2B Portals are a means of connecting your clients to your Kianda subscription through their own subscription. This provides a means of allowing your clients to interface with processes you have already created, be it through updating existing processes, deleting processes or creating processes. Access to the B2B Portal can be controlled by your own administrator and each B2B portal can have multiple users for your clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To share data with B2B portal users, there are a number of steps involved starting with:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a) &lt;a href="create-users-and-groups-for-the-B2B-portal">Creating users and groups&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b) &lt;a href="create-dashboards-to-share">Create dashboards to share&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c) &lt;a href="create-shared-processes-and-attach-dashboards-to-share">Create shared processes and attach dashboards to share&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These steps are covered within the headings below. In addition you can manage &lt;a href="data-access-at-a-datasource-level">data access at a datasource level&lt;/a>, click on the link to see more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="create-users-and-groups-for-the-b2b-portal">Create users and groups for the B2B portal&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To begin create &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> for the B2B portal. If you are an &lt;strong>administrator,&lt;/strong> navigate to the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> section in the left-hand side menu and click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Within this page you will be able to view all existing &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> in the portal. In the left-hand side, under &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> you can see user names, emails, role and if they are active or not. All existing &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> can be seen in the right-hand side of the screen. Here you can see group names and the number of members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-main-view.jpg" alt="Users main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For full details on how to create, edit and delete users and groups got to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/">Users&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="create-dashboards-to-share">Create dashboards to share&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Within your own portal you may then wish to create &lt;strong>Dashboards&lt;/strong> to share. Dashboards provide a convenient way to gain insights into how your business processes are performing. They offer easy reporting, permissions management, quick build, condition-based filtering amongst other features. For details on how to get started with dashboards go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/platform/pages/">Dashboards&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="create-shared-processes-and-attach-dashboards-to-share">Create shared processes and attach dashboards to share&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When the dashboard that you want to share within your &lt;strong>B2B portal&lt;/strong> has been created, then you can control access by two means: a) Using the &lt;strong>Shared Processes&lt;/strong> feature within &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> within &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> and b) within the B2B portal itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To implement a) go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> and within the &lt;strong>Shared processes&lt;/strong> section, click on &lt;strong>Share a process&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Type in a &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Instructions for partner&lt;/strong>, click on the &lt;strong>plus symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-process.jpg" alt="Add shared process"> to add a selected process design to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then click on the dropdown list to search for a process to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add the selected shared process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Add partner group&lt;/strong> button to add a group from step 3 and click on &lt;strong>Dashboard template&lt;/strong> to add the desired Dashboard (from step 4) to share. Security can be set on this dashboard so that only a defined group can see the dashboard - click on the field under &lt;strong>Dashboard security&lt;/strong> to add in a named &amp;lsquo;partner group&amp;rsquo; to enable access to this group only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit Shared Process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add as many shared dashboards and partner groups as needed using the previous instructions. In addition the level of access for each shared process can be controlled through system settings. Click on the on the &lt;strong>tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to change the shared processes details, and then click on the &lt;strong>Cog/Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> and edit the details within the &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> dialog box, for example as shown for a Training Request process below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-selected-prop.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Within the &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> dialog box you can check radio buttons for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Allow partner to create a new process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to create new process instances from the chosen shared process design. A field &lt;strong>Partner user group allowed to create new instances&lt;/strong> appears, where you can define the group(s) in the partner organisation, that can create these new process instances. If you leave the field blank, then anyone in the partner organisation can create process instances.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Allow partner delete a process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to delete new process instances from the chosen shared process design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner user group allowed to create new instances&lt;/strong>- choose from the &lt;strong>Partner user groups&lt;/strong> that you created previously. By selecting a group here this dictates who can enter the process. Thus, defining a sub set of your B2B Portal users which can interact with that specific process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner process form visibility mode&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong>, then the invited partner(s) can view only assigned form versus all forms, if &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong> is chosen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="data-access-at-a-datasource-level">Data access at a datasource level&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When a &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> is shared within the B2B portal, you may choose to include one or more of your datasources. You may not wish to share all records from the datasource within the B2B portal, so you can limit access within the datasource itself. B2B Security can be enabled with the following datasources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Directory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Docusign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dropbox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FTP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Global Payments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MySQL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Office 365&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oracle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PowerShell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>REST Service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salesforce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SAP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SOAP Service&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the Datasource management main view, click on a data source that has already been created with a status of &lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong>, by clicking on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the data source, or create a new Data source by clicking on &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong>, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/">Data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-management.jpg" alt="Datasource management view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Data source details&lt;/strong> screen, click on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/security-button.jpg" alt="Security button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Security settings&lt;/strong> dialog box, complete the fields as shown on screen, starting with &lt;strong>Connection administrators&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/security-settings.jpg" alt="Security settings dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Connection administrators&lt;/strong> - only users or groups listed here are allowed to modify the connection settings. Click on the dropdown list to choose &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and/or &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong>. If you leave the field blank, all &lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> and those users with the &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong> role can edit the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Complete the field for &lt;strong>Connection users&lt;/strong>. Only users or groups listed here are allowed to query data using this connection. Click on the dropdown list to choose &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and/or &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong>. If you leave the field blank, any user can query data within the datasource.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Check/Uncheck &lt;strong>Enable B2B&lt;/strong>. If you check the checkbox, this allows B2B external users to query the connection. The &lt;strong>Enable partner default query parameters&lt;/strong> checkbox appears.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Check/Uncheck &lt;strong>Enable partner default query parameters&lt;/strong>. If you check the checkbox, you can define default query parameters that are applied to any partner originated query. Parameters defined here take precedence over any design time queries. Click on &lt;strong>Add mapping&lt;/strong> to choose a query type and table/operation as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Query type&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Create, Read, Update, Delete&lt;/strong> (CRUD). These CRUD operations allow you to create, read, update and delete records within your datasource.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Table/Operation&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Select a table&lt;/strong> to select a resource within the data connector. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you are finished editing, or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Query parameters&lt;/strong> - when a datasource resource is chosen, for example a SharePoint list called &amp;lsquo;Countries&amp;rsquo; below, then you will have an option to set conditions for filtering data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/query-parameters-security.jpg" alt="Query parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Filter conditions&lt;/strong> to open an &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box and from there click on &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you choose to set conditions using the steps above, then in the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box, you can set conditions based on data source parameters, operators and form fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The parameter on the left comes from the &lt;strong>data source&lt;/strong>, for example for SharePoint, there are 18 possible values listed in &lt;a href="#sharepoint-parameters/docs/platform/connectors/sharepoint/">SharePoint parameters&lt;/a>. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Data sources&lt;/a> for information about other data connectors.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-conditions.jpg" alt="Edit conditions dialog box in Security settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Within this dialog box you can also use different operators, for example &lt;strong>Equals&lt;/strong> as shown above. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a> for more details on using conditions in Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The right-most field relates to the B2B Portal and B2B User. There are standard options listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Main Contact Name –&lt;/strong> the first name and last name of the Partner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Main Contact Email –&lt;/strong> the email of the Partner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner Company Name –&lt;/strong> the Partner organisation of the Partner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner Current User Name –&lt;/strong> the user within the B2B Portal that is accessing the datasource&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner Current User Email –&lt;/strong> the user&amp;rsquo;s email within the B2B Portal that is accessing the datasource&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/b2b-parameters.jpg" alt="B2B form parameters">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added conditions click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the security settings dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about User and group management, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/">Users&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about Dashboards, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/">Dashboards&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about Conditions, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read more about data source parameters, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Connectors&lt;/a> and from there navigate to the different predefined data connectors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>