<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda low-code platform for business process automation – Task Automation with Kianda</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Task Automation with Kianda on Kianda low-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/platform/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Platform: Scheduled tasks</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/automation/scheduledtasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/platform/automation/scheduledtasks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane, or on the top right toolbar depending on the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/#general-settings">chosen orientation&lt;/a>, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Scheduled tasks function allows you to schedule a task, that could be a process or a rule for example to send reminder emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To use the Scheduled tasks function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view scheduled tasks via this function in the &lt;strong>Task automation&lt;/strong> main tasks view. The current tasks listed is a subset of all tasks, see Step 4 below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-view.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this main view you can see:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> of the task&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>Schedule&lt;/strong> for example weekly or monthly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the task was &lt;strong>last run&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the task will &lt;strong>next run&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of the task such as &amp;lsquo;Complete&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the name of the associated &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> and process &lt;strong>instance&lt;/strong> where relevant, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>who&lt;/strong> is the administrator of the task/who has created the task.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The buttons beside each task are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trigger task manually&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trigger-task-manually.jpg" alt="Trigger task manually"> - clicking on this button instantly creates a new process instance/record by executing the task or process. This process instance can be viewed in a list widget in a dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show task history&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/show-task-history.jpg" alt="Show task history"> - when you click on this button, a dialog box opens showing a list of all the past executions of the task, listed by date and time and status, for example if there was an error or if the task completed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delete task&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/delete-task.jpg" alt="Delete task"> - to delete a task from the list, click on this button. A popup will appear asking you to confirm if you want to remove the task or not. To continue with the deletion click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, otherwise click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the name of a task to see the details of the task.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To see a complete list of scheduled tasks click on &lt;strong>Show All&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/show-all.jpg" alt="Show All button">. This list will include all tasks that are running as a result of processes, for example scheduled reminders that are running as a result of rules in a process. Each item listed is a process instance related to a process, for example as shown in the image below. The process instances can be viewed in a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">list widget&lt;/a> in a dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/scheduled-tasks.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks list">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To see the shorter list again of tasks created via this function, click on &lt;strong>Show All&lt;/strong> again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="scheduling-a-task">Scheduling a task&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To schedule a new task, click on the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-a-task.jpg" alt="Schedule a task button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> dialog box, select a &lt;strong>Task name&lt;/strong> for the task and then a &lt;strong>schedule&lt;/strong> choosing from &lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong>, or a periodic schedule from: &lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-box.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Depending on which option you choose, different &lt;strong>time modes&lt;/strong> or ways of scheduling the task will be presented:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> as shown in the image above. Choosing &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> means the time starts at the date and time entered into the date and time field, choosing &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> means you can choose that the schedule starts in X number of &lt;strong>days&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>mins&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes box&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes and &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/hours-schedule.jpg" alt="Hourly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong> - enter a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule and check the checkbox for &lt;strong>Week days&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong> to only schedule the task on weekdays.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong> - enter a day of the week in the &lt;strong>Week day&lt;/strong> field, a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Day&lt;/strong> field to set what day of the month, or choose values to set when the task should happen for example, the &lt;strong>First&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Monday&lt;/strong> of a month, as shown in the image below. Also select a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-monthly.jpg" alt="Monthly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option then a &lt;strong>Task Webhook URL&lt;/strong> field will appear. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the URL is generated by the system. This will send a POST request to the generated URL to trigger the task on demand. If you add an optional instanceID parameter you can run the task on a specific instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, you can check the &lt;strong>Expire&lt;/strong> checkbox, and from there set if you want the schedule to end &lt;strong>By&lt;/strong> a particular date and time or &lt;strong>After&lt;/strong> a set number of occurrences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/task-expiry.jpg" alt="Set task expiry">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, select a process from the &lt;strong>Process design&lt;/strong> dropdown list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, for &lt;strong>Process ID&lt;/strong> leave the field empty if it is a new task or enter the process ID for a given record/process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have finished editing the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>