<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Administration</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: B2B Portals</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>B2B Portals&lt;/strong> is available within the &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> function and available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Manage partners&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The function allows you to share business processes processes to select business partners as external links.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To access B2B portals:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any shared processes or invited partners in the main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-main.jpg" alt="Invite partner main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two main areas: &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Shared processes&lt;/strong>, these are explained in more detail below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="shared-processes">Shared processes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Existing shared processes appear within this section in the right-hand side of the main view. Before you invite a partner you must choose a process to share from within this section first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To share a process with a business partner, click on the &lt;strong>Share a process&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Edit Shared Process&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill out the fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit Shared Process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fields in this box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - provide a title for the shared process&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructions for partner&lt;/strong> - provide instructions for the selected partner&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>plus symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-process.jpg" alt="Add shared process"> to add a selected process design to share. Then click on the dropdown list to search for a process to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add the selected shared process. To change the selected shared process properties by clicking on the &lt;strong>Cog/Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> or delete the selected shared process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-selected-prop.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the **Cog/Settings **button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> a &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> dialog box appears, as shown above, for example Training Request properties. You can check radio buttons for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner to create a new process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to create new process instances from the chosen shared process design. A field &lt;strong>Partner user group allowed to create new instances&lt;/strong> appears, where you can define the group(s) in the partner organisation, that can create these new process instances. If you leave the field blank, then anyone in the partner organisation can create process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner delete a process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to delete new process instances from the chosen shared process design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Partner process form visibility mode - choose from &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong>, then the invited partner(s) can view only assigned form versus all forms, if &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong> is chosen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> then a pop-up appears to &lt;strong>Confirm removal&lt;/strong>, choose from &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-removal.jpg" alt="Confirm removal of selected shared process">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add further selected processes to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Add partner group&lt;/strong> button to add one or more partner groups. Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete partner groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Dashboard template&lt;/strong> click on the dropdown list to select an existing dashboards to share with the selected processes. If you choose to share a dashboard then you can select parameters:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard name in partner&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Use your company name &amp;lsquo;Name of your organisation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Same as selected dashboard&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make welcome page&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then the selected dashboard becomes the welcome page for the partner if no other welcome page is configured.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard security&lt;/strong> - choose from created partner groups within this field to ensure that only users in these partner groups can access the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="to-view-details-of-an-existing-shared--process">To view details of an existing shared process&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main shared processes view, click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a shared process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-processes.jpg" alt="Shared processes view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit Shared Process&lt;/strong> dialog box appears with the same parameters as described in the &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit shared process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>From the main shared processes view click on the &lt;strong>Send Update&lt;/strong> button if you want to send an update to your partner dashboard. Then in the &lt;strong>Confirm shared process update&lt;/strong> dialog box click on &lt;strong>Yes proceed&lt;/strong> to send the update or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to cancel sending the update.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-process-update.jpg" alt="Confirm shared process update">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a shared process,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To invite partners to shared processes go to the &lt;a href="#partners">Partners&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="partners">Partners&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Existing partners appear within this section in the left-hand side of the main view. Before you invite a partner create a shared process as demonstrated in the section &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To invite partners to view shared processes, click on the &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill out the fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-dialog.jpg" alt="Invite partner dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ The fields in this box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Partner organisation&lt;/strong> - provide the name of the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact first name&lt;/strong> - provide the first name of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact last name&lt;/strong> - provide the surname of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact email&lt;/strong> - provide the email of a contact&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Shared process selection&lt;/strong> - in the dropdown list choose a shared process created using the steps listed in &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>More fields&lt;/strong> to see more fields these include: &lt;strong>Partner country&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Partner city&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Partner logo&lt;/strong> which you can add by clicking on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> and browsing your PC or network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="to-view-details-of-existing-partners">To view details of existing partners&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main partners view, click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of an existing partner from the list of partners or type in the name of a partner in the &lt;strong>Search partner&lt;/strong> search box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-main-view.jpg" alt="Partners view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Partner account details&lt;/strong> dialog box appears and details can be edited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-details.jpg" alt="Partner account details">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This dialog box contains same parameters as described in the &lt;a href="#to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/a> section, in addition to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner attributes&lt;/strong> - any additional partner attributes are listed here. See &lt;a href="#partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/a> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Processes shared with partner&lt;/strong> - any processes shared with the partner organisation, following the steps in the &lt;a href="#to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/a> section, are listed here.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-process-update.jpg" alt="Confirm shared process update">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main shared processes view click on the &lt;strong>New invite&lt;/strong> button if you want to invite a partner to a different shared process from the original one. Click on the dropdown list under &lt;strong>Shared process selection&lt;/strong> and select one of the listed shared processes. When you have made your choice, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-process-selection.jpg" alt="Shared process selection">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> results in an email invite being sent and the status in the Partners main view for the partner will be &lt;strong>Pending&lt;/strong> until the partner clicks on &lt;strong>Accept&lt;/strong> in the email, as shown in the example below, following by &lt;strong>Accept invite&lt;/strong> in a further screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-process-email.jpg" alt="Invite partner email example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a shared process, Then in the &lt;strong>Remove partner&lt;/strong> dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to remove the partner, or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to cancel the removal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/remove-partner.jpg" alt="Remove partner">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To edit existing partner properties, go to the &lt;a href="#partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To add new partner properties click on the &lt;strong>Partner properties&lt;/strong> button in the main Partners view.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you click on the button, the &lt;strong>Partner account custom attributes&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> and type in a property, for example Partner region as shown in the example below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-custom.jpg" alt="Partner account custom attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> to add further properties, or click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a property.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>When a new property has been added you will receive a notification &lt;strong>Global settings updated&lt;/strong> and the attribute can be edited for partners when you click on the partner &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> in the main view and edit the &lt;strong>Partner attributes&lt;/strong> details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-details-attribute.jpg" alt="Partner account details attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about creating process designs in Designer and how to use the interface to create forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data sources</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. Data sources is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The data sources function allows you to connect your processes to external data sources like SharePoint, Salesforce or SAP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting your data sources in this way allows real-time scalability, so as your organisation and data grows, the processes created in Kianda will continue to operate with these data sources, providing sustainable, flexible growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda comes with 19 predefined &lt;strong>data connectors&lt;/strong> allowing you to connect to these data sources. These are listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Directory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DocuSign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dropbox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamics CRM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FTP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GlobalPayments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MySQL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Office 365&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oracle database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PowerShell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salesforce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SAP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SOAP Service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>REST Service&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are a developer and want to connect to a datasource that is not included in the predefined set, you can use SOAP or REST to create your own API for data transfer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a SharePoint data connector, the steps are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To connect to a datasource, select &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> from the left-hand side pane and then click &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button and then one of 19 data connectors, for example &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the case of a SharePoint data connector, fill out the &lt;strong>Site URL&lt;/strong> and choose from options like &lt;strong>SharePoint version&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong> as in, if it is a &lt;strong>Site&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Site Collection&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Authentication mode&lt;/strong>. For example, if you choose &lt;strong>System User Credentials&lt;/strong> as an authentication mode, you must provide your SharePoint system username and password.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> and then &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once the data connector is created, this can be used with controls like lists and rules, for example in the image below, a SalesForce data connector called &amp;lsquo;Training&amp;rsquo; has been setup within the Data sources function. Lists within SharePoint can then be linked to list fields in Kianda, by clicking on Data connector in the Edit list dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-list-eg.jpg" alt="Datasource">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about data connectors and how to use them, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>. Designer is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Designer function allows you to create processes and forms using the intuitive easy-to-use no-code interface. Within Designer you can create forms, add controls and rules to create processes to work the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To start creating a process so that Kianda Designer will open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any created processes in the main process view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-view.gif" alt="Process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To view an existing process, click on a process name, or click on a folder or group to see processes within that group, for example a group like &lt;strong>Training&lt;/strong> in the image above.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To import a process created for example in another workspace, click on &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong>. Also note that from the main process view you can also export processes listed here for use in another workspace, by clicking on &lt;strong>Export&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a process using a predefined template, click on the &lt;strong>App Store&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Add new process dialog box appears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-process.jpg" alt="New process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this dialog box fill out the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - give the new process a title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> - the Unique ID field is autofilled from the title field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong> - a short description that describes the new process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - choose an existing group/folder to add the new process to, or type in a new group name to create a new group of processes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or a mix of both users and groups for people who will be administrators of this process. The process administrator(s) is the only person/people who can edit &lt;strong>draft&lt;/strong> process designs. Once the process design is published, workspace administrators will be able to access the process design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once a process is opened, you are brought straight into Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-view.jpg" alt="Designer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="designer-view">Designer view&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is made up of three panes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In the left-hand pane, you will find the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> as well as buttons to &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> processes, as well as exiting Kianda Designer to return to the main process view.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the centre pane, also called the &lt;strong>canvas&lt;/strong>, you can view form details and manipulate form fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the right-hand pane, you can view and edit process and field &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> as well as viewing rules assigned to fields, forms and processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Designer and how to use the interface to create forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Developer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>. The Developer function is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The function allows you to create customised field, rule and dashboard widgets using pre-defined widget UI and code templates that you can add your own code to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To start using &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any customised widgets that have been created will be visible in the main widget view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/developer-view.jpg" alt="Developer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the widget view you can click on the &lt;strong>Version History&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-version-history.jpg" alt="Version History button"> to view the widget creation history, or click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-edit.jpg" alt="Edit widget button">, or click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-delete.jpg" alt="Delete widget button"> to delete a widget. To view widget details, click on the name of a widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new widget click on &lt;strong>New widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Developer and how to use the interface to low-code development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Recycle bin</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The recycle bin holds deleted process instances, dashboard pages and process designs. Deleted items are held for 30 days and are permanently deleted after this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view items in the Recycle bin:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any deleted items in the main recycle bin view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/recycle-bin-view2.jpg" alt="Recycle bin main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first column in the view shows &lt;strong>Item type&lt;/strong> and in this example there are two processes, four dashboard pages and five process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To restore an item click on the &lt;strong>Restore item&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore-bin-item.jpg" alt="Restore recycle bin button"> beside the item name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you click on the button you will get a pop-up confirmation asking you to confirm that you want to restore that item, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> if you wish to restore the item or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to exit. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the item is restored, for example a dashboard page appears again under &lt;strong>Dashboard&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and form go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Scheduled tasks</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Scheduled tasks function allows you to schedule a task, that could be a process or a rule for example to send reminder emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view use the Scheduled tasks function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any current tasks in the main tasks view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-view.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this view you can see the &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> of the task, the &lt;strong>Schedule&lt;/strong> for example weekly or monthly, when the task was &lt;strong>last run&lt;/strong>, when the task will &lt;strong>next run&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of the task, the name of the associated &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> and process &lt;strong>instance&lt;/strong> where relevant, and &lt;strong>who&lt;/strong> is the administrator of the task/who has created the task.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To see a complete list of scheduled tasks click on &lt;strong>Show All&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To schedule a new task, click on the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> dialog box, select a &lt;strong>Task name&lt;/strong> for the task and then a &lt;strong>schedule&lt;/strong> choosing from &lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong>, or a periodic schedule from: &lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-box.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Depending on which option you choose, different &lt;strong>time modes&lt;/strong> or ways of scheduling the task will be presented:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> as shown in the image above. Choosing &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> means the time starts at the date and time entered into the date and time field, choosing &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> means you can choose that the schedule starts in X number of &lt;strong>days&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>mins&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes box&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes and &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule, see image below:
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/hours-schedule.jpg" alt="Hourly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong> - enter a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule and check the checkbox for &lt;strong>Week days&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong> to only schedule the task on weekdays.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong> - enter a day of the week in the &lt;strong>Week day&lt;/strong> field, a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Day&lt;/strong> field to set what day of the month, or choose values to set when the task should happen for example , the &lt;strong>First&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Monday&lt;/strong> of a month, as shown in the image below. Also select a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-monthly.jpg" alt="Monthly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option then a &lt;strong>Task Webhook URL&lt;/strong> field will appear. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the URL is generated by the system. This will send a POST request to the generated URL to trigger the task on demand. If you add an optional instanceID parameter you can run the task on a specific instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select a process from the &lt;strong>Process design&lt;/strong> dropdown list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For &lt;strong>Process ID&lt;/strong> leave the field empty if it is a new task or enter the process ID for a given record/process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Subscription</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. This function allows you to update the look and feel of your workspace, set regional, mobile and single sign-on settings and design the login page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view use the Scheduled tasks function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any current tasks in the main tasks view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/subscription-page.jpg" alt="Subscription view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this view you can typically make changes to six areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> allows you to change the look and feel for your workspace, for example adding company logos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong> allows you to design the login page for your workspace for example to change, background and font colours and add taglines.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to set your operational &lt;strong>time zone&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>regional settings&lt;/strong>, such as English Ireland for language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to customise how the Kianda workspace will appear as a mobile app.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscription Details&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Single Sign-On (SSO)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These areas are covered in more detail in the sections below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a particular area to edit details or click on &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> to use a wizard to edit &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="look-and-feel">Look and Feel&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>You can access this section by clicking on &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> or by clicking on &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> in the main &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/look-and-feel.jpg" alt="Look and feel">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note logo sizes are 200 x 65px for a full-sized logo and 45 x 45px for a collapsed logo. You can also select a colour scheme under Themes and preview the results under Workspace preview on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Users &amp; Groups</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> function is available to users with the &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> role and is found in the left-hand side pane under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. This function allows you to manage users and groups in your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Start &lt;strong>typing&lt;/strong> &lt;em>italic&lt;/em> &lt;u>underline&lt;/u>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To access the &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any existing users and groups in the main view pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-main-view.jpg" alt="Users main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two main areas are &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong>. These two areas are explained in more detail below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="users">Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Existing users appear within this section, showing the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the user, &lt;strong>email&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>role&lt;/strong> and whether they are &lt;strong>active&lt;/strong> or not in the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-mgmt-view.jpg" alt="User management main user view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From this main view, you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#view-and-edit-existing-user-details">&lt;strong>view and edit&lt;/strong> existing user details&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#create-a-new-user">&lt;strong>create a new user&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">create new &lt;strong>profile attributes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#import-and-export-users">bulk &lt;strong>import and export&lt;/strong> users&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#add-and-remove-users-to/from-groups">&lt;strong>add and remove users&lt;/strong> to/from groups&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Click on each of the links below to read more about each function. In addition to the above administrative functions, you can also set passwords and delete users from this main view as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To &lt;strong>reset a password&lt;/strong> for a user, click on the &lt;strong>Reset password/key&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/reset-password.jpg" alt="Reset password/key button"> beside a user name. This will open the &lt;strong>reset password&lt;/strong> dialog box where you can type in a new password for the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/reset-password-box.jpg" alt="Reset password dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ When you are finished adding the new password, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>delete an existing user&lt;/strong>, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button beside a user name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/delete-user-popup.jpg" alt="Delete an existing user">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="view-and-edit-existing-user-details">View and edit existing user details&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a user and the user details appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-profile.jpg" alt="User details view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the details box you can edit a user&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First name&lt;/strong> - user&amp;rsquo;s first name&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Last name&lt;/strong> - user&amp;rsquo;s last name&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - how their name will display in the system&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>More roles&lt;/strong> to see additional roles and choose from six system defined roles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> - lowest level of access where users with this role can access dashboards and forms, Help and Account details&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> - highest level of access where users with this role can access all functions under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> such as &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Manage partners&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create shared processes for business partners.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create and manage processes and form designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create and manage data sources such as connections to SAP, Dropbox, SharePoint and Salesforce.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Developes&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create custom widgets for fields/controls, rules and dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Phone number&lt;/strong> - user&amp;rsquo;s phone number (mobile or office)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile picture URL&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a profile picture on a laptop or network drive to add a profile photo for the user.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Active&lt;/strong> checkbox - by default this checkbox is checked but you can &lt;strong>uncheck it to disable&lt;/strong> a user&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile properties&lt;/strong> - click on this option to see additional properties that you can define, see &lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group membership&lt;/strong> - click on this option to see the groups that a user is added to. Click on the red x button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/redx.jpg" alt="Red x"> to remove a user from a group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing a user&amp;rsquo;s details, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="create-a-new-user">Create a new user&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Create new user&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user-button.jpg" alt="Create new user button">.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Complete the fields as listed in Step 2 in [can &lt;a href="#view-and-edit-existing-user-details">&lt;strong>view and edit&lt;/strong> existing user details&lt;/a>](#view-existing-user-details) above. If additional profile properties have been set for the workspace, add in details for those properties. These properties can be set by clicking on the &lt;strong>Profile attributes&lt;/strong> button, see &lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/a> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>Send welcome email&lt;/strong> check box if you wish to have a system generated email sent to the new user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Group membership&lt;/strong> to view a user&amp;rsquo;s group membership, see &lt;a href="Groups">Groups&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you are finished editing a user&amp;rsquo;s details, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user.jpg" alt="User profile properties and group membership">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>When the user is created they will appear in the main Users view.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As an administrator you can set profile attributes for workspace users within your organisation. For example if your organisation uses particular grade levels for roles, then these can be set using this feature. To modify attributes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Profile attributes&lt;/strong> button in the main &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> section&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/profile-attributes.jpg" alt="Profile attributes button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Modify user attributes&lt;/strong> dialog box, any existing attributes will be listed under &lt;strong>Property&lt;/strong>. To remove an attribute, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin/Trash button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/modify-user-attributes.jpg" alt="Modify user attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a new attribute, click on the &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-attribute.jpg" alt="Add attribute button"> then type in the name of the new attribute.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing attributes, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="importing-and-exporting-users">Importing and exporting users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In addition to clicking on the &lt;strong>Create new user&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user-button.jpg" alt="Create new user button"> you can import users using an Excel file by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bulk import users&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="viewing-and-editing-group-members">Viewing and editing group members&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the radio button beside the group name to see the group members.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/group-members.jpg" alt="Group membership">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From this view you can &lt;strong>remove a user from the group&lt;/strong> by checking the checkbox beside a user name and click on &lt;strong>Remove user(s) from group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also change &lt;strong>users&lt;/strong> from the current group &lt;strong>to another group&lt;/strong> by clicking on the dropdown list of group names, by choosing a group, checking the checkbox beside the username and click on &lt;strong>Add user(s) to group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-user-to-group.jpg" alt="Add user to group">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: You can only add users to groups, if you yourself are an administrator for the group, see next section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="viewing-and-editing-group-details">Viewing and editing group details&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>group name&lt;/strong> to see details for a group.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Edit group &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> dialog box appears.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-group.jpg" alt="Edit group dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In this dialog box you can edit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group name&lt;/strong> - the name of the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong> - the primary role of the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group member sync&lt;/strong> - options are &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group administrators&lt;/strong> - only users or groups listed here can manage the group; if you leave the field blank then Kianda administrators can manage the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete a group, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> icon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/help">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>