<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Administration</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong>. Designer is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Designer function allows you to create processes and forms using the intuitive easy-to-use no-code interface. Within Designer, you can create forms, add controls and add rules to create processes to work the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Using your Administration or Design business process role, start creating or editing a process so that Kianda Designer will open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any existing created processes in the main &lt;strong>Process design&lt;/strong> view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/main-process-view.jpg" alt="Process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Processes may be arranged in folders or groups. Click on the folder name to see processes within that group, for example a group like &lt;strong>Training&lt;/strong> as shown in the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/training-folder.jpg" alt="Training folder of processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can search for a specific process or process group by typing into the process design &lt;strong>Search bar&lt;/strong>, found above the list of processes. Click on the &lt;strong>cancel&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cancel-btn.png" alt="Cancel button" style="zoom:80%;" /> to clear your search query.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/searching-processes.png" alt="Searching for a process">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a process name to see the process design. You are then brought into &lt;strong>Kianda Designer&lt;/strong>, see &lt;a href="#designer-view">Designer view&lt;/a> details below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To import a process created for example in another workspace, click on &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/import_frame.png" alt="Import button">. Also note that from the main process view you can also export processes listed here for use in another workspace, by clicking on &lt;strong>Export&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/export_frame.png" alt="Export process">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a process using a predefined template, click on the &lt;strong>App Store&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add new process&lt;/strong> dialog box appears where you can fill out details for your new process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-process.jpg" alt="New process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this dialog box fill out the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - give the new process a title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> - the Unique ID field is autofilled from the title field. Note that this ID is unique for each process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong> - a short description that describes the new process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - choose an existing group/folder to add the new process to, or type in a new group name to create a new group of processes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or a mix of both users and groups for people who will be administrators of this process. The process administrator(s) is the only person/people who can edit &lt;strong>draft&lt;/strong> process designs. Once the process design is published, workspace administrators will be able to access the process design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once a process is opened, you are brought straight into Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>, see &lt;a href="#designer-view">Designer view&lt;/a> below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="designer-view">Designer view&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> allows you to create forms within your process, add in fields, rules and set out exactly how you want your form to appear, for example mandatory fields, help text, connection to a data source that pulls in information into the form as well as using &lt;strong>settings&lt;/strong> to control who has access to forms and fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is made up of three panes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-view.jpg" alt="Designer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In the left-hand pane, you will find the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> as well as buttons to &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> processes, as well as exiting Kianda Designer to return to the main process view.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the centre pane, also called the &lt;strong>canvas&lt;/strong>, you can view form details and manipulate form fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the right-hand pane, you can view and edit process and field &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> as well as viewing rules assigned to fields, forms and processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Designer in detail and how to use the interface to create forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Subscription</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. This function allows you to update the look and feel of your workspace, set regional, mobile and single sign-on settings and design the login page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For &lt;strong>developers&lt;/strong> who wish to &lt;strong>customise and style&lt;/strong> their Kianda workspace and processes, there are options to support you in achieving a high level of design that is instantly recognisable for users. These options include creating a &lt;strong>custom branding style&lt;/strong>, customised &lt;strong>login page&lt;/strong> and option to control how your platform will look on &lt;strong>mobile devices&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To view, use the Subscription function as an administrator:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The main Subscription page opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/subscription-main.jpg" alt="Subscription view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this view you can typically make changes to six areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> allows you to change the look and feel for your workspace, for example adding company logos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong> allows you to design the login page for your workspace, for example to change background and font colours and add taglines.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to set your operational &lt;strong>time zone&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>regional settings&lt;/strong>, such as English Ireland for language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong> allows you to customise how the Kianda workspace will appear as a mobile app.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscription Details&lt;/strong> allows you to view your company details and enable a Global SMTP Mail connector for sending automated emails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Storage Files&lt;/strong> allows you upload, delete and view public and private files within your subscription. You can also create folders to organise your files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These areas are covered in more detail in the sections below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a particular area to edit details or click on the &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/open-wizard-btn.jpg" alt="Open wizard button"> button to use a wizard to edit &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Design Login Page&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Regional Settings&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Mobile Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Details on each area are available below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="look-and-feel">Look and Feel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can access this section by clicking on &lt;strong>Open Wizard&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> or by clicking on &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> in the main &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively you can access this section by clicking on the &lt;strong>Look and Feel&lt;/strong> shortcut found in the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/">&lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/look-and-feel.jpg" alt="Look and feel">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Logo sizes are 200 x 65px for a full-sized logo and 45 x 45px for a collapsed logo. You can also select a colour scheme under Themes and preview the results under Workspace preview on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Details for each of the areas within the page - &lt;a href="#logos">Logos&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#layout">Layout&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#themes">Themes&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#css">CSS&lt;/a> are available below. Make sure to click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="logos">Logos&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a logo for your company:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> beside &lt;strong>Logo Url&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. The recommended size is 200px x 65px.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To add a logo that will appear when the left-hand side menu is collapsed, click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> beside &lt;strong>Collapsed Logo URL&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. The recommended size is 45px x 45px.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="layout">Layout&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The options for your workspace layout are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Boxed&lt;/strong> - moving the slider across to enable a boxed layout, that is the workspace appears in a box in the browser, with space appearing around the box and content is centred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/boxed-layout.jpg" alt="Boxed layout">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>RTL&lt;/strong> - moved the slider across to enable a right-to-left (RTL) layout, that is text, layout, icons and so on are right-hand based.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disable Zoom on Mobile&lt;/strong> - move the slider across to enable the &amp;lsquo;disable zoom on mobile&amp;rsquo; option, which means that the zooming option is disabled on mobile web pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome page&lt;/strong> - click on the &lt;strong>Change&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-button.jpg" alt="Change button"> to change the Welcome page for users of your Kianda workspace. The &lt;strong>Update welcome page&lt;/strong> dialog box opens where you can click on the drop-down list under &lt;strong>New welcome page&lt;/strong> to choose a new welcome page, from the Home page and dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/update-welcome-page.jpg" alt="Update welcome page dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save changes or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Click on a &lt;strong>Theme&lt;/strong> of choice. Options range from two-tone layouts, to those with a dark left-hand side menu as shown in the middle of the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/themes.jpg" alt="Themes">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="css">CSS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section you can modify the &lt;strong>Global CSS File&lt;/strong> to make changes to the look and feel of the site as well as processes. If you have an existing CSS file, you can access the existing CSS details by clicking on the on the &lt;strong>ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expression.jpg" alt="Ellipsis button"> to open a CSS Editor and add to those details, or click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a CSS file to add in customised styling. See &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-css/">Global CSS file&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure to click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="design-login-page">Design Login Page&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section allows you to design the login page, choose background and font colours and complete fields for Taglines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-login-page.jpg" alt="Design login page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Login Page Logo Url&lt;/strong> - add/change a logo for the login page to Kianda by clicking on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo on your PC or network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Background Color&lt;/strong> - to create a background colour for the login page, you can either click on the colour itself and select a colour in the main view, or using the slider, or type in an RGB, HSL or HEX value in the fields above, or click in the box beside it to add in a HEX value for a colour, for example #BFBFBF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/background-color.jpg" alt="Background Color">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Font Color&lt;/strong> - as with the Background Color, to create a font colour, choose an appropriate colour using the colour box itself or type in a value in the field beside the colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tagline 1&lt;/strong> - type in the first tagline that will appear under your company logo on the login page. A maximum of 25 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tagline 2&lt;/strong> - type in the second tagline that will appear under your company logo on the login page. A maximum of 20 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/taglines.jpg" alt="Taglines">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="regional-settings">Regional Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here you can set your operational time zone and regional settings, such as English Ireland, from the dropdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/regional-settings.jpg" alt="Regional settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regional settings&lt;/strong> - choose a language setting from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Time zone&lt;/strong> - choose a time zone from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button"> to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chosen options are reflected in the text below the fields, for example &lt;strong>date and time format&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mobile-settings">Mobile Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here you can customise how the Kianda workspace will appear to users on mobile devices. You can choose your App name, App short name, Splash Screen Colour, and Theme Colour and upload a mobile size icon (note the icon size is 512 x 512 px).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/mobile-settings.jpg" alt="Mobile settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this page you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>App name&lt;/strong> - add/change a name to set a custom app name for your app/workspace that reflects your business. A maximum of 45 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>App short name&lt;/strong> - add/change a shortened name for your app/workspace, for user in areas without space for longer text strings. A maximum of 12 characters is recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Splash Screen Color&lt;/strong> - to set the introductory screen colour that appears while your application loads (splash screen), you can either click on the colour itself and select a colour in the main view, or using the slider, or type in an RGB, HSL or HEX value in the fields above, or click in the box beside it to add in a HEX value for a colour, for example #037dd3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/splash-screen-color.jpg" alt="Splash screen color">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Theme Color&lt;/strong> - as with the Splash Screen Color, choose an appropriate colour for the mobile app theme font using the colour box itself or type in a value in the field beside the colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mobile Icon&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a logo to add from your PC or network. This will be displayed on the home screen of your users&amp;rsquo; mobile devices. The recommended size is 512px x 512px.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes, click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="subscription-details">Subscription Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>General settings include details like your company name, subscription ID, renewal date and business identity (your workspace URL, for example, green-itr.kianda.com). You can also enable a Global SMTP Mail Connector to enable email flow to/from your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within general settings, administrators can set who the Global Administrator is, or the main administrator for the workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/company-details.jpg" alt="Subscription details" style="zoom:80%;" />
&lt;h3 id="company-details">Company details&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>in this section you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Company Name&lt;/strong> - add in your company name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business identity&lt;/strong> - the business identity for your company workspace is automatically added in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Country&lt;/strong> - choose a country from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>City&lt;/strong> - choose a city from the drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Address&lt;/strong> - add in your company address.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Renewal date&lt;/strong> - your subscription renewal date is automatically added in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscription Id&lt;/strong> - your company subscription identity is automatically generated. This is needed when you need to perform authorisation to use Instance API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Address&lt;/strong> - add in your company address.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="general-settings">General settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section you can make the following changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable Global SMTP Mail Connector&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to set a global Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP) connector used to send emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The global connector will ignore all other connectors and will no longer use &lt;a href="mailto:no-reply@kianda.com">no-reply@kianda.com&lt;/a> as a sender. To enable this you must have an email connector set up in advance. To learn more about email connectors go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/email/">Email connector&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition you can choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>Enable save to Sent Items&lt;/strong> so that sent email are automatically saved in a &amp;lsquo;Sent items folder&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/global-smtp-email-connector.jpg" alt="Enabling Global SMTP Mail Connector">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Global Administrator&lt;/strong> - change the global administrator of your company&amp;rsquo;s Kianda platform from the list of users that are in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Global JavaScript&lt;/strong> - allows you to create a JavaScript file with custom functions as helper or action functions allowing you to perform any functionality you may want. The file is accessible globally and will load when the application first starts. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/global-javascript-file/">Global JavaScript file&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you are finished making changes click on &lt;strong>Save Changes&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-changes.jpg" alt="Save changes button">to save any changes made and click on &lt;strong>Back&lt;/strong> to go back to the &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="storage-files">Storage files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can access this section by clicking on &lt;strong>Storage Files&lt;/strong> in the main &lt;strong>Administration &amp;gt; Subscription&lt;/strong> page. Here you can see all public and private files that are in your platforms storage. You can search for files using the search box and navigate between &lt;strong>Public&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Private&lt;/strong> files using the provided tabs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/storage-files.jpg" alt="Single Sign-On Details">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="upload-files">Upload file(s)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To upload a file to Storage files, click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/upload-file.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/storage-file-upload.jpg" alt="upload file">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A file explorer will open in which you can select multiple files to upload to you platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="create-folder">Create folder&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To create a folder, click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/file-storage-create-folder.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-folder.jpg" alt="create folder">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The folder will appear alphabetically in the main view where you can see all your files. To upload a file into folder, first, you need to click on the folder name to open it and then click on &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/upload-file.jpg" alt="upload file"> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any time, you can go to left-hand side menu and click on &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> to edit any of the settings for the headings above.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data sources</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. Data sources is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The data sources function allows you to connect your processes to external data sources like SharePoint, Salesforce or SAP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting your data sources in this way allows real-time scalability, so as your organisation and data grows, the processes created in Kianda will continue to operate with these data sources, providing sustainable, flexible growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda comes with 19 predefined &lt;strong>data connectors&lt;/strong> allowing you to connect to these data sources. These are listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Directory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DocuSign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dropbox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamics CRM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FTP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GlobalPayments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MySQL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Office 365&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oracle database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PowerShell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salesforce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SAP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SOAP Service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>REST Service&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are a developer and want to connect to a datasource that is not included in the predefined set, you can use SOAP or REST to create your own API for data transfer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start viewing existing data sources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To see the datasource management function, select &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> from the left-hand side pane and then click &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any existing data sources that have been created for your workspace are shown in the main view under &lt;strong>Datasource management&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-list.jpg" alt="Existing data connectors">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Data sources are listed by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - assigned title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Type and icon&lt;/strong> - assigned data connector type and icon image&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified&lt;/strong> - the date the connector was modified&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modified By&lt;/strong> - the person who last made changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong> - for example &lt;strong>ready&lt;/strong> means the connection has been tested and is working, while &lt;strong>incomplete&lt;/strong> means that more details still need to be added.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>search&lt;/strong> for a data source, type in the name or type of data source in the &lt;strong>search box&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> a data source, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin/Trash button"> beside the name of the datasource. You will receive a popup asking to you to confirm deletion by clicking &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or you can exit the deletion by clicking on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>see the details&lt;/strong> of a data source, click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the Data source and from there you are brought to the &lt;strong>Data source details&lt;/strong> page:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-details-eg.jpg" alt="Data source details example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The details will vary depending on the data source, but there are some common elements:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - the name of the data source as it will display in your system. Choose something meaningful, as you will use this name in process design to connect your forms to your data source.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Information about the data source&lt;/strong> - this could be a URL, Server name, Client ID, root folder path etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Authentication details&lt;/strong> - this could be a username, password, client secret etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Option to use &lt;strong>Kianda Cloud Connect&lt;/strong> - you enable this feature and download a zip file which you can install on your server, allowing the Kianda system to reach your server and get access to data, for example SQL Server, making system integration quick and efficient.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> - all data source detail pages will allow you to test your connection using this button to ensure data exchange can happen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> - at any time you can save details, even if some parameters need to be completed, allowing you to return to the configuration at any point.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> - all data sources can have different levels of security set up, including administrators for the connection, and users of the connection, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> - allows you to exit from the data source details page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-create-a-new-datasource">How to create a new datasource&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following uses &lt;strong>SharePoint as an example&lt;/strong> when creating a new datasource. The main steps for any datasource will be similar, that is: click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button, fill out the &lt;strong>datasource details&lt;/strong> page, &lt;strong>test the connection&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>save&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>add security&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main datasource management view, click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new data connector button"> and then one of 19 data connectors that appear, for example &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fill out fields in the &lt;strong>SharePoint details&lt;/strong> screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/sharepoint-connector.jpg" alt="Sharepoint datasources">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - the name of the data source, for example SharePoint HR&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Site URL&lt;/strong> - this is the link to your SharePoint data&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SharePoint version&lt;/strong> - choose from a) SharePoint Online (also known as SharePoint in Microsoft 365) b) SharePoint 2016 or c) SharePoint 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Site for example a particular SharePoint website or b) Site Collection, a collection of SharePoint sites&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authentication mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) SharePoint Online Authorisation and b) System User Credentials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) SharePoint Online Authorisation then click on &lt;strong>Authorize&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/authorize.png" alt="Authorize button"> in this instance you will need SharePoint administration rights&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) System User Credentials then fill out your username and password. In this instance you do not need SharePoint administration rights.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have added SharePoint details, you are ready to test your connection and add security. At the bottom of the &lt;strong>SharePoint details&lt;/strong> page, click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/test-connection.jpg" alt="Test connection for REST Service"> and if the service has been correctly configured, then you should receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Connection test succeeded&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save-connection.jpg" alt="Save connection button"> to save the connection and you will receive a notification saying &lt;strong>Details saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add Security settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/security-button.jpg" alt="Security button">, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/#setting-security-for-data-sources">Setting security for data sources&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the details page and return to the datasource management main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once the data connector is created, this can be used with controls like lists and rules, for example in the image below, a SharePoint data connector called &amp;lsquo;SharePoint Training Test&amp;rsquo; has been setup within the datasources function. Lists within SharePoint can then be linked to list fields in Kianda, by clicking on &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> in the Edit list dialog box. In the example below, a list called &lt;strong>Companies&lt;/strong> is the data source for the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/list-datasource-example.jpg" alt="Datasource">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about data connectors and how to use them, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Data Connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Scheduled tasks</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Scheduled tasks function allows you to schedule a task, that could be a process or a rule for example to send reminder emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To use the Scheduled tasks function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view scheduled tasks via this function in the &lt;strong>Task automation&lt;/strong> main tasks view. The current tasks listed is a subset of all tasks, see Step 4 below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-view.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this main view you can see:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> of the task&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>Schedule&lt;/strong> for example weekly or monthly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the task was &lt;strong>last run&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the task will &lt;strong>next run&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>status&lt;/strong> of the task such as &amp;lsquo;Complete&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the name of the associated &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> and process &lt;strong>instance&lt;/strong> where relevant, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>who&lt;/strong> is the administrator of the task/who has created the task.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The buttons beside each task are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trigger task manually&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trigger-task-manually.jpg" alt="Trigger task manually"> - clicking on this button instantly creates a new process instance/record by executing the task or process. This process instance can be viewed in a list widget in a dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show task history&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/show-task-history.jpg" alt="Show task history"> - when you click on this button, a dialog box opens showing a list of all the past executions of the task, listed by date and time and status, for example if there was an error or if the task completed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delete task&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/delete-task.jpg" alt="Delete task"> - to delete a task from the list, click on this button. A popup will appear asking you to confirm if you want to remove the task or not. To continue with the deletion click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, otherwise click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the name of a task to see the details of the task.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To see a complete list of scheduled tasks click on &lt;strong>Show All&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/show-all.jpg" alt="Show All button">. This list will include all tasks that are running as a result of processes, for example scheduled reminders that are running as a result of rules in a process. Each item listed is a process instance related to a process, for example as shown in the image below. The process instances can be viewed in a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/">list widget&lt;/a> in a dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/scheduled-tasks.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks list">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To see the shorter list again of tasks created via this function, click on &lt;strong>Show All&lt;/strong> again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="scheduling-a-task">Scheduling a task&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To schedule a new task, click on the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-a-task.jpg" alt="Schedule a task button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> dialog box, select a &lt;strong>Task name&lt;/strong> for the task and then a &lt;strong>schedule&lt;/strong> choosing from &lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong>, or a periodic schedule from: &lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-tasks-box.jpg" alt="Scheduled tasks view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Depending on which option you choose, different &lt;strong>time modes&lt;/strong> or ways of scheduling the task will be presented:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One time&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> as shown in the image above. Choosing &lt;strong>Absolute&lt;/strong> means the time starts at the date and time entered into the date and time field, choosing &lt;strong>Relative from now&lt;/strong> means you can choose that the schedule starts in X number of &lt;strong>days&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>hours&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>mins&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minutes&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes box&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hourly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value into the minutes and &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule, see image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/hours-schedule.jpg" alt="Hourly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong> - enter a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field, to set a recurring schedule and check the checkbox for &lt;strong>Week days&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong> to only schedule the task on weekdays.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong> - enter a day of the week in the &lt;strong>Week day&lt;/strong> field, a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong> - enter a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Day&lt;/strong> field to set what day of the month, or choose values to set when the task should happen for example, the &lt;strong>First&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Monday&lt;/strong> of a month, as shown in the image below. Also select a time in the &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> field, and a numeric value in the &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/schedule-monthly.jpg" alt="Monthly schedule option">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On demand&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option then a &lt;strong>Task Webhook URL&lt;/strong> field will appear. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the URL is generated by the system. This will send a POST request to the generated URL to trigger the task on demand. If you add an optional instanceID parameter you can run the task on a specific instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, you can check the &lt;strong>Expire&lt;/strong> checkbox, and from there set if you want the schedule to end &lt;strong>By&lt;/strong> a particular date and time or &lt;strong>After&lt;/strong> a set number of occurrences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/task-expiry.jpg" alt="Set task expiry">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, select a process from the &lt;strong>Process design&lt;/strong> dropdown list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For each time mode chosen, for &lt;strong>Process ID&lt;/strong> leave the field empty if it is a new task or enter the process ID for a given record/process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have finished editing the &lt;strong>Schedule a task&lt;/strong> dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Recycle bin</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong> function is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The recycle bin holds deleted process instances, dashboard pages and process designs. Deleted items are held for 30 days and are permanently deleted after this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view items in the Recycle bin:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for an item by typing in key words into the &lt;strong>Search items&lt;/strong> box for example &amp;lsquo;Office&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view existing deleted items in the &lt;strong>Recycle bin&lt;/strong> main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/recycle-bin-view2.jpg" alt="Recycle bin main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deleted items are listed by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Item type&lt;/strong> - this is the type of deleted item, for example a widget, process instance, datasource or page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Item details&lt;/strong> - the name of the deleted item, for example the name of a process instance and the unique name (ID) for that process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deleted date&lt;/strong> - the date the item was deleted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deleted by&lt;/strong> - the name of the user who deleted the item.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the example above there is one process design, four dashboard pages and three process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To restore an item click on the &lt;strong>Restore item&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore-bin-item.jpg" alt="Restore recycle bin button"> beside the item name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you click on the button you will get a pop-up confirmation asking you to confirm that you want to restore that item.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore-item.jpg" alt="Restore item">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> if you wish to restore the item or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to exit. If you click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> the item is restored, for example a datasource appears again within the Datasource management main view when you click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane. To learn more about this, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources">Data sources&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource-restored.jpg" alt="Datasource restored">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and form go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read about other parts of the platform go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/">Administration&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Users &amp; Groups</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> function is available to users with the &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> role and is found in the left-hand side menu under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. This function allows you to manage users and groups in your Kianda workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access the &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> function:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any existing users and groups that have been created in the main view pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-main-view3.png" alt="Users main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two main areas are 1. &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and 2. &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong>. These two areas are explained in more detail below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="users">Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Existing users appear within this section, showing the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the user, &lt;strong>email&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>role&lt;/strong> and whether they are &lt;strong>active&lt;/strong> or not in the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-mgmt-view2.png" alt="User management main user view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From this main view, you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#view-and-edit-existing-user-details">&lt;strong>view and edit&lt;/strong> existing user details&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#create-a-new-user">&lt;strong>create a new user&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">create new &lt;strong>profile attributes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#importing-and-exporting-users">bulk &lt;strong>import and export&lt;/strong> users&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#groups">&lt;strong>add and remove users&lt;/strong> to/from groups&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Click on each of the links above to read more about each function. In addition to the above administrative functions, you can also set passwords and delete users from this main view as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To &lt;strong>reset a password&lt;/strong> for a user, click on the &lt;strong>Reset password/key&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/reset-password.jpg" alt="Reset password/key button"> beside a user name. This will open the &lt;strong>reset password&lt;/strong> dialog box where you can type in a new password for the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/reset-password-box.jpg" alt="Reset password dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ When you are finished adding the new password, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To &lt;strong>delete an existing user&lt;/strong>, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button beside a user name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/delete-user-popup.jpg" alt="Delete an existing user">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="licenses">Licenses&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before managing the user accounts on your platform, you will need to understand the concept of &lt;strong>Licenses&lt;/strong>. Depending on your subscription type, you will be allocated a certain number of licenses, which allow your users to be active on your platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A single license is used by each individual active user within your platform, for example if your platform has 250 total licenses and you have 19 activated accounts, you will have 231 remaining licenses. If a user license is &lt;strong>issued&lt;/strong>, the total number of licenses will &lt;strong>decrease&lt;/strong>, and if a user license is &lt;strong>revoked&lt;/strong>, the total number of licenses will &lt;strong>increase&lt;/strong>. If there are no more remaining licenses, new users will be deactivated. You can get more licenses by deactivating users or purchasing additional licenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/licenses.png" alt="Licenses image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="view-and-edit-existing-user-details">View and edit existing user details&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a user and the user details appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/user-profile2.png" alt="User details view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the details box you can edit a user&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>First name&lt;/strong> - user&amp;rsquo;s first name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Last name&lt;/strong> - user&amp;rsquo;s last name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong> - how their name will display in the system. The display name is autofilled based off of the user&amp;rsquo;s entered first and last names, which can be changed if necessary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>License activation status&lt;/strong> - Checking this box will create the user as active. This will consume a license from your subscription. If you are out of licenses you will be prompted to purchase an additional license.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>More roles&lt;/strong> to see additional roles and choose from six system defined roles.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> - lowest level of access where users with this role can access dashboards and forms, Help and Account details&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> - highest level of access where users with this role can access all functions under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> such as &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Manage partners&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create shared processes for business partners.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create and manage processes and form designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create and manage data sources such as connections to SAP, Dropbox, SharePoint and Salesforce.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> - users with this role can access the same areas as &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>Developes&lt;/strong> function under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> to create custom widgets for fields/controls, rules and dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Profile picture URL&lt;/strong> - click on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> to browse for a profile picture on a laptop or network drive to add a profile photo for the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Profile properties&lt;/strong> - click on this option to see additional properties that you can define, see &lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group membership&lt;/strong> - click on this option to see the groups that a user is added to. Click on the red x button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/redx.jpg" alt="Red x"> to remove a user from a group.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing a user&amp;rsquo;s details, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="create-a-new-user">Create a new user&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Create new user&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user-button.jpg" alt="Create new user button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Complete the fields as listed in Step 2 in &lt;a href="#view-and-edit-existing-user-details">View and edit existing user details&lt;/a> above. If additional profile properties have been set for the workspace, add in details for those properties. These properties can be set by clicking on the &lt;strong>Profile attributes&lt;/strong> button, see &lt;a href="#modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Check the &lt;strong>Send welcome email&lt;/strong> check box if you wish to have a system generated email sent to the new user.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Group membership&lt;/strong> to view a user&amp;rsquo;s group membership, see &lt;a href="#groups">Groups&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing a user&amp;rsquo;s details, click on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user2.png" alt="User profile properties and group membership">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When the user is created they will appear in the main Users view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="modify-profile-attributes">Modify profile attributes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As an administrator you can set profile attributes for workspace users within your organisation. For example if your organisation uses particular grade levels for roles, then these can be set using this feature. To modify attributes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Profile attributes&lt;/strong> button in the main &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> section.&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/modify-user-attributes2.png" alt="Profile attributes button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Modify user attributes&lt;/strong> dialog box, any existing attributes will be listed under &lt;strong>Property&lt;/strong>. To remove an attribute, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin/Trash button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/modify-user-attributes.jpg" alt="Modify user attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a new attribute, click on the &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-attribute.jpg" alt="Add attribute button">, then type in the name of the new attribute.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing attributes, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="importing-and-exporting-users">Importing and exporting users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In addition to clicking on the &lt;strong>Create new user&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-new-user-button.jpg" alt="Create new user button">, you can &lt;strong>import&lt;/strong> users using an Excel file by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bulk import users&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bulk-import-users.jpg" alt="Bulk import users">. The &lt;strong>Import users&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/import-users.jpg" alt="Import users dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Import users&lt;/strong> dialog box you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Browse User Import Excel File&lt;/strong> to browse for a file of users to add.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Download sample user import Excel file&lt;/strong> to see the file structure needed to import users. The key user fields here are: Email, First Name, Last Name, Display Name and optional is Telephone number.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can &lt;strong>export&lt;/strong> a list of users by clicking on the &lt;strong>Export to csv&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/export-to-csv.jpg" alt="Export to csv">. The resulting file will list users by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display name&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Email&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> - they are members of&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Active&lt;/strong> - if the user is active and is currently using a license&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Last active&lt;/strong> - when the user was last active&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Seen below is an example CSV output in excel:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/csv-file-export.png" alt="exported csv image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="groups">Groups&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you create predefined &lt;strong>groups,&lt;/strong> you can use these group names in a myriad of ways, for example to create a set of finance managers who can then be listed as &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-owners/">form owners&lt;/a> to edit forms in process instances for procurement, or a set of contractors in an &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/sso/">SSO bypass group&lt;/a> who can go the workspace login page to login to Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/groups.jpg" alt="Groups in User Management">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Existing groups appear within the &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> section of the &lt;strong>User management page&lt;/strong>, showing the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of the group and the &lt;strong>number of members&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From this main view you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#viewing-and-editing-group-members">view and edit group members&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#viewing-and-editing-group-details">view and edit group details&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#deleting-groups">delete groups&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#creating-new-groups">create a new group&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="viewing-and-editing-group-members">Viewing and editing group members&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the radio button beside the &lt;strong>group name&lt;/strong> in the main view to see the group members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/group-members2.png" alt="Group membership">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From this view, you can &lt;strong>remove a user from the group&lt;/strong> by checking the checkbox beside a user name and click on &lt;strong>Remove user(s) from group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also change &lt;strong>users&lt;/strong> from the current group &lt;strong>to another group&lt;/strong> by clicking on the dropdown list of group names, by choosing a group, checking the checkbox beside the username.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-user-to-group2.png" alt="Add user to group">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add user(s) to group&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: You can only add users to groups, if you yourself are an administrator for the group, see next section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="viewing-and-editing-group-details">Viewing and editing group details&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>group name&lt;/strong> in the main view to see details for a group.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Edit group &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> dialog box appears.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-group.jpg" alt="Edit group dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In this dialog box you can edit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group name&lt;/strong> - the name of the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong> - the primary role of the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group member sync&lt;/strong> - options are &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>. By choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> this allows synchronisation of the Kianda group with Active Directory or other databases connected to Kianda as data sources. As a result of choosing Yes, other parameters appear:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Override group members&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>. By choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, a full synchronisation is enabled between the Kianda group and the data source of users. Any users that are not listed in the data source, will be removed from this group in Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/group-sync.jpg" alt="Group member synch">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> - choose a data source from the dropdown list. This data source must be already created, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Data connectors&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group name&lt;/strong> - choose a name for the group if desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Auto disable previously imported users that are missing on re-import&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>. By choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, any previously imported users that no longer exist in the data source, will be disabled in Kianda when re-synchronisation is executed. Their account will still exist in the system, but they will no longer be able to login to Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Auto remove previously imported users that are missing on re-import&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>. By choosing &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, any previously imported users that no longer exist in the data source, will be removed from Kianda when re-synchronisation is executed. They will no longer be able to login to Kianda as their account will be removed from the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: When a group is synchronised, a &lt;strong>scheduled task&lt;/strong> is created to import users from the data source group every one hour by default. This can be changed by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Scheduled tasks&lt;/strong>. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/">Scheduled tasks&lt;/a> to find out more about different schedules.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group administrators&lt;/strong> - only &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> listed here can manage the group; if you leave the field blank then Kianda administrators can manage the group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="deleting-groups">Deleting groups&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete a group, click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin/trash button"> beside the name of the group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will receive a popup asking you if you want to delete the particular team. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to delete the team, or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="creating-new-groups">Creating new groups&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new group, click on the &lt;strong>Create new group&lt;/strong> button in the main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Add group&lt;/strong> dialog box, type in details for the group:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-group.jpg" alt="Add group dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group name&lt;/strong> - the name of the group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primary role&lt;/strong> - choose a role for the group from &lt;strong>User&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Manage partners&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> as before, see Role details in &lt;a href="#view-and-edit-existing-user-details">Viewing and editing existing user details&lt;/a>. In addition there is another role, &lt;strong>Design own business process&lt;/strong> that allows groups to design their own process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-own-process.jpg" alt="Group roles">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group administrators&lt;/strong> - add &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and/or &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> to add people who can manage group membership. If you leave the field blank, any Kianda administrator can manage the group. If you specify administrators, as group creator you must add yourself as group administrator.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save changes, otherwise click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: B2B Portals</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>B2B Portals&lt;/strong> is available within the &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> function and available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Manage partners&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong> is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The function allows you to share business processes processes to select business partners as external links.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access B2B portals:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Invite partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any shared processes or invited partners in the main view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-main.jpg" alt="Invite partner main view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two main areas: &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Shared processes&lt;/strong>, these are explained in more detail below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="shared-processes">Shared processes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Existing shared processes appear within this section in the right-hand side of the main view. Before you invite a partner you must choose a process to share from within this section first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To share a process with a business partner, click on the &lt;strong>Share a process&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Edit Shared Process&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill out the fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit Shared Process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fields in this box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - provide a title for the shared process&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructions for partner&lt;/strong> - provide instructions for the selected partner&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>plus symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/add-process.jpg" alt="Add shared process"> to add a selected process design to share. Then click on the dropdown list to search for a process to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add the selected shared process. To change the selected shared process properties by clicking on the &lt;strong>Cog/Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> or delete the selected shared process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-selected-prop.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the &lt;strong>Cog/Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process properties"> a &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> dialog box appears, as shown above, for example Training Request properties. You can check radio buttons for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner to create a new process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to create new process instances from the chosen shared process design. A field &lt;strong>Partner user group allowed to create new instances&lt;/strong> appears, where you can define the group(s) in the partner organisation, that can create these new process instances. If you leave the field blank, then anyone in the partner organisation can create process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow partner delete a process instance&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you are allowing invited partner(s) to delete new process instances from the chosen shared process design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Partner process form visibility mode - choose from &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Assigned&lt;/strong>, then the invited partner(s) can view only assigned form versus all forms, if &lt;strong>All forms&lt;/strong> is chosen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> then a pop-up appears to &lt;strong>Confirm removal&lt;/strong>, choose from &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-removal.jpg" alt="Confirm removal of selected shared process">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Tick symbol&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-selected-process.jpg" alt="Edit selected shared process"> to add further selected processes to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Add partner group&lt;/strong> button to add one or more partner groups. Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete partner groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Dashboard template&lt;/strong> click on the dropdown list to select an existing dashboards to share with the selected processes. If you choose to share a dashboard then you can select parameters:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard name in partner&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Use your company name &amp;lsquo;Name of your organisation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Same as selected dashboard&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make welcome page&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then the selected dashboard becomes the welcome page for the partner if no other welcome page is configured.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dashboard security&lt;/strong> - choose from created partner groups within this field to ensure that only users in these partner groups can access the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="to-view-details-of-an-existing-shared--process">To view details of an existing shared process&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main shared processes view, click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of a shared process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-processes.jpg" alt="Shared processes view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit Shared Process&lt;/strong> dialog box appears with the same parameters as described in the &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-shared-process.jpg" alt="Edit shared process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main shared processes view click on the &lt;strong>Send Update&lt;/strong> button if you want to send an update to your partner dashboard. Then in the &lt;strong>Confirm shared process update&lt;/strong> dialog box click on &lt;strong>Yes proceed&lt;/strong> to send the update or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to cancel sending the update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-process-update.jpg" alt="Confirm shared process update">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a shared process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To invite partners to shared processes go to the &lt;a href="#partners">Partners&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="partners">Partners&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Existing partners appear within this section in the left-hand side of the main view. Before you invite a partner create a shared process as demonstrated in the section &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To invite partners to view shared processes, click on the &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Invite partner&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill out the fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-dialog.jpg" alt="Invite partner dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ The fields in this box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Partner organisation&lt;/strong> - provide the name of the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact first name&lt;/strong> - provide the first name of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact last name&lt;/strong> - provide the surname of a contact in the partner organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Contact email&lt;/strong> - provide the email of a contact&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Shared process selection&lt;/strong> - in the dropdown list choose a shared process created using the steps listed in &lt;a href="#to-share-a-process">To share a process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>More fields&lt;/strong> to see more fields these include: &lt;strong>Partner country&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Partner city&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Partner logo&lt;/strong> which you can add by clicking on &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> and browsing your PC or network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="to-view-details-of-existing-partners">To view details of existing partners&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main partners view, click on the &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> of an existing partner from the list of partners or type in the name of a partner in the &lt;strong>Search partner&lt;/strong> search box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/invite-partner-main-view.jpg" alt="Partners view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Partner account details&lt;/strong> dialog box appears and details can be edited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-details.jpg" alt="Partner account details">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This dialog box contains same parameters as described in the &lt;a href="#to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/a> section, in addition to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner attributes&lt;/strong> - any additional partner attributes are listed here. See &lt;a href="#partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/a> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Processes shared with partner&lt;/strong> - any processes shared with the partner organisation, following the steps in the &lt;a href="#to-invite-partners">To invite partners&lt;/a> section, are listed here.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/confirm-process-update.jpg" alt="Confirm shared process update">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the main shared processes view click on the &lt;strong>New invite&lt;/strong> button if you want to invite a partner to a different shared process from the original one. Click on the dropdown list under &lt;strong>Shared process selection&lt;/strong> and select one of the listed shared processes. When you have made your choice, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-process-selection.jpg" alt="Shared process selection">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> results in an email invite being sent and the status in the Partners main view for the partner will be &lt;strong>Pending&lt;/strong> until the partner clicks on &lt;strong>Accept&lt;/strong> in the email, as shown in the example below, following by &lt;strong>Accept invite&lt;/strong> in a further screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/shared-process-email.jpg" alt="Invite partner email example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a shared process, Then in the &lt;strong>Remove partner&lt;/strong> dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to remove the partner, or &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> to cancel the removal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/remove-partner.jpg" alt="Remove partner">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To edit existing partner properties, go to the &lt;a href="#partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="partner-properties">Partner properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add new partner properties click on the &lt;strong>Partner properties&lt;/strong> button in the main Partners view.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you click on the button, the &lt;strong>Partner account custom attributes&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> and type in a property, for example Partner region as shown in the example below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-custom.jpg" alt="Partner account custom attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add attribute&lt;/strong> to add further properties, or click on the &lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin-shared-process.jpg" alt="Bin button for shared processes"> to delete a property.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, or else click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box at any stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a new property has been added you will receive a notification &lt;strong>Global settings updated&lt;/strong> and the attribute can be edited for partners when you click on the partner &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong> in the main view and edit the &lt;strong>Partner attributes&lt;/strong> details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partner-account-details-attribute.jpg" alt="Partner account details attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about creating process designs in Designer and how to use the interface to create forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Developer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> is available to &lt;strong>administrators&lt;/strong> and those users with the role &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>. The Developer function is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The function allows you to create customised field, rule, dashboard and data connector widgets using pre-defined widget UI and code templates that you can add your own code to, to create the effects you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also quickly use Kianda &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> to add webhooks, providing an efficient way to push GET requests to other applications in real-time as the Kianda process(es) runs and avoiding the need to poll for data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda uses EmberJS to build widgets, and in particular the Handlebars templating library, to power the application&amp;rsquo;s user interface. See &lt;a href="#emberjs-templating-basics">templating basics&lt;/a> to get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start using &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any customised widgets that have been created will be visible in the &lt;strong>Developer resources&lt;/strong> view below. &lt;strong>Field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>rule&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>dashboard&lt;/strong> widgets are visible in the left-hand &lt;strong>Widgets&lt;/strong> pane and customised &lt;strong>connectors&lt;/strong> are available in the right-hand &lt;strong>Connectors&lt;/strong> pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that &lt;strong>widgets&lt;/strong> can be &lt;strong>grouped&lt;/strong> into folders as shown in the image below. This is explained in step 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/developer-view-updated.jpg" alt="Developer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can search for a specific field, rule or dashboard widget by typing into the widget &lt;strong>Search bar&lt;/strong>, found above the list of widgets on the top left. Click on the &lt;strong>cancel&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cancel-btn.png" alt="Cancel button" style="zoom:80%;" /> to clear your search query.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/searching-widgets.png" alt="Searching for a process">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To view details for existing widgets, click on the widget name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-example.jpg" alt="Widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Widget&lt;/strong> pane you can update existing Widget UI and Widget Code within the editor and then click on &lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/update-button.jpg" alt="Update button">. Alternatively click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the page at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the &lt;strong>Developer resources&lt;/strong> main widget view you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>View the widget creation history by clicking on the &lt;strong>Version History&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-version-history.jpg" alt="Version History button">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit a widget by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-edit.jpg" alt="Edit widget button">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete a widget by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-delete.jpg" alt="Delete widget button">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new widget click on &lt;strong>New widget&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-widget-button.jpg" alt="New widget button">. This will open the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-widget-dialog-box.jpg" alt="Edit widget example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fill out details as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - fill out a title for the widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Unique Id&lt;/strong> - this is a unique value that is autofilled from the Title.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Widget Icon&lt;/strong> - choose an appropriate icon from the drop-down list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - add in a group name to group widgets together in a folder in the main widget view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Widget type&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Rule&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Dashboard widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="#emberjs-templating-basics">EmberJS templating basics&lt;/a> to find out more about EmberJS to build widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are finished editing the dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new customised connector click on the &lt;strong>New Connector&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-connector-button.jpg" alt="New connector button"> and populate the four tabs that appear. Details on how to create a customised connector are found at &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/custom-connector/">Custom connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can search for a specific connector by typing into the connector &lt;strong>Search bar&lt;/strong>, found above the list of connectors on the top right. Click on the &lt;strong>cancel&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cancel-btn.png" alt="Cancel button" style="zoom:80%;" /> to clear your search query.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connector-searching.png" alt="Searching for connectors">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create your own webhooks, click on &lt;strong>Webhooks&lt;/strong> to configure URLs to respond to process instance create, update and delete events.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/webhook-edit.jpg" alt="Instance Callback URLs">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Move the slider across for each type of operation (Create, Update, Delete) to add in a URL to enable callback.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For example for &lt;strong>Enable Deleted Callback&lt;/strong>, will enable the URL callback every time a process instance is updated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HTTP GET with parameters &lt;code>instanceID={instanceID}, processName={processName}&lt;/code> and &lt;code>eventType=deleted&lt;/code> will be issued to the provided URL.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you are finished editing the dialog box click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> at any time to exit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="emberjs-templating-basics">EmberJS templating basics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With Handlebars you can quickly build web applications that are made up of different components. Handlebar templates contain static HTML and dynamic content inside Handlebars expressions, which are summoned with double curly braces: {{ }}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dynamic content inside a Handlebars expression is rendered with data-binding. This means if you update a property, your usage of that property in a template will be automatically updated to the latest value.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="helpers">Helpers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ember gives the ability to write your helpers, to bring a minimum of logic into Ember templating. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you would like the ability to add a few numbers together, without needing to define a computed property everywhere you would like to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Helper example&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/write-our-own-helpers.png" alt="Helpers">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="conditionals">Conditionals&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Statements like &lt;strong>if&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>unless&lt;/strong> are implemented as built-in helpers. Helpers can be invoked three ways; inline invocation, nested invocation and block invocation. For more details, go to: &lt;a href="https://guides.emberjs.com/v2.18.0/templates/conditionals/">https://guides.emberjs.com/v2.18.0/templates/conditionals/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Developer and how to use the platform for low-code development, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/">Low code development&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/general/help/">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>