<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Form basics</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/</link><description>Recent content in Form basics on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Form owners</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-owners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-owners/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When creating forms, is important to consider &lt;strong>form access&lt;/strong> during the design phase, that is who can access and edit forms in a process instance. For example if an employee submits a performance review form, a line manager may wish to access that submitted process instance/record and edit the form, adding in comments and performance grades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two key principles to keep in mind in terms of &lt;strong>form access&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Forms are &lt;strong>assignable&lt;/strong> - this means that only a form assignee, that is, someone that is assigned to a form, can &lt;strong>edit&lt;/strong> a particular form in a process instance. The &amp;lsquo;assignee&amp;rsquo; can be a combination of users and groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Only form owners&lt;/strong> can edit a given form by &lt;strong>default&lt;/strong>. Any other user with access to view the form will see it in read-only mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>So what is &lt;strong>form owner&lt;/strong>? A form owner can be assigned when a form is created in Kianda Designer. Only the form owner will be able to edit &lt;strong>process instances&lt;/strong> (records).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a process has been designed and users can initiate new process instances or records from a dashboard page, then the only people who can edit process records are the form owners or someone who has had the record assigned to them.
For example, a line manager who is a form owner may need to add additional information about work goals in an appraisal form that their employee has already filled out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-started-with-form-owners">Getting started with Form owners&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To create form owners:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on a process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on an existing process or create a new process by clicking on &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> and complete the &lt;strong>Add new process&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then within Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> click on a form of interest and then click on the &lt;strong>Edit/(Pen)&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit/Pen button"> button for that form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box you can add form owners in the &lt;strong>Default owner(s)&lt;/strong> field - this can be &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-form-owners.jpg" alt="Partner account details attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>default owner&lt;/strong> is the person or group that the form is assigned to &lt;strong>when the the form is created&lt;/strong>. By default, only this person or group &lt;strong>can edit the form&lt;/strong>. All other users can only view forms in read mode. The default owner however can reassign forms to other individuals and/or groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Form display modes</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-display-modes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-display-modes/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Remember there are three principles to consider when working with forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reading modes&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>Form users&lt;/strong> can either use forms in &lt;strong>edit&lt;/strong> mode or &lt;strong>read&lt;/strong> mode. Edit mode means that users can submit information, while read mode means that users can only view forms. The latter may be useful for example for certain staff to review feedback in a form, but not be able to edit/update it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form owner&lt;/strong>: The &lt;strong>default owner&lt;/strong> is the person or group that the form is assigned to &lt;strong>when the the form is created&lt;/strong>. By default, only this person or group &lt;strong>can edit the form&lt;/strong>. All other users can only view forms in read mode. The default owner however can reassign forms to other individuals and/or groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Current form&lt;/strong>: Typically there are several forms in a process, and only the form that has the status ‘&lt;strong>current form’&lt;/strong> is &lt;strong>editable&lt;/strong>. However, in a complex multi-step process, other forms can be configured to &lt;strong>activate with&lt;/strong> the current form, meaning they can also become editable at the same time, creating a form group.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These three considerations are established when the form is created, as seen in the dialog box below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>New form dialog box&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/newformsegments-1.gif" alt="New form dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These properties can also change &lt;strong>dynamically&lt;/strong> as a result of &lt;strong>rules being applied&lt;/strong>, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-set-edit-and-read-modes">How to set edit and read modes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Forms in process instances will be &lt;strong>editable&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>Default owner(s)&lt;/strong> that is the &lt;strong>form owners&lt;/strong> defined when the form is created, or a form is edited. Form owners are defined in the &lt;strong>New form/Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box, shown in part 1 of the image above. When a process instance runs, the form owner can then edit the form in that instance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By default the first form in a process becomes the &lt;strong>current form&lt;/strong>, so only this form will be &lt;strong>editable&lt;/strong> for form owners. However if several forms are &lt;strong>activated with&lt;/strong> the current form, defined when the form is created or edited in the &lt;strong>New form/Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box, then &lt;strong>all forms in that group&lt;/strong> will be editable by the form owner in a process instance, as shown in part 2 of the image above.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Submit mode&lt;/strong> means that when a process instance is running you can choose &lt;strong>only this form&lt;/strong> to be submitted, or you can choose &lt;strong>all forms in edit mode&lt;/strong> meaning that several forms could have their details submitted or saved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong> allows you to &lt;strong>statically&lt;/strong> enable a) &lt;strong>reassignment&lt;/strong>, b) &lt;strong>edit&lt;/strong>, and c) &lt;strong>custom actions&lt;/strong> on any form. For a) and b) you can choose individuals and/or groups who can reassign or edit forms. In the case of b) edit there are options to &lt;strong>hide form footer buttons&lt;/strong> when editing, and to &lt;strong>trigger rules on save&lt;/strong> against a set field when saving edits. For c) custom actions, you can set your own custom action and create an action label against a particular form field. This means the user(s) assigns the custom action will see the labelled action designated for them. As a designer you can choose the &lt;strong>action display mode&lt;/strong> as read-only, edit or both, so you can decide what type of access the user(s) will have.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="changing-form-display-with-rules">Changing form display with rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you use the &lt;strong>Form action&lt;/strong> rule called &lt;strong>Field display mode&lt;/strong> you can change how a field or form displays dynamically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you add this rule, under &lt;strong>Action&lt;/strong> you can choose a field or form and choose from &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Read mode&lt;/strong>. How the form or field displays can then be based on a condition using the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-display-rule.jpg" alt="Field display rule">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information on this rule go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/form-actions/field-display-mode/">Field Display mode rule&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Form quick actions menu</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-quick-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-quick-action/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form quick action&lt;/strong> menu will appear to designated users as a quick action menu option in the top right-hand corner of a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on what type of quick actions are enabled and if you are assigned quick actions as a form user,, then you will see options when you click on the &lt;strong>quick action&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/quick-action-button.jpg" alt="Quick action menu">, for example to reassign a form to someone else, or to perform a custom action like signing off on a purchase order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/quick-action-view.jpg" alt="Quick action menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To enable quick actions, click on a process with Kianda Designer and then a form of choice so that the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) icon is visible.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit pen icon"> to edit a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box, check the checkbox beside &lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you select &lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong> then you have three options to select:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable re-assign&lt;/strong> - allows a form in a process instance to be reassigned to a by a designated person/group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable edit&lt;/strong> - allows a form in a process instance to be edited by a designated person/group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable custom action&lt;/strong> - allows a form in a process instance to have customised actions associated with it, and these actions are assigned to a designated person/group&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/setting-quick-actions.jpg" alt="Quick action menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check the checkbox beside the desired action as necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you check a checkbox for example &lt;strong>Enable edit&lt;/strong> then you can click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis-frame" alt="Ellipsis button"> to assign users to the quick action. This opens the &lt;strong>Action settings&lt;/strong> dialog box, such as the &lt;strong>Edit action settings&lt;/strong> box shown in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-action-settings.jpg" alt="Edit action settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Options in the &lt;strong>action settings&lt;/strong> dialog box are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Action users&lt;/strong> - select the users, groups or partners who will use the action&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong> - allows form owners to use the action&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When editing auto hide form footer buttons&lt;/strong> - hides form footer buttons when users are editing forms in a process instance&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Trigger rules on save&lt;/strong> - allows rules to be triggered when a form is saved/submitted. In this case select enter the button name used as the trigger in the &lt;strong>Save action field&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when complete or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trigger-rule-quick-action.jpg" alt="Trigger rule quick action">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/help">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Form responsive layout</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/responsive-layout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/responsive-layout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Responsive layout refers to the fact that all forms will display equally well on laptop screens, tablets and mobile phone screens. As a form designer you can set the appear of form fields using the layout function.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Within Kianda Designer, click on a process, then a form of choice so that the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) icon is visible.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on a &lt;strong>field&lt;/strong> of choice within the form so the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit pen icon"> is visible for the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) icon button for the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> under Field properties in the right-hand pane.
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/layout.jpg" alt="Layout property">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Expand&lt;/strong>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/layout-arrow.jpg" alt="Layout expand"> button within Layout to see Mobile and desktop layout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Collapse&lt;/strong> button to minimise the Layout property.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about how to create processes and forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out about help and support, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/help">Help&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>