<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Application designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/</link><description>Recent content in Application designer on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> provides an intuitive interface where you can quickly start building &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong> for any business use case. Forms are an important component of any process. They might be used as a stage of a process and can be made active individually or at the same time (parallel forms).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-designer-works">How Designer works&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This video introduces Kianda Designer and demonstrates how to start creating a form and add fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/designerintro.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>There are 3 key principles to consider when working with forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>design&lt;/strong> - what a form looks like, what elements it contains, for example controls and rules&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>interaction&lt;/strong> - how users can use forms depending on certain sequences happening&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>management&lt;/strong> - who can edit and access forms&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This page presents the information you need related to &lt;strong>form design&lt;/strong>, that is what a form looks like, and what it contains. By default, &lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> and those with the &lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong> role can edit forms, but they can also set how other people interact with forms, for example to make forms viewable as &lt;strong>read-only&lt;/strong>. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-owners/">Form owners&lt;/a> to find out more about how form ownership works, and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/form-display-modes/">Form display modes&lt;/a> to find out out more about how forms display.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="designer-layout">Designer layout&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access processes, go to the left-hand pane and &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process that you have created or imported, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/#creating-your-first-process">Create your first process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the main process view, click on any process to add forms.
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clickonprocess.png" alt="Clicking on a process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> window opens and is made up of 3 main parts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/designer-3-parts.jpg" alt="Form Designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key components of the designer are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Left-hand pane contains both &lt;strong>controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong> that can be added to forms. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to find out more. The left-hand pane also houses the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit process"> to go back to the process list, the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> to save your work, the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview"> to preview what you have created and the &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/publish.png" alt="Publish button"> to publish your work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that clicking on &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> saves a &lt;strong>draft&lt;/strong> of a process design. Click on &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> to publish the design and update changes to existing process instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you click on the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit process"> to go back to the process list &lt;u>without&lt;/u> clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button you will be prompted with a dialog box detecting &lt;strong>Unsaved changes&lt;/strong> prompting you to Abandon changes if desired. Click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to exit &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> without saving, or &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> to exit and save.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/unsaved-changes.jpg" alt="Unsaved changes detected popup">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The central area is where the current &lt;strong>form canvas&lt;/strong> is displayed. The canvas also houses 3 buttons by default: &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong>. Go to &lt;a href="#adding-form-elements">Adding form elements&lt;/a> to find out more about editing these buttons and adding elements to the canvas.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The right-hand pane is where the &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong> are displayed for the selected item, see &lt;a href="#properties">Properties&lt;/a> for more information. From this pane you can also &lt;a href="#import-forms">Import forms&lt;/a>, see the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/version-history/">Version history&lt;/a> for a process and set process &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/">Settings&lt;/a>. Click on the links to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: The name of the process you are working on is shown in the top menu bar, for example Quarterly Training Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Multiple users can view and design a process synchronously, allowing for seamless collaboration on your processess. The below error message is displayed in the bottom right corner when another user(s) is/are &lt;strong>viewing/editing&lt;/strong> the current process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/another-user-editing-notification.png" alt="Another user editing process image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When another user &lt;strong>saves a change&lt;/strong> to the process design that you are currently viewing, the below error message is displayed in the bottom right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/another-user-save-changes-notification.png" alt="Another user save changes notification image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started-with-forms">How to get started with forms&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How you get started with forms depends on if you:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>have created a process using the App Store, see &lt;a href="#predefined-forms">Predefined forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>have created a process from scratch or want to create a form from scratch, see &lt;a href="#new-forms">New forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>import forms that have already been created, see &lt;a href="#import-forms">Import forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once your form is created, you are ready to start adding elements to your form, see &lt;a href="#adding-form-elements">Adding form elements&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In addition there are a number of settings you can change, see &lt;a href="#properties">Properties&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#settings">Settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="predefined-forms">Predefined forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you have created a process using the App Store, then a number of forms will already be part of the process. For example the process Security Incident Management has 5 forms attached: Incident detail, Data breach, Malware outbreak, Root cause remedy and Caller review.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To edit form details, simply click on a form and click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> to edit the form. You can also click on the &lt;strong>Add form&lt;/strong> button to add a new form. Edit options are shown under &lt;a href="#new-forms">New forms&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="new-forms">New forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>How to add new form&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/How to add new form 2.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>If you have created a process from scratch, an empty form is added to your process by default, called &amp;ldquo;form 1&amp;rdquo;. This is the first form. Click on this form and the &lt;strong>Edit/Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> to customise it. You can also click on the &lt;strong>Add form&lt;/strong> button to add a new form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addform.png" alt="Add form">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="editing-forms">Editing forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you click on a chosen form, then click on the &lt;strong>Edit/Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> to edit the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form1_resized.png" alt="Edit form">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box opens where you can edit the fields. There are a number of edit options below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editingform.png" alt="Edit form options">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: as you change any of the options in the dialog box, the impact will be shown in real-time on the form in the background, for example a title, or colour form theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the form title, for example Employee Request Form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default owner(s)&lt;/strong> - by default the form creator is an owner. You can remove this owner by clicking on &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/x.png" alt="x"> and add other owners by clicking on the arrow and choose from &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Users - allows you to choose individual owners&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Groups - allows you to choose from defined groups for example HR Team or Management Team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partners - allows you to choose predefined partner organisations that you want to share with or provide permissions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Activate with&lt;/strong> - will decide when the form will be active. If you have several forms attached to a process, then select from a dropdown list the form you want to activate with the current form. If you leave the field blank, the new form will be activated &lt;strong>sequentially&lt;/strong> after the first form is submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Submit mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) &lt;strong>Only this form&lt;/strong> (the current form) or b) &lt;strong>All forms in edit mode&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form icon&lt;/strong> - click on the arrow to choose from hundreds of icons to attach to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong> - if you tick the checkbox, you can select from the options a) &lt;strong>Enable re-assign&lt;/strong> b) &lt;strong>Enable edit&lt;/strong> and c) &lt;strong>Enable custom action&lt;/strong>. Click on &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis_frame.png" alt="Ellipsis button"> to further modify the action settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable re-assign&lt;/strong>, you can reassign action settings to particular Users, Groups or Partners. Click on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong> if you want form owners to be able to reassign actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable edit&lt;/strong>, you can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to edit the form, along with form owners by clicking on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other options include a checkbox for &lt;strong>When editing auto hide form footer buttons&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Trigger rules on save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you check &lt;strong>Trigger rules on save&lt;/strong> then click into the &lt;strong>Save action field&lt;/strong>, you can choose an action trigger from the drop-down list as to when the form is saved, for example on execution of the Submit, Save or Close buttons. These can be other actions depending on what you have defined.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editactions_resized.png" alt="Edit action settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable custom action&lt;/strong>, you can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to edit the form, along with form owners by clicking on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other options include &lt;strong>Action label&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Target action field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Action display mode&lt;/strong>, for example &lt;strong>Read-only mode&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Both&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/customsetting_resized.png" alt="Custom action settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>As a form designer, you can set up actions dependent on certain conditions, for example an Action label that targets a certain button appearing for example Close button, only when a certain display mode is chosen, for example Read-only mode. If &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> is chosen, then the button will only appear when the form is being &lt;strong>edited&lt;/strong>. In this way you can create dynamic forms that suit user interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You are now ready to start adding &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> to your form. To implement additional settings, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/">Process Settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="import-forms">Import forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can import a previously designed form by clicking on the &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importform.png" alt="Import button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the arrow to select from the drop-down list to &lt;strong>Select a process design&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a process of interest and then click on the forms to import under &lt;strong>Select fields or forms to import&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Forms&lt;/strong> are indicated by a &lt;strong>+ symbol&lt;/strong> and can be expanded to show elements within a form for example a panel containing different fields such as lists and text boxes. This means you can import a whole form, or just elements of a form. In this way you can very quickly reuse some or all parts of an existing form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importing-form-example.jpg" alt="Import from another process">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="adding-form-elements">Adding form elements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have added a new form during the form creation process, then a blank canvas with three default buttons are available to you: &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form-buttons-example.jpg" alt="Form button edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within a form like the one shown above you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add elements to this canvas by clicking on &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> in the left-hand pane. Click on each link to find out more about the 16 control fields and 60 rule types.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move elements by clicking on the &lt;strong>Drag Handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/move.png" alt="Drag handle"> beside the item and dragging it to where you want to place it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit elements by clicking on each item and clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit/Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon">, for example if you click on the &lt;strong>Close button&lt;/strong>, there are a number of options to choose from when editing, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/actions/button/">Button control&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="properties">Properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to adding fields/controls and rules, there are a number of ways to create the form and process design you want. You can set &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> at &lt;strong>property, form&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>field level&lt;/strong>. Properties represent how an element presents itself, for example the title and layout of the element.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/right-hand-pane-designer.jpg" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Properties at all levels are visible in the &lt;strong>right-hand pane&lt;/strong> of Kianda designer, along with the:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importform.png" alt="Import button"> to allow you to import forms and form elements like fields&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Version history&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version-history-example.jpg" alt="Version history example"> to allow you to manage version of the process design&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings-button.jpg" alt="Settings button"> to allow you to apply process security settings amongst other options&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="process-level-properties">Process level properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you click on a process from the main process view, straight away you will see the &lt;strong>Process properties&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane as shown in the image above. To find out more about process go to the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/properties/">Process properties&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you click on a form within a process, then the properties view changes to show &lt;strong>Form properties&lt;/strong>, as shown in the image in &lt;a href="#form-level-properties">Form level properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to &lt;strong>return to Process properties,&lt;/strong> click on the &lt;strong>process name&lt;/strong> beside the Designer and chevron symbol, that is:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-name-chevron.jpg" alt="Process name">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="form-level-properties">Form level properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you click on a form in Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>, the properties for that form appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/form-properties-view.jpg" alt="Form properties view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out more about form properties go to the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/#form-properties">Form properties&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that at form level, additional buttons appear above &lt;strong>Form properties&lt;/strong> namely:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Edit/Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit/pen button"> where clicking on this button opens the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> dialog box for the chosen item, for example a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clone&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clone.png" alt="Clone button"> that allows you to make a duplicate form. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to make a copy or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the dialog box and cancel the copy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bin/trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin button"> where clicking on this button opens a popup asking you to confirm that you want to &lt;strong>delete&lt;/strong> the selected form. Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to make a copy or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the dialog box and cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="field-level-properties">Field level properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you add controls to forms Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>, and select a field/control, the properties for that field appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/field-properties-view.jpg" alt="Field properties view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The type of field/control is listed in the properties pane, for example &amp;lsquo;Text box&amp;rsquo; as shown in the image above. How the field appears is easy to control simply by checking/unchecking a number of boxes. To find out more about field/control properties go to the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties/">Control properties&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="change-field-button">Change field button&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Note that at field level, in addition to the buttons visible at &lt;a href="#form-level-properties">Form level&lt;/a>, a &lt;strong>Change field&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-field-button.jpg" alt="Change field button"> is visible. To change field type:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select a field in a form by clicking on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Change field&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A pop-up box appears allowing you to choose from the full range of field types, including &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/low-code/field-widget/">customised field widgets&lt;/a> created in Kianda &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/change-name-dialog-box.jpg" alt="Change field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>radio button&lt;/strong> beside the field type of choice and click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to make the change, or &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to close the dialog box and cancel the change.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box appears allowing you to change settings for that new field type.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="settings">Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to &lt;a href="#properties">Properties&lt;/a>, you can use &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> at process, form and field level to give you the type of processes and forms you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="process-settings">Process settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Basic process information&lt;/strong>, such as deciding who the process administrators are is available at the main process level, by exiting &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> clicking on the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit process"> to go the main process view, and then click on the process name to bring up the &lt;strong>Edit process&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-process-dialog-box.jpg" alt="Edit process dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More detailed &lt;strong>process settings&lt;/strong> are available within Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane by clicking on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings-button.jpg" alt="Process settings button"> and from here use the parameters available in the &lt;strong>Process settings&lt;/strong> dialog box to enable process security, anonymous sharing of forms and custom process ID, amongst other options. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/settings/">Process settings&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="form-and-field-settings">Form and field settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form and field settings&lt;/strong> are available when you &lt;strong>select&lt;/strong> an item in the form &lt;strong>canvas&lt;/strong> so that the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>/&lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit/pen button"> is available. An &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> dialog box appears allowing you to make the necessary changes to that item. Edit form dialog box is shown in &lt;a href="#editing-forms">Editing forms&lt;/a>. Field settings will be described within the information page for each field, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/">Controls&lt;/a> to start navigating to individual control pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Click on the links to find out more about aspects of Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>, namely &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/">Processes&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/">Forms&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To read about managing versions of forms, go to the link below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Form basics</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/forms/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Processes in Kianda are made up of &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong>. Forms contain all the buttons, fields, and rule triggers needed to execute your process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using your &lt;strong>Administrator&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Design business process&lt;/strong> role, you will use Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> to design &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>end users&lt;/strong> who will use the platform to submit, save and review information, either as named users in the platform, users who receive a link to an anonymous form, or partners who can access shared processes. These end users will create new &lt;strong>process instances&lt;/strong> or records in the system, or access &lt;strong>existing process instances&lt;/strong> which shows information that has either been &lt;strong>saved or submitted&lt;/strong> in a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When discussing forms we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about &lt;strong>form design&lt;/strong> that is creating and updating forms within a process using Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> as well &lt;strong>form use&lt;/strong> which refers to end users who will edit or read forms in a process instance/record in the system, built using the &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="form-design-principles">Form design principles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you work with Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> you are designing the &amp;lsquo;user interface&amp;rsquo; for users to interact with a particular process. Keeping the end user in mind, there are three design principles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reading modes&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>Form users&lt;/strong> can either use/access forms in &lt;strong>edit&lt;/strong> mode or &lt;strong>read&lt;/strong> mode. Edit mode means that users can submit information, while read mode means that users can only view forms. The latter may be useful for example for certain staff to review customer feedback in a form, but not be able to change/edit the feedback form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Current form&lt;/strong>: Typically there are several forms in a process, and by default the &lt;strong>first form&lt;/strong> in a process is the &lt;strong>current form&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/3-form-example.jpg" alt="Three form process example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example in the Training Attendance Process above, the process flow is as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Training Request&lt;/strong> - an employee initiates a process instance by filling out this form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Training Approval&lt;/strong> - the manager approves the request using this form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Training Attendance&lt;/strong> - when training approval occurs, a trainer invites the employee to attend training and once complete, the trainer completes a this form to evaluate the employee&amp;rsquo;s participation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore when a process instance is initiated upon submission of the &lt;strong>Training Request&lt;/strong> form, then the next form in the process becomes the &lt;strong>current form&lt;/strong>, in this case the &lt;strong>Training Approval&lt;/strong> form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only the form that has the status ‘&lt;strong>current form’&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>is editable&lt;/strong> by a form owner (see point 3 below). In a complex multi-step process, several forms can be configured to &lt;strong>activate with&lt;/strong> the current form, meaning they are also editable at the same time, creating a &lt;strong>form group&lt;/strong>, see section 2 of &lt;a href="#new-form-creation">New form creation&lt;/a>. Rules can also be used to change the workflow and make other forms the &amp;lsquo;current form&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also note that &lt;strong>all first forms&lt;/strong> in a process flow add the current user as a &amp;lsquo;form owner&amp;rsquo; therefore allowing &lt;strong>all users&lt;/strong> to edit the first form, as clicking on &amp;lsquo;submit&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;save&amp;rsquo; in the first form results in a new process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form owner&lt;/strong>: The &lt;strong>default owner&lt;/strong> is the person or group that the form is assigned to, this means they can &lt;strong>edit the &lt;u>current&lt;/u> form(s) in a process instance&lt;/strong>. Default owners are typically set when a form is created, see section 1 of &lt;a href="#new-form-creation">New form creation&lt;/a> below. By default, &lt;strong>only this person or group can edit the &lt;u>current&lt;/u> form&lt;/strong> in a process instance. All other users can only view forms in read mode. The default owner however can reassign forms to other individuals and/or groups. Form ownership can also be assigned dynamically using the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/assign-form/">Assign form&lt;/a> rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>These three considerations are established when the form is created, as seen in the dialog box below, and these parameters can be updated at any time by editing the form design. These properties can also change &lt;strong>dynamically&lt;/strong> as a result of &lt;strong>implementing rules&lt;/strong>, for example the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/go-to-form/">Go to form&lt;/a> rule can change the workflow in a process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-form-creation">New form creation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As mentioned in the &lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a> there are certain considerations to keep in mind when working with forms. The image below shows a &lt;strong>New form&lt;/strong> dialog box that is created when the &lt;strong>Add form&lt;/strong> button is clicked in Kianda Designer. At any time if you click on a form and then the &lt;strong>Edit/pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit/pen button"> an &lt;strong>Edit form&lt;/strong> dialog box appears which has the same parameters as the one shown in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>New form dialog box&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://academy.kianda.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/newformsegments-1.gif" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="new-form-considerations">New form considerations&lt;/h5>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Default owner(s)&lt;/strong> field is where you can set individuals and groups as the default &lt;strong>form owners&lt;/strong> who can edit the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Activate with&lt;/strong> means that the form can be activated with other forms within the process, so they can be edited at the same time. This means several forms become the &lt;strong>current form&lt;/strong> in a form group.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Submit mode&lt;/strong> means that when a process instance is running you can choose &lt;strong>only this form&lt;/strong> to be submitted, or you can choose &lt;strong>all forms in edit mode&lt;/strong> meaning that several forms could have their details submitted or saved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong> allows you to &lt;strong>statically&lt;/strong> enable a) reassignment, b) edit, and c) custom actions on any form. For a) and b) you can choose individuals and/or groups who can reassign or edit forms. In the case of b) edit there are options to &lt;strong>hide form footer buttons&lt;/strong> when editing, and to &lt;strong>trigger rules on save&lt;/strong> against a set field when saving edits. For c) custom actions, you can set your own custom action and create an action label against a particular form field. This means that the user(s) assigning the custom action will see the labelled action designated for them. As a designer you can choose the &lt;strong>action display mode&lt;/strong> as read-only, edit or both, so you can decide what type of access the user(s) will have.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced the principles of working with forms. To read more about working with forms, click on the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Getting started with Kianda processes</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The power of Kianda lies in giving anyone, even those without coding experience, the ability to design a &lt;strong>business application or process&lt;/strong> quickly and efficiently, for example, this process could be a Quality Assurance checklist that installation engineers must follow on site using a mobile app or it could be a HR process to allow employees to submit annual leave requests and approve these online. Processes can connect to your data sources like Sharepoint or SalesForce allowing for the flexibility of your applications to grow as your business grows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each process can be linked to &lt;strong>dashboards&lt;/strong> so you can see at a glance, for example, how many leave requests were submitted, purchase orders approved and so on. And you can customise all of these processes the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you begin, we at Kianda recommend doing some simple planning before you design your process. It could be something as simple as a quick flow chart or a spreadsheet where you quickly log the key components, fields or rules that should be needed in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-processes">Creating processes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To start creating your first process, go to the side menu on the left of the screen and click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create processes you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use Kianda&amp;rsquo;s pre-defined processes or Apps, see &lt;a href="#using-the-app-store">Using the App Store&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create your own processes from scratch, see &lt;a href="#creating-your-own-processes">Creating your own processes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Import processes that are already created, see &lt;a href="#importing-processes">Importing processes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have created your process(es) go to &lt;a href="#editing-processes">Editing processes&lt;/a> to find out how to start adding forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also export any processes for backup and reuse, see &lt;a href="#exporting-processes">Exporting processes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="using-the-app-store">Using the App Store&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can choose from Kianda&amp;rsquo;s process templates by clicking on the &lt;strong>App Store&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/appstore.png" alt="App Store button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from &lt;strong>General&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>IT&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Customer Services&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Finance&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Travel&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Quality&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Accounting&lt;/strong> apps by clicking on the relevant button in the left-hand pane and then select an app from within that category, for example Customer Support Queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/appstoreegs.png" alt="App Store General Apps">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can click on &lt;strong>Read More&lt;/strong> to read about the app and click on &lt;strong>Import Process App&lt;/strong> to import the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/supportapp.png" alt="Customer Support Queries App">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If the process is an existing process, you can choose to override the existing process by clicking &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or if not, click &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. Change the Title and Name of the process as needed, for example Customer Queries, and click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importcustomerprocess.png" alt="Override existing processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The system will report datasources being imported. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importbusinessprocess_frame.png" alt="Import business processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select dashboards to be included by checking the checkbox beside dashboards you want to import. In each case you can decide to override the existing dashboards by clicking on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> or if not &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importcustomerdashboard_frame.png" alt="Import dashboards">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will see a summary of what is about to be imported. Click on &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> to execute the import.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Imported processes are available to view and edit from the main process view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have created your process go to &lt;a href="platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a> to find out more on how to add and change forms within your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="creating-your-own-processes">Creating your own processes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create your own process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew.png" alt="Add new process button"> . Note that if you click on the arrow on the button, you have options to create a &lt;strong>Process&lt;/strong>, a &lt;strong>Component&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Create from datasource&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/newprocessoptions_resized.png" alt="Add new process options">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Process&lt;/strong> is a complete set of forms that encapsulates a business process for example, Purchase Order Approval.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Component&lt;/strong> is a part of a business process, and you can decide your approach and how you want to order and present forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Create from datasource&lt;/strong> refers to using a particular data source and elements within that datasource tree, for example if you choose Kianda pre-defined processes then when you select &lt;strong>Kianda&lt;/strong> you can see all the processes that are already imported into your system as shown on the right in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasourcecreate_frame.png" alt="Kianda data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished to save your work, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The following edit options are available:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the process, for example Annual Leave Approval&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong> - a description of the process&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - a defined group of users for example HR Managers. If you choose &amp;lsquo;Create new group&amp;rsquo;, a further field &lt;strong>New group name&lt;/strong> will be displayed, where you will enter the new group&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Users or b) Groups&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are the users or groups who will act as administrators for the process, for example to edit or delete the process. For example if you click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and click in the Administrators field you will see a list of all the users who are approved to administrate this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/adminusers_frame.png" alt="Admin users">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished to save your work, or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have created your process go to &lt;a href="platform/form_designer2.md">Designer&lt;/a> to find out more on how to add forms to your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="importing-processes">Importing processes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you already have Kianda processes, you can also import these by clicking on the &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/import_frame.png" alt="Import process button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Browse Process App&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/browse-process-app-btn.jpg" alt="browse brocess app button"> to browse for Kianda files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the files you want, for example quarterly-training-request.kianda and click on Open.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importkianda2.png" alt="Importing processes" style="zoom:80%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If the process name is an already existing process in your environment, then this new process will override it. However, if the process name does not match any current process, a new process will be created. Change the Title and Name of the process as needed and click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/overrideprocess2.jpg" alt="Override existing processes" style="zoom:67%;" />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The system will report any datasources being imported. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importbusinessprocess.png" alt="Import business processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Dashboards to be included&lt;/strong>, you can view the Title and Name of the dashboards that are present in the Kianda file. If this dashboard already exists in your environment, then including this dashboard in your upload will overwrite it. If this dashboard does not currently exist, then it will create a new dashboard. When finished, click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importdashboards2.png" alt="Import dashboards">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Included custom widgets&lt;/strong>, you can view the title of the custom widgets that are included within the Kianda file being imported. In this example, a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a> is included for use within the User Training Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> to continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/import-custom-widgets.png" alt="User Training Dashboard Widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will see a summary of what is about to be imported. Click on &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> to execute the import.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importsummary2.png" alt="Import summary">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Imported processes are available to view and edit from the main process view.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you have imported your process(es) go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a> to find out more on how to edit or add forms to your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="editing-processes">Editing processes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When processes are created they are available to view and to edit from the central view panel found within &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/firstprocess_resized.png" alt="Process created">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information related to your processes, is found in this panel, for example who created the process, and when, the version of the process and a description if it exists.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first version of a process is &lt;strong>0.1&lt;/strong> and will increment to 0.2 and so on, each time a process is updated. Once the process is &lt;strong>published&lt;/strong> the version changes to &lt;strong>1.0&lt;/strong> and increments with each publication. This makes it is easy to keep track of who made changes and when, and to restore an older version if needed. You can also search for processes by typing your keywords into the search bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>At any time you can edit the Title, Description, Group and Administrators of the process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images//penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> beside your process of choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>At any time you can delete a process by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the process title and you are sure that this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you have created your process, you are ready to add forms. Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/designer/">Designer&lt;/a> to find out more on how to add and change forms within your process(es).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="exporting-processes">Exporting processes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can export any processes, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Export&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/export_frame.png" alt="Export Process"> and select a process to export from the dropdown list. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> when you have selected your desired process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exportprocesses_frame2.png" alt="Export processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The system will report what datasources are included. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exportanddata_frame.png" alt="Exporting business processes with datasources">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select dashboards to be included by checking the checkbox beside dashboards you want to export. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exportingprocesses_frame2.png" alt="Export business processes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Include custom widgets?&lt;/strong>, you check the checkbox beside the displayed custom widget(s) to include this custom widget within the exported Kianda file. In this example, a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/custom/">Custom dashboard widget&lt;/a> is included for use within the User Training Dashboard. Click on &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> to continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/include-custom-widgets.png" alt="Custom widget include">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The final screen displays a confirmation message communicating that the process is now ready for export. Click on the &lt;strong>Export&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/export-btn.png" alt="Export button"> to export the Kianda file.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The result is a downloadable file of type .kianda. This can be kept as a backup on a separate system and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/#importing-processes">imported&lt;/a> into other Kianda instances as needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/kianda-downloadable.png" alt="Exported files">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced how to create, edit and export processes. To read more about process instances and settings go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Component</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/component/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/component/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Kianda &lt;strong>component&lt;/strong> acts like a smaller version of a &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> made up of &lt;strong>various&lt;/strong> control &lt;strong>fields and rules&lt;/strong>. You can &lt;strong>reuse&lt;/strong> the component in your process designs to save you time and effort when creating each field and rule combination from the beginning. Within the component you can add all preconfigured control types and rules to match your needs, as well as customised field and rules found under &lt;strong>Custom&lt;/strong>. Creating a component will &lt;strong>significantly&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>speed up&lt;/strong> your process &lt;strong>creation time&lt;/strong> if some of your processes demand the &lt;strong>same fields and logic&lt;/strong>. For example if a lot of your processes have sections in common, for example a &lt;strong>Personal Details&lt;/strong> section where a user needs to fill in their &lt;strong>first&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>last&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>name&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>email&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>job role&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>phone&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>number&lt;/strong>. To save process creation time, you can create a component with those exact fields and rules you need and then use the component in various process designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The component you create can be updated at any time. Once you publish your component it can be used in any process of your choice and any processes that already use your component will be automatically updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-create-a-new-component">How to create a new component&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the home page, navigate to &lt;strong>Administrator &amp;gt; Designer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are in the &lt;strong>Process designer&lt;/strong> screen navigate your mouse to the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew-component.jpg" alt="Idea icon"> button and click the &lt;strong>down arrow.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-addnew.jpg" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dropdown menu click on &lt;strong>Component&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-create-new.jpg" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Add new component&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill in the following detail:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-add-new-dialog.jpg" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - represents the title of your component.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> - represents the &lt;strong>unique&lt;/strong> id of the component. Ensure that the ID entered here is unique across all components and processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong> - enter a valid description of the component you are creating.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - using this drop-down list, you can add your component to a existing group or create a new one.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> - select the appropriate component administrators from , to read more about process and component administrators visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/security/process-level-security">Process security&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you are finished filling out the detail. You will be automatically moved to the component designer screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="editing-an-existing-component">Editing an existing component&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the home page, navigate to &lt;strong>Administrator &amp;gt; Designer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Process designer&lt;/strong> screen, navigate to the folder (if used) where your component is click the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Idea icon">. Note that the type will state &lt;strong>Component&lt;/strong> within the list of all processes and components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-access-edit-copy.jpg" alt="Edit component">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Edit component dialog will appear allowing you to change some of the detail which include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are happy with the changes made to the details, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="accessing-an-existing-component">Accessing an existing component&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the home page, navigate to &lt;strong>Administrator &amp;gt; Designer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Process designer&lt;/strong> screen, in the list of processes, components and folders, navigate to the until you see your component and click on the &lt;strong>title&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-access-edit.jpg" alt="Edit component">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will be navigated to the component designer screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To read more about field control visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/">Controls&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To read more about rules visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Create from Datasource</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/create-from-datasource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/create-from-datasource/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Create from Datasource&lt;/strong> feature allows you to create a process using a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Datasource&lt;/a> of your choice where the datasource elements will populate your Kianda form. Note that the datasource is already created within your platform within the &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using this feature serves as a way of swiftly populating your process with the relevant fields from your datasource lists so that you can increase design productivity from the beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Examples of fields that can be populated instantly into your processes include &lt;strong>ProcessID&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>, and other fields such as an associated utility panel - important hidden metadata relating to your list.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="creating-a-process-from-a-datasource">Creating a process from a datasource&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the home page, navigate to &lt;strong>Administrator &amp;gt; Designer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are in the &lt;strong>Process designer&lt;/strong> screen navigate your mouse to the &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addnew-component.jpg" alt="Idea icon"> button and click the small &lt;strong>down arrow.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/component-addnew.jpg" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the dropdown menu click on &lt;strong>Create from datasource&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-from-datasource-new.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Select datasource&lt;/strong> dialog box, fill in the following details, note that these data sources must be precreated using the &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Datasource&lt;/a> function under Administration:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/select-datasource-create-from-datasource2.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Replace list form with Kianda forms?&lt;/strong> - select between &lt;em>Yes&lt;/em> or &lt;em>No&lt;/em>, where the default option is Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Datasources&lt;/strong> - select your datasource of choice that you would like to create the process with. The window displays data sources that are already created and connected within your Kianda platform. For more information, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Datasources&lt;/a>. In this example we will choose a &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/sharepoint/">SharePoint&lt;/a> datasource.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Datasource tree&lt;/strong> - once a datasource has been selected, select which elements in that datasource that you want to use in your process, for example a list or a folder. You can drill down into the tree by clicking on the main datasource node at the top and select the relevant element, and you can search the tree by using the search bar in the top right. In this example we will choose &lt;strong>Accounts&lt;/strong> as shown in the image above.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when you are finished filling out the details. Alternatively you can click &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the creation dialog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: When creating a new process from a datasource, ensure that there is not already &lt;strong>a process with the name&lt;/strong> of the datasource list as this may cause conflicts in the unique names of the processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Your process will then be opened and it will detect all the fields of your selected datasource node and populate them into a form of the same name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/create-from-datasource-process.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: If you create new list columns within your chosen datasource, these options will not be reflected within the design unless you repeat the creation process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To read more about field control visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/process/">Controls&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To read more about rules visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To read more about datasources visit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Datasources&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>